<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>French on Paul&#39;s Particles</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/french/</link>
    <description>Recent content in French on Paul&#39;s Particles</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 20:19:47 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/french/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Butter Lemon Pork</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/butter-lemon-pork/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 20:19:47 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/butter-lemon-pork/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So today, I tried to do something new with pork belly. Most of my recipes involving this ingredient are Chinese, and so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d spice things up a little by taking some more inspiration from the French kitchen. Be warned, this recipe is quite fatty, but otherwise it&amp;rsquo;s very easy to make and nutritious to boot.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Butter&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dried oregano&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt and Pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pork belly&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lemon juice&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Honey&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Water&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dark soy sauce (for color)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ginger (or ginger powder)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;High smoking point oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Serve with white rice.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;First, slice your pork belly into bite sized pieces and cover with a little salt, pepper and dried oregano.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add some oil to a heated pan. For added crisp and brownness from your pork, use a cast iron pan.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add your pork belly to a pan and let it crisp properly. Once it has browned, add in 2 thin slices of butter and keep cooking your pork until crisp.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Remove your pork and add in onion (in rings or slices). Leave it to brown for a while. For quick caramelisation, you may add some hot water to your pan and cover it with a lid. This way, your onion will come into contact with even more heat, quickening the process. This also prevents your onion from burning when you prepare the sauce.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In a sauce pan, add 2 thin slices of butter, a little bit of oil and your garlic. Stir it until it is fragrant and sauteed. For this sauce, it is up to your own taste, so keep tasting while cooking it so that you can adjust how much of your ingredients to add.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To your sauce, add the ginger, lemon juice and more dried oregano. To sweeten your sauce and counteract the sourness, add in honey to taste. After that, add a little water and dark soy sauce for coloring. Reduce the sauce until it is thick and keep adjusting your sauce until it is to your liking. If needed, you can add a cornstarch slurry to make it thicken faster.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add the sauce, pork and onion into your pan and stir a little until everything is covered.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OE (Onion &amp; Eggs)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/egg-and-onion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 21:33:38 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/egg-and-onion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, we will be making OE. I&amp;rsquo;ll let you figure out what that means.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Onions&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Eggs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(also some pepper, salt and cooking oil)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We will be using about one onion per one egg.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;For people that like the taste of onion, I suggest you let the onions sweat by using a medium-low heat, until the onions turn translucent. This takes about 10 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;For those of you that have time on their hands, let the onions caramelise on the same medium-low heat. This takes an additional 30 to 40 minutes, until they have turned brown and crisp.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add in the eggs and stir on a high heat, untill you have the consistency of scrambled eggs.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, add pepper and salt to taste.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
