<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Wok on Paul&#39;s Particles</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/wok/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Wok on Paul&#39;s Particles</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 21:39:46 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/wok/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Nasi Goreng Biasa</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/nasi-goreng-biasa/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2025 21:39:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/nasi-goreng-biasa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love cooking fried rice, and I wanted to share this basic (Biasa = basic) recipe with you all because it really is versatile and delicious. From this base, a lot of very delicious types of Nasi Goreng can be constructed, and it can be served with almost any Indonesian, Malay, Thai, or even Chinese dish.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cooking oil (high smoke point)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Old cooked rice (as dry and grainy as possible)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kecap Manis (can be subbed with dark soy sauce combined with palm sugar)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shallots&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fish sauce or Shrimp paste (substitute 2 tbsp fish sauce for 1 tbsp shrimp paste)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fresh chilies (optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chop your garlic, shallots and fresh chilies until they are fine. Add them to a bowl.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Heat your wok and add a layer of cooking oil to the bottom of it.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next, add your aromatics and cook them for a little while until they begin to brown.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add your rice to the pan, followed by your fish sauce and kecap manis.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Make sure to stir and toss your rice while cooking to keep it from sticking to the pan.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Stir-fry this until most of the water has evaporated and you are left with loose grains. This only takes about 2 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sweet and Spicy Hoisin Beef Tips</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/sweet-and-spicy-hoisin-beef-bliss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 21:28:30 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/sweet-and-spicy-hoisin-beef-bliss/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love wokking, but it has been a bit too cold to use my wok in the last few months. Today however, I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t resist the urge to wok, and this delicious recipe is the result.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;marinade&#34;&gt;Marinade&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Beef tips&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Black pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hoisin sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cornstarch&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Baking powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sugar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;sauce&#34;&gt;Sauce&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hoisin sauce (2 tbsp) (1 tbsp if you like it a little less sweet)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chili garlic sauce (1 tbsp)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Honey (1 tbsp)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soy sauce (2 tbsp)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Water (2 tbsp)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sesame seeds (optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;for-wokking&#34;&gt;For wokking&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White or yellow onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Green peppers (to add some nice spice, don&amp;rsquo;t remove the seeds)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Spring onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bell peppers (can sub for green peppers if you don&amp;rsquo;t like spicy)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Vegetable oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Combine your marinade in a bowl and let it sit while you prepare your veggies and sauce. For this marinade, combine soy sauce and hoisin sauce in a 3/1 ratio. The cornstarch is meant to retain moisture for your beef tips, and the baking powder is a secret technique to make your meat more tender in a short amount of time.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next, prepare your sauce by mixing all ingredients in a bowl.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chop your veggies into large chunks.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Prepare your wok with some vegetable oil and wait until your wok is smoking hot.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add your veggies and stir-fry until browned a little.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next, add your beef and quickly stir-fry until browned and a little crispy.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, add your sauce and reduce until it creates a nice coating on your meat and veggies.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Serve with white rice&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sweet and Sour Chicken</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/sweet-and-sour-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 21:59:06 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/sweet-and-sour-chicken/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have always loved sweet and sour chicken. When I was little, I used to eat this on vacations to New York, at a local mall in Middletown, New York. I wanted to recreate this taste, but without having to use tomato ketchup, as that is usually a little too processed for me (and also, I don&amp;rsquo;t always have it in my pantry). The result is this recipe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chicken breasts (cubed)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cornstarch&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Black pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sunflower oil (or other cooking oil with a high smoking point)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bell peppers (red and green)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ginger&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sugar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tomato paste&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Black vinegar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pineapple chunks (Optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pineapple juice (extra sweet) or lemon juice (extra sour) (Optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Serve with white rice&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Start by cubing your chicken breasts, seasoning them generously with salt and pepper. Afterwards, coat with cornstarch.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add a large amount of sunflower oil to a pan and fry your chicken until golden brown.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In the meantime, prepare the sauce by adding the following: soy sauce, black vinegar and tomato sauce in a 3:3:2 tbsp ratio. Also add about 2-3 cloves of garlic and some grated ginger to taste. Add your lemon/pineapple juice if you want. Finally, add sugar to taste.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Remove your chicken from the pan and leave them to rest on some paper towels to catch off excess oil. Store most of the oil in a container, and leave a small amount to cook your vegetables.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cut your bell peppers and white onion into large chunks and stir-fry them on medium-high heat. After a little while, also add your optional pineapple chunks for a more traditional recipe.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;After your onion has become nice and brown on the edges, add in your sauce and stir until thickened.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add your chicken at the end in order to keep them crispy for longer. Serve with white rice.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
