<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Difficulty 1|5 on Paul&#39;s Particles</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/difficulty-15/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Difficulty 1|5 on Paul&#39;s Particles</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 17:18:42 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/difficulty-15/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Burger Sauce</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/burger-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 17:18:42 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/burger-sauce/</guid>
      <description>Today, I share a very simple recipe for a burger sauce. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to make and a lot more interesting than your usual mayonaise or ketchup that you put on your burger. When making burgers, I suggest you assemble the following: your buns, a leave of lettuce, some fried onions, gherkins/pickles, your patty and lastly this burger sauce.&#xA;Ingredients Mayonaise (250 grams) Mustard (30 grams) 1 tbsp of white vinegar 0.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OE (Onion &amp; Eggs)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/egg-and-onion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 21:33:38 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/egg-and-onion/</guid>
      <description>Today, we will be making OE. I&amp;rsquo;ll let you figure out what that means.&#xA;Ingredients Onions Eggs (also some pepper, salt and cooking oil) Cooking plan We will be using about one onion per one egg. For people that like the taste of onion, I suggest you let the onions sweat by using a medium-low heat, until the onions turn translucent. This takes about 10 minutes. For those of you that have time on their hands, let the onions caramelise on the same medium-low heat.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mint Dip</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/mint-dip/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 21:09:25 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/mint-dip/</guid>
      <description>So I am looking more into the indian cuisine. To start things off, I made a simple mint dip to eat with a meal, or just to dip naan in.&#xA;Ingredients Yoghurt Mint leaves (dried if fresh isn&amp;rsquo;t available) Lemon juice A clove of garlic Salt and pepper Cooking plan Finely chop the garlic and mint leaves Mix the ingredients to taste ENJOY! </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bbq Sauce</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/bbq-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 18:57:14 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/bbq-sauce/</guid>
      <description>I really enjoy this bbq-sauce with pulled pork or as a glaze for spare-ribs.&#xA;Ingredients Ketchup Worcester Sauce Mustard Vinegar Garlic powder Onion powder Salt, pepper and sugar to taste Cooking plan Put it all into a pan and stir over low heat. Go easy on the mustard and vinegar. ENJOY! </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tzatziki</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/tzatziki/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 14:03:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/tzatziki/</guid>
      <description>After a trip to Greece, I fell in love with greek cuisine. Of course, you cant say Greek without Tzatziki, and so I will share this easy recipe for this beloved sauce.&#xA;Ingredients Greek yoghurt Garlic Vinegar Olive oil (I like extra virgin) Dill Cucumber Some salt Preparation Finely grate a cucumber and wring out the moisture using a towel. Finely press the garlic, and add it to the yoghurt along with the other ingredients.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
