<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Italian on Paul&#39;s Particles</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/italian/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Italian on Paul&#39;s Particles</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 09:26:04 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/italian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Marry Me Chicken</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/marry-me-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 09:26:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/marry-me-chicken/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Before getting started with this recipe, &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.delish.com/cooking/recipe-ideas/a46330/skillet-sicilian-chicken-recipe/&#34;&gt;I must credit the original recipe&lt;/a&gt;, as it is a classic and this dish is heavily based on it. I really liked the dish, but felt that I could give it a bit of a twist to suit my own taste. From that, this recipe spawned into existence.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Boneless chicken breasts.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Butter&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Flour (optional, you can skip this step, but it makes chicken juicier)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Black pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Thyme&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Oregano&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Red pepper flakes (can sub with chili powder)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chicken broth&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sun-dried tomatoes&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Heavy cream&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Grated parmesan&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Parsley (fresh, for garnish, optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Extra virgin olive oil (optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Preheat your oven to 200 degrees Celcius.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Start by seasoning your chicken breasts with salt and black pepper.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Melt some butter in an oven-proof pan on high heat. Meanwhile, coat your chicken in flour.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cook your chicken until golden brown (about 2-3 minutes on both sides). Remove from pan and let rest on a plate afterwards.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chop up some garlic and a lot of sun-dried tomatoes, and add them to your pan on medium-low heat.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next, add your heavy cream, thyme, oregano and red pepper flakes (or chili powder).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Grate some parmesan and add it to your sauce and season to taste with salt and pepper.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, put your chicken back into the pan and cover in the sauce. Put it into the oven for about 10 minutes, until the sauce has achieved a desireable color.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Can be served with pasta, bread or just eaten like this.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meatballs in tomato sauce</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/tomato-meatballs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 18:11:37 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/tomato-meatballs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ok, so last week I was thinking about what I wanted to cook, when I stumbled upon some inspiration for meatballs in tomato sauce, thinking back to how delicious those were back when I visited Greece. Now I am not about to tell you that this is an authentic Greek recipe (it is more of an Italian recipe I believe), but this is an authentic Paul banger, and as such, I would love to share it with you all. If you don&amp;rsquo;t feel like rolling meatballs, you can also just use ground beef. This has the added benefit of making storage for later easier.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbonara</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/carbonara/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 20:03:41 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/carbonara/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, yesterday I was craving some good &amp;lsquo;ol spaghetti. I usually go with a tomato sauce, but this time, I saw that I still had some parmigiano in my fridge. I simply couldn&amp;rsquo;t resist the urge to try something new, and ended up making this delicious carbonara. It may not be the healthiest, but it was definitely worth it in the end. I included a secret ingredient of miso paste in order to boost the umami content. Although I strongly recommend you put it, the dish will still turn out yummy if omitted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
