<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Difficulty 3|5 on Paul&#39;s Particles</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/difficulty-35/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Difficulty 3|5 on Paul&#39;s Particles</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 21:28:30 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/difficulty-35/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sweet and Spicy Hoisin Beef Tips</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/sweet-and-spicy-hoisin-beef-bliss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 21:28:30 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/sweet-and-spicy-hoisin-beef-bliss/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love wokking, but it has been a bit too cold to use my wok in the last few months. Today however, I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t resist the urge to wok, and this delicious recipe is the result.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;marinade&#34;&gt;Marinade&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Beef tips&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Black pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hoisin sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cornstarch&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Baking powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sugar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;sauce&#34;&gt;Sauce&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hoisin sauce (2 tbsp) (1 tbsp if you like it a little less sweet)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chili garlic sauce (1 tbsp)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Honey (1 tbsp)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soy sauce (2 tbsp)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Water (2 tbsp)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sesame seeds (optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;for-wokking&#34;&gt;For wokking&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White or yellow onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Green peppers (to add some nice spice, don&amp;rsquo;t remove the seeds)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Spring onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bell peppers (can sub for green peppers if you don&amp;rsquo;t like spicy)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Vegetable oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Combine your marinade in a bowl and let it sit while you prepare your veggies and sauce. For this marinade, combine soy sauce and hoisin sauce in a 3/1 ratio. The cornstarch is meant to retain moisture for your beef tips, and the baking powder is a secret technique to make your meat more tender in a short amount of time.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next, prepare your sauce by mixing all ingredients in a bowl.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chop your veggies into large chunks.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Prepare your wok with some vegetable oil and wait until your wok is smoking hot.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add your veggies and stir-fry until browned a little.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next, add your beef and quickly stir-fry until browned and a little crispy.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, add your sauce and reduce until it creates a nice coating on your meat and veggies.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Serve with white rice&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roti</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/roti/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 17:23:35 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/roti/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love roti, and having now made it myself, I can safely say that its lovely flavor carries over to the home kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Flour (500 grams)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Butter (40 grams)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Butter (80+ grams) (used for cooking)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Water (200 grams)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt (1 teaspoon)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Heat about 40 grams of butter in a pan until melted.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add together this melted butter, your flour and water. Mix in a dough mixer or by using two forks until your dough is smooth and not as sticky anymore.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Roll out your dough into thin sheets. The thinner they are, the better they will be cooked once they go into your pan.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cook your roti at high heat in a skillet or non-stick pan. For each roti you cook, coat the pan with butter and lay your roti on it. Wait until it bubbles up a little and starts to brown, and then flip it over. Your roti should be coated in the butter, so add more if you didn&amp;rsquo;t add enough.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;tips&#34;&gt;Tips&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You may want to pre-melt your butter used for cooking. This way, you have more control over the amount of butter added, and you can add more or less depending on the thickness of your dough (for thicker dough, it would be better to add twice instead of just once, so as to evenly coat both sides).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You can rest your dough for about 15 minutes if time permits. This makes it easier to handle the dough. It does not do much for the flavor from what I have noticed, but it made rolling into sheets a bit easier for me.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sweet and Sour Chicken</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/sweet-and-sour-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 21:59:06 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/sweet-and-sour-chicken/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have always loved sweet and sour chicken. When I was little, I used to eat this on vacations to New York, at a local mall in Middletown, New York. I wanted to recreate this taste, but without having to use tomato ketchup, as that is usually a little too processed for me (and also, I don&amp;rsquo;t always have it in my pantry). The result is this recipe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chicken breasts (cubed)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cornstarch&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Black pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sunflower oil (or other cooking oil with a high smoking point)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bell peppers (red and green)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ginger&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sugar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tomato paste&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Black vinegar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pineapple chunks (Optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pineapple juice (extra sweet) or lemon juice (extra sour) (Optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Serve with white rice&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Start by cubing your chicken breasts, seasoning them generously with salt and pepper. Afterwards, coat with cornstarch.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add a large amount of sunflower oil to a pan and fry your chicken until golden brown.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In the meantime, prepare the sauce by adding the following: soy sauce, black vinegar and tomato sauce in a 3:3:2 tbsp ratio. Also add about 2-3 cloves of garlic and some grated ginger to taste. Add your lemon/pineapple juice if you want. Finally, add sugar to taste.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Remove your chicken from the pan and leave them to rest on some paper towels to catch off excess oil. Store most of the oil in a container, and leave a small amount to cook your vegetables.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cut your bell peppers and white onion into large chunks and stir-fry them on medium-high heat. After a little while, also add your optional pineapple chunks for a more traditional recipe.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;After your onion has become nice and brown on the edges, add in your sauce and stir until thickened.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add your chicken at the end in order to keep them crispy for longer. Serve with white rice.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gochujang Chicken</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/gochujang-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 15:14:28 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/gochujang-chicken/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my first Korean recipe on this blog (cool). When I was out grocery shopping, I stumbled upon Gochujang, and it looked so good that i decided I simply HAD to make something with it. This is the result. Serve with rice.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Gochujang&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chicken breasts&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cornstarch&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Spring onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sugar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sesame oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Toasted sesame seeds (optional, garnish)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cooking oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cut your chicken breasts into cubes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Coat your chicken in a layer of cornstarch&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In a seperate bowl, prepare your sauce by mixing sugar, garlic, soy sauce, sesame oil and gochujang.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In a pan (or a wok if possible) stir fry your chicken breasts until it has become a bit crispy. Make sure to use a lot of oil, as otherwise the cornstarch will stick to the pan.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chop your white onion into large chunks.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once the chicken is crisp, remove some of the excess oil and add your spring onion and white onion.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, add your sauce to the pan and stir it until it has the right consistency.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meatballs in tomato sauce</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/tomato-meatballs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 18:11:37 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/tomato-meatballs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ok, so last week I was thinking about what I wanted to cook, when I stumbled upon some inspiration for meatballs in tomato sauce, thinking back to how delicious those were back when I visited Greece. Now I am not about to tell you that this is an authentic Greek recipe (it is more of an Italian recipe I believe), but this is an authentic Paul banger, and as such, I would love to share it with you all. If you don&amp;rsquo;t feel like rolling meatballs, you can also just use ground beef. This has the added benefit of making storage for later easier.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tikka Masala</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/tikka-masala/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 21:18:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/tikka-masala/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I always love the taste of Indian cuisine, and I usually turn to Indian food when I want a fix of rich and hearty flavours paired with a healthy feel. Today&amp;rsquo;s recipe is rather easy to make compared to other Indian curries, and it is an easy fix for when you crave something creamy. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if it can be classified as a weekday meal, but it is definetely easy enough to make it on a lazy sunday. You&amp;rsquo;ll probably have leftovers to boot.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mesa&#39;a&#39;ah</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/mesa-ah/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 08:22:49 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/mesa-ah/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There were too many eggplants in my fridge, so I decided to do something about that. I could have made my &lt;a href=&#34;https://paulstapel.com/recipes/melitzanosalata/&#34;&gt;melitzanosalata&lt;/a&gt;, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like that would be filling enough, and it was too cold outside to grill. That&amp;rsquo;s when I stumbled upon a dish I had never heard of before. Behold, the Egyptian dish &amp;ldquo;mesa&amp;rsquo;a&amp;rsquo;ah&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tomato paste (about 1 tsp)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Eggplants (Like, 2 or something)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Strained tomatoes (about 500 grams or something)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dried coriander&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cumin&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lots of olive oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic (about 6 cloves?)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dice your onion and mince your garlic. Add olive oil to a pot and cook your aromatics until fragrant and a little browned.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Start slicing your eggplants into disks (they will be grilled, so try to keep them thick enough). Afterwards, sprinkle them generously with salt and dried coriander.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add tomato paste to your pot and turn up the heat a little. Be careful not to burn the paste.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In a separate pan, grill your eggplant slices (in batches if they don&amp;rsquo;t fit in your pan).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To your pot, finally add your strained tomatoes and cumin to taste. Let it cook on medium heat while you finish grilling your eggplant.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, add your eggplant to your pot and cover it in the sauce. Serve wit pita.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Butter Lemon Pork</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/butter-lemon-pork/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 20:19:47 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/butter-lemon-pork/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So today, I tried to do something new with pork belly. Most of my recipes involving this ingredient are Chinese, and so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d spice things up a little by taking some more inspiration from the French kitchen. Be warned, this recipe is quite fatty, but otherwise it&amp;rsquo;s very easy to make and nutritious to boot.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Butter&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dried oregano&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt and Pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pork belly&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lemon juice&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Honey&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Water&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dark soy sauce (for color)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ginger (or ginger powder)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;High smoking point oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Serve with white rice.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;First, slice your pork belly into bite sized pieces and cover with a little salt, pepper and dried oregano.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add some oil to a heated pan. For added crisp and brownness from your pork, use a cast iron pan.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add your pork belly to a pan and let it crisp properly. Once it has browned, add in 2 thin slices of butter and keep cooking your pork until crisp.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Remove your pork and add in onion (in rings or slices). Leave it to brown for a while. For quick caramelisation, you may add some hot water to your pan and cover it with a lid. This way, your onion will come into contact with even more heat, quickening the process. This also prevents your onion from burning when you prepare the sauce.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In a sauce pan, add 2 thin slices of butter, a little bit of oil and your garlic. Stir it until it is fragrant and sauteed. For this sauce, it is up to your own taste, so keep tasting while cooking it so that you can adjust how much of your ingredients to add.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To your sauce, add the ginger, lemon juice and more dried oregano. To sweeten your sauce and counteract the sourness, add in honey to taste. After that, add a little water and dark soy sauce for coloring. Reduce the sauce until it is thick and keep adjusting your sauce until it is to your liking. If needed, you can add a cornstarch slurry to make it thicken faster.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add the sauce, pork and onion into your pan and stir a little until everything is covered.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scuffins</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/scuffins/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 20:22:45 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/scuffins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At first, I was planning on making scones. Because of a lack of better moulds, I decided to use a muffin tray, and the rest is history. This recipe yields about 12 medium-sized scuffins.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;500 grams of all-purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;200 grams of granulated sugar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;About 10 grams of baking powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2 eggs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;250 grams of butter&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;200 grams of crème fraîche&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;About 20 milliliters of milk&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;About 3 teaspoons of vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A pinch of salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Optionally, toppings like milk chocolate, blueberries or caramel&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A muffin tray&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;baking-plan&#34;&gt;Baking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Preheat an oven to 200 degrees Celsius.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add the flour, sugar, salt, and baking powder to a large bowl.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In small cubes or pieces, add in the butter while mixing your bowl. I mix using a mixer, but a whisk would work as well. Mix until you are left with a crumbly dough.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add in your vanilla extract, crème fraîche and eggs. Mix together until the dough becomes sticky and thick. Add in your milk incrementally to make your batter less thick. It should still be sticky!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Butter a muffin tray and fill it with your batter. I used two spoons to transfer the batter, as it will easily stick to your hands.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;With a glove (or your bare hands), push in your toppings. Use a bit more than you might initially think, as the flavours may be lost in the batter.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bake your scuffins in the oven for about 20 - 25 minutes, until they are golden brown.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Serve with clotted cream and jam. (for a quick and easy clotted cream, mix mascarpone and crème fraîche)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Burrito</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/burrito/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 07:38:59 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/burrito/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A good burrito recipe has been like the holy grail for me. I looove burritos, but I just wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to get them to taste quite right. This recipe is finally close to the taste I have been searching for.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ground beef&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Vegetable or olive oil.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lots of beans. I use kidney beans. They will be pasted.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;About 2 parts Salt, 1 part Pepper, 1 part Garlic powder, 4 parts Paprika powder, 8 parts Cumin. This will be your seasoning.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Optionally, you may add vegetables like bell pepper, carrots, leek or whatever you think will taste good. I like the extra variation each bite brings when you add some vegetables to this dish.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Water or beef stock (be careful with the salt content!).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;serve-with&#34;&gt;Serve with&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shredded cheese&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sour cream&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Guacamole&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White or brown rice&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tortillas&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jalapeños&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Optionally, tortilla chips.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Coat your pan lightly with oil and start browning the beef.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;While this is happening, blend your beans until they form a bean paste.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once the beef has been browned, remove it from your pan and start sweating your onions until translucent.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Now, add your optional vegetables and wait until they are done.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add back your ground beef and add your bean paste. Also add in your seasoning.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add some water or beef stock to deglaze your pan and let the water content reduce until the burrito filling has your desired texture. It should be thick and a little runny, but not watery.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Assemble your delicious burrito(s).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Melitzanosalata</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/melitzanosalata/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 07:12:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/melitzanosalata/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love cooking Greek food. Something about the balance of oils, fresh herbs and grilled meats just really gets me going. But Greek food can be more than just gyros and souvlaki. To give our vegetarians some love, and in order to diversify your Greek palette, let me introduce you to this lovely dish called Melitzanosalata (eggplant salad).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A few Eggplants&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Half a red onion (or a full shallot, if you want a more delicate flavour)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Olive oil, preferably extra virgin.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A clove of garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Apple vinegar (white vinegar also works, just use a bit less)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Some fresh parsley (can be subbed with oregano)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Feta cheese (for garnish, can be omitted)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Olives (for garnish, can be omitted)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Start by roasting your eggplants over a grill or open fire. This takes about 10 minutes, or until the eggplants become soft and mushy inside.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Start mixing together olive oil and vinegar in (roughly) a 4:1 ratio, also adding in a minced clove of garlic.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mince your red onion, and put it in a bowl. Add your mixture, and some chopped parsley.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Remove your eggplant from the fire, and scoop out the flesh. Process the flesh untill it has become a mush.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Optional step, you may want to squeeze out excess moisture with a towel, as it may dilute the flavor of your salad.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, mix everything together and add some feta cheese and olives to your salad as garnish.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sausage Stew</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/sausage-stew/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 21:05:34 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/sausage-stew/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This recipe is a Paul-certified classic. It is easy to make (only about 30 minutes), and is quite filling for when you are having a busy week.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sausage (pork works well)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cooking oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A (small) tin of tomato paste&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yellow onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bell peppers (different colors looks the nicest, doesn&amp;rsquo;t really matter for taste)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Beef broth&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garam masala (can sub for 5-spice)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dark soy sauce (for color and salt)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;First, cook your sausage in an oiled pan until golden brown. Get some Maillard reaction going.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Put the sausage aside and cut it into bit-sized pieces.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dice your onion and bell peppers, and heat them in the pan until most of the water has evaporated.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add your garlic and tomato paste, and let it cook until fragrant.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add your garam masala and pepper to a beef broth. You should be able to smell it.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add the seasoned beef broth and cooked sausage into the pan, and let the mixture reduce to a desired texture.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, add some dark soy sauce for color and salt.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Orange Chicken</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/orange-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 21:28:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/orange-chicken/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have to admit, this is a guilty pleasure of mine. I don&amp;rsquo;t make this often, as it can take a bit long to make, but I always enjoy it when I do. If you are looking for a sweet and unique taste, look no further than this recipe. I suggest serving this with white rice.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;for-the-meat&#34;&gt;For the meat&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chicken breasts (whole, or already cubed)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;All purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cornstarch&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;High smoke-point oil like peanut oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;for-the-sauce&#34;&gt;For the sauce&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A bunch of oranges (5 per kilo of chicken, more if you like it saucy)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Alternatively, you can use orange juice instead of fresh oranges&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A bit of sugar (If it isn&amp;rsquo;t sweet enough already)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ginger (or ginger powder)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cornstarch (to thicken the sauce)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Squeeze the oranges and strain the juice.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add some soy sauce, garlic powder, ginger, (optional sugar) and cornstarch to the mixture.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cut the chicken into bite sized pieces (TIP; use sciccors)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Create a batter by mixing the flour and cornstarch in a ratio of about 2/1. Add a bit of water until the batter is smooth and then add a little bit of oil untill the batter is only a little thick.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Heat up a pan of your oil untill very hot. You can check this by putting in a drop of your batter.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Coat your chicken in your batter, and start adding the pieces to your pan one by one. Do this slowly, so that the pieces won&amp;rsquo;t stick to eachother. Be careful with splashing, as the oil doesn&amp;rsquo;t like the water of the batter. To prevent splashing, add some salt to the oil. Put the browned pieces onto a seperate plate.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once all chicken has been fried once, you can choose to fry them again. this will make the coloring nicer, and it will add a nicer crisp to the chicken.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Store the oil somewhere for later use, and pour your sauce mixture into the hot pan. Let it reduce at high heat untill the sauce becomes thick to your liking. I&amp;rsquo;d suggest letting it thicken a little longer than you&amp;rsquo;d think.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, add back the chicken, and coat it in the sauce. Serve it while it&amp;rsquo;s hot, and try not to let it rest too long, because it will lose its crisp.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hoisin Ground Beef</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/hoisin-ground-beef/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 10:51:32 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/hoisin-ground-beef/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This recipe is both simple and delicious. This is easy comfort food for when I don&amp;rsquo;t feel like cooking for too long.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ground beef&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yellow onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Spring onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(Optional) Shallots&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garden peas&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hoisin sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Oyster sauce (optional, adds umami)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shaoxing cooking wine (to deglaze)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sesame oil (optional, but it really is a finishing touch)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White rice&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Wash the rice and cook it. cut up the spring onion and reserve the greens for garnishing.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cut up the onions, shallots and garlic, and let them sweat on a medium heat, until they turn translucent.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mix in the ground beef, and let it brown on high heat&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add about a tablespoon of cooking wine to deglaze.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add soy sauce, hoisin sauce, oyster sauce and sesame oil in a 1/2/2/1 ratio.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, add the garden peas and garnish&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mongolian Beef</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/mongolian-beef/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 10:01:01 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/mongolian-beef/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This recipe makes for a delicious and saucy beef dish. It takes some time to prepare, but is well worth it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;marinade&#34;&gt;Marinade&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Beef (I like using cheap steak for this, as the baking soda will tenderize it anyway)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shaoxing (cooking wine, sub with any rice wine)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(Dark) soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Oyster sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Some white pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A little cooking oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Baking soda (To tenderize the meat)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cornstarch (To keep the beef moist)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;sauce&#34;&gt;Sauce&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soy Sauce (light or dark)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sugar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Oyster Sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shaoxing (To deglaze)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A little cornstarch + water to thicken&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;veggies-for-stir-fry&#34;&gt;Veggies (for stir-fry)&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ginger&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Spring onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bell pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dried chili pepper (you can remove this if you don&amp;rsquo;t like spicy food)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cut the beef into strips and mix it with the marinade (add the cornstarch at the end) Let it sit for at least 15 minutes, but preferably a few hours.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cut the vegetables&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Prepare the sauce in a small bowl, with a separate bowl for the cornstarch slurry&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If time permits, I suggest you deep fry your beef in vegetable oil. This way, the texture will turn out crispy while the beef remains moist. Else, you can simply stir fry your mongolian beef instead.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Remove some of the oil and stir fry the veggies.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add in the sauce and the beef, and season to taste.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
