<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Difficulty 3|5 on Paul&#39;s Particles</title>
    <link>http://localhost:50145/categories/difficulty-35/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Difficulty 3|5 on Paul&#39;s Particles</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 20:19:47 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:50145/categories/difficulty-35/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Butter Lemon Pork</title>
      <link>http://localhost:50145/recipes/butter-lemon-pork/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 20:19:47 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:50145/recipes/butter-lemon-pork/</guid>
      <description>So today, I tried to do something new with pork belly. Most of my recipes involving this ingredient are Chinese, and so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d spice things up a little by taking some more inspiration from the french kitchen. Be warned, this recipe is quite fatty, but otherwise it&amp;rsquo;s very easy to make and nutritious to boot.&#xA;Ingredients Butter Dried oregano Salt and Pepper Pork belly Lemon White onion Garlic Water Dark soy sauce (for color) Ginger (or ginger powder) High smoking point oil Serve with white rice.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scuffins</title>
      <link>http://localhost:50145/recipes/scuffins/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 20:22:45 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:50145/recipes/scuffins/</guid>
      <description>At first, I was planning on making scones. Because of a lack of better moulds, I decided to use a muffin tray, and the rest is history. This recipe yields about 12 medium-sized scuffins.&#xA;Ingredients 500 grams of all-purpose flour 200 grams of granulated sugar About 10 grams of baking powder 2 eggs 250 grams of butter 200 grams of crème fraîche About 20 milliliters of milk About 3 teaspoons of vanilla extract A pinch of salt Optionally, toppings like milk chocolate, blueberries or caramel A muffin tray Baking plan Preheat an oven to 200 degrees Celsius.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Burrito</title>
      <link>http://localhost:50145/recipes/burrito/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 07:38:59 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:50145/recipes/burrito/</guid>
      <description>A good burrito recipe has been like the holy grail for me. I looove burritos, but I just wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to get them to taste quite right. This recipe is finally close to the taste I have been searching for.&#xA;Ingredients Ground beef White onion Vegetable or olive oil. Lots of beans. I use kidney beans. They will be pasted. About 2 parts Salt, 1 part Pepper, 1 part Garlic powder, 4 parts Paprika powder, 8 parts Cumin.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Melitzanosalata</title>
      <link>http://localhost:50145/recipes/melitzanosalata/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 07:12:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:50145/recipes/melitzanosalata/</guid>
      <description>I love cooking Greek food. Something about the balance of oils, fresh herbs and grilled meats just really gets me going. But Greek food can be more than just gyros and souvlaki. To give our vegetarians some love, and in order to diversify your Greek palette, let me introduce you to this lovely dish called Melitzanosalata (eggplant salad).&#xA;Ingredients A few Eggplants Half a red onion (or a full shallot, if you want a more delicate flavour) Olive oil, preferably extra virgin.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sausage Stew</title>
      <link>http://localhost:50145/recipes/sausage-stew/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 21:05:34 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:50145/recipes/sausage-stew/</guid>
      <description>This recipe is a Paul-certified classic. It is easy to make (only about 30 minutes), and is quite filling for when you are having a busy week.&#xA;Ingredients Sausage (pork works well) Cooking oil A (small) tin of tomtato paste Yellow onion Garlic Bell peppers (different colors looks the nicest, doesn&amp;rsquo;t really matter for taste) Beef broth Garam masala (can sub for 5-spice) Pepper Dark soy sauce (for color and salt) Cooking plan First, cook your sausage in an oiled pan until golden brown.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Orange Chicken</title>
      <link>http://localhost:50145/recipes/orange-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 21:28:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:50145/recipes/orange-chicken/</guid>
      <description>I have to admit, this is a guilty pleasure of mine. I don&amp;rsquo;t make this often, as it can take a bit long to make, but I always enjoy it when I do. If you are looking for a sweet and unique taste, look no further than this recipe. I suggest serving this with white rice.&#xA;Ingredients For the meat Chicken breasts (whole, or already cubed) All purpose flour Cornstarch High smoke-point oil like peanut oil For the sauce A bunch of oranges (5 per kilo of chicken, more if you like it saucy) Alternatively, you can use orange juice instead of fresh oranges A bit of sugar (If it isn&amp;rsquo;t sweet enough already) Soy sauce Garlic powder Ginger (or ginger powder) Cornstarch (to thicken the sauce) Cooking plan Squeeze the oranges and strain the juice.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hoisin Ground Beef</title>
      <link>http://localhost:50145/recipes/hoisin-ground-beef/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 10:51:32 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:50145/recipes/hoisin-ground-beef/</guid>
      <description>This recipe is both simple and delicious. This is easy comfort food for when I don&amp;rsquo;t feel like cooking for too long.&#xA;Ingredients Ground beef Garlic Yellow onion Spring onion Shallots Soy sauce Hoisin sauce Oyster sauce (optional, adds umami) Shaoxing cooking wine (to deglaze) Sesame oil (optional, but it really is a finishing touch) White rice Cooking plan Wash the rice and cook it. cut up the spring onion and reserve the greens for garnishing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mongolian Beef</title>
      <link>http://localhost:50145/recipes/mongolian-beef/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 10:01:01 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:50145/recipes/mongolian-beef/</guid>
      <description>This recipe makes for a delicious and saucy beef dish. It takes some time to prepare, but is well worth it.&#xA;Ingredients Marinade Beef (I like using cheap steak for this) Shaoxing (Cooking Wine) (Dark) Soy Sauce Oyster sauce Some white pepper A little cooking oil Baking Soda (To tenderize the meat) Cornstarch (To keep the beef moist) Sauce Soy Sauce (light or dark) Sugar Oyster Sauce Shaoxing (To deglaze) A little cornstarch + water to thicken Veggies (for stir-fry) Garlic Ginger Spring onion Onion Bell pepper Dried chili pepper (you can remove this if you don&amp;rsquo;t like spicy food) Cooking plan Cut the beef into strips and mix it with the marinade (add the cornstarch at the end) Let it sit for at least 15 minutes, but preferably a few hours.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
