<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Recipes on Paul&#39;s Particles</title>
    <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Recipes on Paul&#39;s Particles</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 07:47:32 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://paulstapel.com/recipes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Peanut Noodles</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/peanut-noodles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 07:47:32 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/peanut-noodles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On a budget? Check! Done in under 10 minutes? Check! Vegan? Check! Delicous? CHEACHK (check in Portuguese?).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Whole peanuts&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sesame seeds&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Peanut butter&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Noodles (I use udon noodles)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Spring onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soy sauce (I use dark, but light works as well for a stronger flavor)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Vinegar (I use Chinkiang vinegar)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chili oil (Lao Gan Ma also works)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ginger&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Grind some of your peanuts and leave some whole for a more interesting texture. Then, start by toasting your whole peanuts and sesame seeds.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next, finely mince your garlic and ginger, add chili oil to your pan and sauté your aromatics.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Meanwhile, bring some water to a boil and cook your noodles per package instructions.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once fragrant, add the white part of your spring onion as well.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To your pan, add some vinegar, soy sauce and some scoops of peanut butter to taste. Mix well, as the peanut butter needs to be fully encorporated into the sauce.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally mix your noodles through your sauce and garnish with the green part of your spring onion.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chili Beans</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/chili-beans/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 07:38:52 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/chili-beans/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For this dish, I was inspired by a recipe from a book I was recently given (One Piece: Pirate Recipes xD). It is a very simple recipe, and I wished to expand upon it to make it even tastier.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kidney beans&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ground beef (or pork, or mixed)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ground cayenne pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Paprika powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tomato paste&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Diced chipotle peppers in adobo sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cooking oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Start by seasoning your ground beef with ground cayenne pepper, salt and paprika powder.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To a pan add some cooking oil and brown your ground beef.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Meanwhile, start mincing your onion and garlic. Once your ground beef is done, remove it from your pan and add the onion. After it has turned translucent, add your garlic.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add some tomato paste to your pan, along with the diced chipotle peppers in adobo sauce. Stir and let it deepen its color a little before adding some water and your kidney beans.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Let the beans simmer for a bit until most of the water has evaporated. Finally, add back in your ground beef and season to taste with your spices.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This recipe pairs well with nachos, tortillas or rice for example.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Matcha Cookie</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/matcha-cookie/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 12:34:53 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/matcha-cookie/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When it comes to baked goods, I really love freshly baked cookies. As it happens, I also love matcha tea. It was a no-brainer to combine the two of them, and following some hints I found online about creating the perfect cookie, I finally managed to nail down this recipe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;120 grams of butter&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 tbsp of matcha&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;120 grams of all-purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;10 grams of bread flour or cornstarch&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2.5 grams of baking powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1/2 teaspoon of salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A few drops of vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If you have brown sugar; 50 grams white sugar and 90 grams brown sugar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If you don&amp;rsquo;t have brown sugar; 130 grams of sugar plus about 1.5 tbsp of honey&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2 eggs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;100 grams of white chocolate&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;baking-plan&#34;&gt;Baking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Take some butter and brown it on medium heat. (Heat it up until the milk solids give the butter a brown color)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;While your butter is browning, mix your flour, cornstarch, baking powder, salt and matcha until combined.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In another bowl, mix your sugars (and honey).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add brown butter to your sugar, and mix for a little. Add your vanilla extract and eggs.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mix in your dry ingredients and stir until it forms a smooth paste. This may take some muscle. Alternatively, you may use a mixer.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cut up some chunks of white chocolate and mix them into your dough.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Put your bowl in the fridge for about an hour, until it has chilled completely.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;When you want to bake your cookies, start by preheating the oven to 180 degrees Celcius.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Make scoops from your dough and place them on a baking tray lined with parchement paper. Give them some space, as they will spread out in the oven.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Put your cookies in the oven for about 12 minutes. Let them cool a little before eating, as they will be very soft when they leave your oven.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gunter Chicken Masala</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/gunter-chicken-masala/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 07:12:39 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/gunter-chicken-masala/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been making a lot of masala recently, and this gunter chicken masala was really tasty when I tried making it. I have made some adjustments to my first iteration, and I hope you enjoy cooking this! Do keep in mind, this dish is among the spiciest I&amp;rsquo;ve made so far, so reduce the amount of dried chili&amp;rsquo;s if that is a problem.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;masala-powder&#34;&gt;Masala powder&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;About 4-5 dried chili&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2 tsp coriander seeds&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 tsp black peppercorns&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 tsp cumin seeds&#xA;To make the masala powder, first toast the whole spices and dried chili&amp;rsquo;s whole, and put them in a spice blender.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;masala-paste&#34;&gt;Masala paste&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2 tsp masala powder (that you just made)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;About 1 - 2 tsp minced ginger&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;About 4-5 cloves of garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A little water to make it a paste&#xA;We will use this masala paste to marinate the chicken. Again, mix all ingredients in a blender&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;marinade&#34;&gt;Marinade&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chicken (bone-in)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tumeric powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Masala paste (that you just made)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garam masala (only a little)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kashmiri chili powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Some salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yoghurt/lemon (yoghurt for more oily sauce, lemon for a bit of a drier curry)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;curry&#34;&gt;Curry&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mustard seeds&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cumin seeds&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Red onions&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tomato passata&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Masala powder (that you just made)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Vegetable oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chopped koriander (for garnish, optional but recommended)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cinnamon (to taste, for seasoning, optional but recommended)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In a pan, add some oil and start by cooking the mustard seeds and cumin seeds until fragrant.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next, add your red onions and stir for a while on medium-high heat, until they become a little browned and crispy.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In a food processor, blend the contents in your pan into a smooth paste. We will add this back later.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In your now cleared pan, start roasting the chicken on high heat. You want your chicken to be browned and almost cooked through.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next, add your tomato passata into the pan, and stir back in your onion paste.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Season with your masala powder, some optional cinnamon (for a little bit of a sweeter note to balance the spicy flavors) and top with your chopped koriander&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eel Brioche Amuse</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/eel-brioche-amuse/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 13:09:16 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/eel-brioche-amuse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My friend Levi and I usually like to cook when we meet up. He is active in the culinary world as a host, and before that he has also worked in the kitchen for a while. It helps that we both have a soft spot for good food :). Last week, he surpised me with an amuse that he had devised himself. It was light yet incredibly tasty, and for how easy it was to make, it left a fancy impression. To honor him, I&amp;rsquo;d like to share this recipe on my blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Saagwala</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/saagwala/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 21:13:47 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/saagwala/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am becoming a little obsessed with Indian cuisine, and while searching for new things to cook I stumbled upon Saagwala, and because I am a large fan of spinach, I simply had to try this. I find it is best served with Naan, but Roti and rice would also complement it quite well.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;marinate&#34;&gt;Marinate&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chicken (bone-in)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cooking oil (1 tbsp)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yoghurt (full) (enough to cover)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cayenne powder (2 tsp)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garam masala (2 tsp)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Coriander powder (2 tsp)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cumin powder (1 tsp)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fenugreek seeds (1 tsp)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;tumeric powder (1/2 tsp)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;curry&#34;&gt;Curry&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Spinach (a load of spinach, about equal weight to your meat)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Vegetable oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White onions (minced)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic (minced)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ginger (grated)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tomato paste&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Red or green chili&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Heavy cream (yoghurt would also work)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mint leafs (fresh, but dried also works)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cumin powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Coriander powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garam masala&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tumeric powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cayenne powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Start by marinating your chicken beforehand. Leave for at least 1 hour, but for about 6 hours or more if possible. Mix all of your marinate ingredients.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Preheat your oven to 200 degrees Celcius. Once it is warm, place your chicken on a baking sheet lined with parchment and cook for 30 minutes, turning it over after 15 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;While this is happening, boil some water and cook your spinach for about 5 minutes, until it has wilted completely. Once your spinach is done, drain it and blend it into a smooth paste.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In a large pan, start by heating up some vegetable oil and stir frying your white onions, garlic and ginger.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once browned a little, add your chili pepper and tomato paste, stiring all the while.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next, add your spices. Cumin powder, coriander powder, garam masala, tumeric powder and cayenne powder.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Stir back in your spinach and cover with heavy cream or yoghurt. Mix your curry well and let it cook through a little. If it is too thick, you may add some water or coconut milk.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;When your chicken is done, add it back to your curry.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garnish with fresh mint leafs. You may add some swirls of heavy cream or yoghurt for garnish as well.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shoyu Ramen</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/shoyu-ramen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 20:44:11 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/shoyu-ramen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shoyu ramen is an amazing dish that can be extended to your liking very easily. The name of this ramen dish comes from the addition of soy sauce to your broth (Shoyu = Japanese soy sauce). As this recipe can be made with lots of different ingredients, I will simply suggest some of the ingredients you could add to your ramen. This recipe may take some multi-tasking if you are adding a lot of toppings, so prepping well is recommended!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Korma</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/chicken-korma/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 20:52:55 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/chicken-korma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am always delighted when I try a new Indian recipe, and today was no different. I have eaten quite some Korma during my last trip to Singapore, and now I am happy to announce that I have managed to bring this flavor home. Enjoy this korma with white rice or naan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;marinade&#34;&gt;Marinade&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chicken (bone-in)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garam masala&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Greek yoghurt (any fatty yoghurt will do)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Paprika powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kurkuma/tumeric powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ginger (fresh or alternatively ground)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic (fresh or alternatively ground)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;curry&#34;&gt;Curry&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ghee (or cooking oil)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Greek yoghurt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ground cardemom&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garam Masala&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White onion (We will caramelise, but for a more traditional flavor, deep fry the onion)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cashew nuts (for extra creaminess, normally tomatoes are added, but I prefer cashew nuts)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Green (or red) chilis&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cinnamon (stick, or ground)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cloves (whole or ground)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Nutmeg (grated or ground)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Coriander powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fresh coriander leafs and/or mint leafs (or dried works fine as well)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bay leaf (optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mace (optional, but traditional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Start by marinating the chicken with all of the ingredients. Let it sit for about half an hour, or longer if time permits.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In a pan, heat up some ghee or oil and add some of your cardemom, until fragrant. Meanwhile, chop up your white onion into small chunks.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add your white onion into the pan and let it caramelise (or at least brown) on medium heat. Add a pinch of salt to speed up this process, as this will draw out the moisture. Near the end of the process, add your cashew nuts and chili pepper.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Put everything in this pan inside of a blender, along with enough yoghurt to cover it all. This will be a paste to add creaminess and flavor to your curry.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add some more ghee or oil to your pan and start by toasting your cinnamon, cloves, bay leaf, mace and some more cardemom.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once they are fragrant, add your chicken to the pan and let it cook on medium-high heat until it is (almost) cooked through.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next, add back your blended paste along with some hot water and season with garam masala and ground coriander.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, season to taste with some salt, garam masala, nutmeg and ground cloves (be careful with the amount you add!)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garnish with fresh koriander leafs and/or mint leafs, and serve with white rice or naan.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Festival</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 09:40:40 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/festival/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I really like &lt;a href=&#34;https://paulstapel.com/recipes/jerk-chicken/&#34;&gt;my take on jerk chicken&lt;/a&gt;, which is why I decided to try a side-dish to complement it. I eventually settled on this classic Jamaican treat: festivals. It is quick and easy to make, and can even be enjoyed as a dessert with some added sugar.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Flour (500 grams)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cornmeal (60 grams) (or substitute with breadcrumbs)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Baking powder (25 grams)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Brown sugar (2 - 4 table spoons, depending on how sweet you like it)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cocounut milk (200 milliliters)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Butter (50 grams) (softened or melted)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A pinch of salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cinnamon (3/4 - 1 tsp)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Grated/powdered nutmeg (A hint, about 1/4 - 1/2 tsp)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Oil to fry in (I used sunflower oil)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In a pan on medium to high, heat up your cooking oil. We will fry the festivals in this. The temperature should not be too high, as it will cause the dough to not cook properly on the inside.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In a bowl, start by quickly mixing your dry ingredients.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Work in your butter, and then incrementally mix in your coconut milk until you get a singular clump of dough. The dough should be a little flaky, and should easily break apart when stretched.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Let your dough rest for at least 10 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;From the dough, roll small cylinders of medium thickness. Fit as many as you can in your pan, but be careful not to overcrowd, as they grow when you place them in the oil. Once they turn a nice golden brown color, remove from the oil and lay on some paper towels to drain off excess oil.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Keep frying until all of the dough has been depleted.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Queso</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/queso/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 09:19:17 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/queso/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I have guests around, I want to make something easy and filling that I can just put on the table and forget about. Dips are perfect for this, as it creates a central piece whereabout everyone can gather. I really like this recipe as a guilty pleasure, and would like to share it with you all now.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ground beef or chorizo (about 300 to 400 grams)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White onion (one large white onion)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Flour (2 tbsp)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Milk (1.5 cups, less if you want a more solid queso)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mozerella (2 pieces)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Old cheese (To taste)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Parmesan (To taste)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cilantro (a.k.a. coriander) (To taste)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt and black pepper (be mindful of salt content in your other ingredients) (To taste)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Diced chipotle peppers (optional, add extra rich flavor and makes the whole more varied)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Preheat your oven to 200 degrees Celcius.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In a skillet, brown your ground beef or heat up your chorizo. Season it with salt and pepper. While it is browning, chop up a white onion.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once browned, add your chopped onion and stir on high heat until translucent and a little browned.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add some flour to your pan and let it heat up for a bit. Then, add your milk as well.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add your mozerella, and grate your old cheese and parmesan. Add it to the pan and let it melt a bit.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Stir through some cilantro (and diced chipotle peppers) and further season to taste with more salt and pepper if necessary.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Put your skillet int he oven until you queso has bubbled up and has achieved a golden yellow color.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pico De Gallo</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/pico-de-gallo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 08:50:28 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/pico-de-gallo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love Mexican food, and I can never resist a good salsa. I wanted to start making more salsa whenever I make Mexican food from now on, and I decided to start with a pico de gallo, as it is well defined and a tried and true recipe. This is definetely not my own recipe, as I am just throwing ingredients in a bowl, but I will outline some of the things I do to make it taste even better.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kheer</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/kheer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 07:31:25 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/kheer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been making breakfast more of a part of my daily routine lately. I think it has something to do with the fact that a lot of SEA-countries have warm breakfast, and I felt more invigorated last time I visited. So I started experimenting with breakfast recipes, and I have now decided to make it an entire category. To start, i wanted to share this Kheer recipe, as it is easy to make and energising. If you add more sugar, it can also be a dessert.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mustard Béchamel Sauce</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/mustard-bechamel-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 07:29:04 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/mustard-bechamel-sauce/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I was looking for something to add some extra flavor to schnitzels, as I really like eating them, but they get a little plain after a while if you only add lemon. That&amp;rsquo;s why I thought of making some kind of mustard sauce, and ended up with this recipe. A friend of mine talked about making béchamel sauce using chicken stock, and after having tried this it actually tasted better than I expected, so I added it to this main recipe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jerk Chicken my way</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/jerk-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 10:54:29 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/jerk-chicken/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I combined my love for Jamaican food and inventing new foods to come up with a delicious take on jerk chicken. The result is this simple recipe that consists of simply grilling the chicken and then broiling it in the flavorsome jerk sauce. I usually serve this with a baguette, as the sauce is just heavenly for dipping.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am trying to experiment with measurements, as I&amp;rsquo;ve had quite some people approach me saying they would like to know exactly how much to add of each ingredient. Keep in mind that I don&amp;rsquo;t exactly measure my ingredients, and that these measurements are thus geusstimates of how much I usually add.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Traditional Teriyaki Sauce</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/traditional-teriyaki-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 03 Feb 2025 08:01:27 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/traditional-teriyaki-sauce/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So half a year ago, I shared with you a recipe for teriyaki sauce. Back then, I didn&amp;rsquo;t really have the ingredients to make traditional teryiyaki sauce, and thus I created an alternative that tasted close to the original in flavour. But of course, we must pay respect to tradition, and that&amp;rsquo;s why we&amp;rsquo;ll be making traditional teriyaki sauce today. For comparison, you can also try my &lt;a href=&#34;https://paulstapel.com/recipes/teriyaki-sauce/&#34;&gt;original recipe&lt;/a&gt; and see which you like best. From there, you can always iterate further on this recipe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sweet and Spicy Hoisin Beef Tips</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/sweet-and-spicy-hoisin-beef-bliss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 21:28:30 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/sweet-and-spicy-hoisin-beef-bliss/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love wokking, but it has been a bit too cold to use my wok in the last few months. Today however, I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t resist the urge to wok, and this delicious recipe is the result.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;marinade&#34;&gt;Marinade&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Beef tips&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Black pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hoisin sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cornstarch&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Baking powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sugar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;sauce&#34;&gt;Sauce&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hoisin sauce (2 tbsp) (1 tbsp if you like it a little less sweet)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chili garlic sauce (1 tbsp)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Honey (1 tbsp)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soy sauce (2 tbsp)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Water (2 tbsp)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sesame seeds (optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;for-wokking&#34;&gt;For wokking&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White or yellow onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Green peppers (to add some nice spice, don&amp;rsquo;t remove the seeds)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Spring onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bell peppers (can sub for green peppers if you don&amp;rsquo;t like spicy)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Vegetable oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Combine your marinade in a bowl and let it sit while you prepare your veggies and sauce. For this marinade, combine soy sauce and hoisin sauce in a 3/1 ratio. The cornstarch is meant to retain moisture for your beef tips, and the baking powder is a secret technique to make your meat more tender in a short amount of time.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next, prepare your sauce by mixing all ingredients in a bowl.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chop your veggies into large chunks.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Prepare your wok with some vegetable oil and wait until your wok is smoking hot.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add your veggies and stir-fry until browned a little.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next, add your beef and quickly stir-fry until browned and a little crispy.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, add your sauce and reduce until it creates a nice coating on your meat and veggies.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Serve with white rice&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roti</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/roti/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 17:23:35 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/roti/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love roti, and having now made it myself, I can safely say that its lovely flavor carries over to the home kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Flour (200 grams)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Butter (40 grams)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Butter (60+ grams) (used for the grilling of the roti)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Water (~100 grams after boiling)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt (1 teaspoon)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add together your butter, flour and a little salt.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Boil your water and let it cool to just below boiling temperature. Add it to your dough (this will melt the butter) and start mixing it. Use forks at first, and your hands after it has cooled down a bit.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Roll out your dough into thin sheets. The thinner they are, the better they will be cooked once they go into your pan.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cook your roti at high heat in a skillet or non-stick pan. For each roti you cook, coat the pan with butter and lay your roti on it. Wait until it bubbles up a little and starts to brown, and then flip it over. Your roti should be coated in the butter, so add more if you didn&amp;rsquo;t add enough.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;tips&#34;&gt;Tips&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You may want to pre-melt your butter used for cooking. This way, you have more control over the amount of butter added, and you can add more or less depending on the thickness of your dough (for thicker dough, it would be better to add twice instead of just once, so as to evenly coat both sides).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You can rest your dough for about 15 minutes if time permits. This makes it easier to handle the dough. It does not do much for the flavor from what I have noticed, but it made rolling into sheets a bit easier for me.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sweet and Sour Chicken</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/sweet-and-sour-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 21:59:06 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/sweet-and-sour-chicken/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have always loved sweet and sour chicken. When I was little, I used to eat this on vacations to New York, at a local mall in Middletown, New York. I wanted to recreate this taste, but without having to use tomato ketchup, as that is usually a little too processed for me (and also, I don&amp;rsquo;t always have it in my pantry). The result is this recipe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chicken breasts (cubed)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cornstarch&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Black pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sunflower oil (or other cooking oil with a high smoking point)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bell peppers (red and green)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ginger&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sugar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tomato paste&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Black vinegar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pineapple chunks (Optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pineapple juice (extra sweet) or lemon juice (extra sour) (Optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Serve with white rice&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Start by cubing your chicken breasts, seasoning them generously with salt and pepper. Afterwards, coat with cornstarch.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add a large amount of sunflower oil to a pan and fry your chicken until golden brown.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In the meantime, prepare the sauce by adding the following: soy sauce, black vinegar and tomato sauce in a 3:3:2 tbsp ratio. Also add about 2-3 cloves of garlic and some grated ginger to taste. Add your lemon/pineapple juice if you want. Finally, add sugar to taste.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Remove your chicken from the pan and leave them to rest on some paper towels to catch off excess oil. Store most of the oil in a container, and leave a small amount to cook your vegetables.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cut your bell peppers and white onion into large chunks and stir-fry them on medium-high heat. After a little while, also add your optional pineapple chunks for a more traditional recipe.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;After your onion has become nice and brown on the edges, add in your sauce and stir until thickened.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add your chicken at the end in order to keep them crispy for longer. Serve with white rice.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gochujang Chicken</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/gochujang-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 15:14:28 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/gochujang-chicken/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is my first Korean recipe on this blog (cool). When I was out grocery shopping, I stumbled upon Gochujang, and it looked so good that i decided I simply HAD to make something with it. This is the result. Serve with rice.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Gochujang&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chicken breasts&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cornstarch&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Spring onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sugar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sesame oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Toasted sesame seeds (optional, garnish)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cooking oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cut your chicken breasts into cubes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Coat your chicken in a layer of cornstarch&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In a seperate bowl, prepare your sauce by mixing sugar, garlic, soy sauce, sesame oil and gochujang.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In a pan (or a wok if possible) stir fry your chicken breasts until it has become a bit crispy. Make sure to use a lot of oil, as otherwise the cornstarch will stick to the pan.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chop your white onion into large chunks.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once the chicken is crisp, remove some of the excess oil and add your spring onion and white onion.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, add your sauce to the pan and stir it until it has the right consistency.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Htipiti</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/htipiti/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 14:47:30 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/htipiti/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is pronounced &amp;ldquo;tee-pee-tee&amp;rdquo; by the way. Serve with pita or something, idk, idc, I&amp;rsquo;m not your mom.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Feta cheese&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Red bell peppers&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Extra virgin olive oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Red wine vinegar or lemon juice&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Black pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Preheat your oven to 200 degrees Celcius&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cut the four sides of your bell peppers and reduce the stem. Lay them out on a baking tray and put them in the oven for roughly 25 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once your peppers are done, put them in a bowl and cover them to let them steam for another 10 to 20 minutes. This will make it easier to remove the skin of the peppers.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To a food processor, add feta cheese, your bell peppers (skin removed), a little red wine vinegar/lemon juice and some extra virgin olive oil.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, season to taste with salt and pepper.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>S&#39;mores in a pan</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/smores/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 14:24:19 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/smores/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I, like most people, like s&amp;rsquo;mores. Shame that I don&amp;rsquo;t really like camping that much :/ but a well. Luckily, I don&amp;rsquo;t have to miss out on this treat, as I can just use my oven to make s&amp;rsquo;mores in a pan.&#xA;I was originally not going to write down the recipe, but after struggling with the marshmallows sticking to the pan the first time, I decided it would be helpful to also explain an easy trick to prevent that from happening.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moussaka</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/moussaka/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 13:22:32 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/moussaka/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is no secret that I love greek food. My stomach simply can&amp;rsquo;t get enough of the delicous fatty recipes that Greek people have come up with. Among these hearty recipes,&#xA;moussaka stands out as one of my favorites. I made it for a birthday dinner last week, and the deliciousness is well worth the preperation time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;meat-filling&#34;&gt;Meat filling&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Beef mince&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tomato passata&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tomato concentrate&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bay leaves&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cinnamon (powder, sticks also work and give an even nicer taste)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Oregano&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sugar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(Cheap) red wine&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Olive oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Beef stock (cubes or homemade)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;besamel-sauce-not-a-typo&#34;&gt;Besamel sauce (not a typo)&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Butter (equal part butter to flower)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Flour&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Milk (cold)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Nutmeg&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Eggs (not vital, but help the sauce brown, creating a nicer color)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Parmesan&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;eggplant-bottom&#34;&gt;Eggplant bottom&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A bunch of eggplants&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;eggplant-bottom-1&#34;&gt;Eggplant bottom&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Start with the bottom of your moussaka by cutting your eggplant into circular slabs of about 1 cm thick.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sprinkle salt over your slabs and let the moisture be drawn out of the eggplant. Let them rest for about 30 minutes while you continue with your meat filling.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Preheat an oven to about 200 degrees Celcius.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;meat-filling-1&#34;&gt;Meat filling&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add some olive oil to a large pan and set it on medium heat. Finely chop up your onions and add them to the pot to caramelise.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;After your onion has browned, turn the heat to high and add your beef mince. Stir it until it has browned, and then add your garlic.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;After your garlic has become fragrant, add your cinnamon, oregano, salt and about a tbsp of sugar to taste. Stir for a bit, before adding wine to almost cover your meat.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;After the alcohol smell is gone, add your tomato concentrate and let it cook a little on high heat.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, add your tomato passata and cover your pan in beef stock. Let this reduce for a while, until filling has become rather thick.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;eggplant-bottom-2&#34;&gt;Eggplant bottom&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pat your eggplant dry of moisture and rub away some of the salt you have previously added.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On a baking tray (or multiple depending on how much you are making), lay out your eggplants and put them in the oven for about 30 minutes. You&amp;rsquo;ll know when they are done when they have become soft.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once done, take them out of the oven and lay them to rest while you prepare the besamel sauce.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Turn the oven to 180 degrees Celcius now, as that is the temperature we will be cooking the moussaka in.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;besamel-sauce&#34;&gt;Besamel sauce&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In a (large) sauce pan, melt your butter and let it sit until it becomes a little browned.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next, add an equal part flower and stir it into the butter (it is easier with slightly more butter if you are struggling with this sauce). You should get a paste that has a texture akin to wet sand, and it should be bubbling a little.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next, add in a bunch of cold milk (about 500 ml per 30 grams of butter/flour). Some people say you should add it incrementally, but I have found that adding it all in one batch helps make the sauce smoother.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Let this sauce simmer for a few minutes, until it has become thick enough to coat the back of a spoon. When you run your finger over the spoon, the line drawn should stay.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, stir in a little nutmeg, some eggs and a bunch of parmesan. The parmesan is what gives this sauce most of its flavor, so be generous.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;assembly&#34;&gt;Assembly&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In a cast iron pan, first layer your eggplant, cover that with meat filling, and finally cover it with your besamel sauce.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Put it in the oven for about 40 minutes, until golden brown.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Let it rest for a bit before serving for the best result.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Larb</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/larb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 13:06:08 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/larb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few years back, I had a trip to Thailand with my family. While there, we ate a lot of very delicious food, and I have been recreating the things I ate there quite often.&#xA;One thing that does bug me about doing this, however, is the fact that some of the ingredients can be quite troublesome to acquire. Not today however, as we will be making larb.&#xA;The ingredients used for this are quite easy to come by in your local Asian supermarket or even just the grocery store. Serve with rice, naan or even tortilla&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cowboy Butter</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/cowboy-butter/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 22:04:16 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/cowboy-butter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is one of my favorite sauces to pair with something like an entrecôte steak. It is also perfect for hamburgers and sausages. It becomes even better if you first cook your meat using this butter.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Butter&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mustard&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lemon juice&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Parsley&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Thyme&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cayenne pepper powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Smoked paprika powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A bunch of black pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chives (optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chili flakes (optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A little apple vinegar (optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mix all of the ingredients into a pan on low-medium heat. Taste and adjust until satisfied with the taste and texture.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beef/Pork Stroganoff</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/beef-stroganoff/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 21:19:53 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/beef-stroganoff/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;All jokes aside, this recipe results in a rich and creamy beef stroganoff. As pork is a lot cheaper where I live, I often use pork as instead of beef. This is still very tasty, but if you can, try making it with beef, as it will be even richer in flavor. You should serve it with pasta. I recommend serving this with pasta like tagliatelle, but mashed potatoes would also be verrryyy good I imagine. Without further ado, let&amp;rsquo;s get into this recipe :D&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pork Adobo</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/pork-adobo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 20:48:12 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/pork-adobo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My auntie Rose from the Philippines shared this awesome recipe with me recently, and i&amp;rsquo;ve made it a few times now. I will be sharing the base recipe with some optional ingredients you may add, but having cooked this dish in a few different ways now, I can safely say that all of them are delicous. Serve with white rice.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pork belly (or chicken for chicken adobo) (Use the bones seperately as well if you have them)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic (lots of it)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Olive oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;String beans (Optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Potatoes (Optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hard boiled egg (Optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White onion (Own addition, optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;for-the-marinade&#34;&gt;For the marinade&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White vinegar (I have found that Chinkiang black vinegar also works, but I prefer white)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Brown sugar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Black pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bay leafs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Warm water&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There are two ways to do the marinade. Firstly, you can add the marinade and salt to your pork and leave it to marinade overnight. Alternatively, you can salt the pork and cook it first, then add the marinade later. Either way, the marinade can be made by mixing all of the ingredients listed and adjusting to taste.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finely mince your garlic. Usually, I use about a foot of garlic. Make sure it is pasted or finely minced.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To a pot on high heat, add your pork (chicken) and brown it. After that is done, you may remove it from the pan and lower the heat.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next add your (optional, chopped) white onion and a (mandatory) lot of garlic to your pan and fry it untill browned.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If you have bones, add them now and cook them in the same oil.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next, you may add your optional string beans and potatoes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once the bones are done, you can add your pork (chicken) back into the pan and continue cooking for a minute before adding your sauce.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;While this is cooking, you may optionally boil some eggs to add to your pan.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Let this simmer on medium heat for a while, until the desired texture is acquired. Serve with white rice.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meatballs in tomato sauce</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/tomato-meatballs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 18:11:37 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/tomato-meatballs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ok, so last week I was thinking about what I wanted to cook, when I stumbled upon some inspiration for meatballs in tomato sauce, thinking back to how delicious those were back when I visited Greece. Now I am not about to tell you that this is an authentic Greek recipe (it is more of an Italian recipe I believe), but this is an authentic Paul banger, and as such, I would love to share it with you all. If you don&amp;rsquo;t feel like rolling meatballs, you can also just use ground beef. This has the added benefit of making storage for later easier.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brownie</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/brownie/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 17:35:12 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/brownie/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t bake often, but from time to time, I really enjoy filling my pantry with some sweet deliciousness. This brownie recipe is one of my favs when it comes to that purpose. You can store this brownie for later, but even better would be to scoop them right out of the pan and eat it while it&amp;rsquo;s hot.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;220 grams sugar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;120 grams butter&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;80 grams all-purpose flower&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;3 or 4 eggs (3 if you want it fudgy, 4 if you like them more solid)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;60 grams cacao powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A little bit of salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Optional vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Optional chocalate chips or chunks&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Optional whipped cream for serving&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;baking-plan&#34;&gt;Baking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Start by heating an oven to about 180 degrees Celcius.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Start by melting the butter in a heated skillet.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;When the butter is melted, add your sugar, mix it well.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once mixed, add your cacao powder and stir it through.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once this has been stirred, you may add some optional vanilla extract. half a teaspoon will do.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;After this, turn of the heat and stir your eggs through the brownie mixture.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next, add your flour and stir it until the mixture has turned brown.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, you may add your optional chocalate chips to the mixture however you may like.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Put the pan in the oven for about 20 (for gooey brownies) to 25 (for more firm brownies) minutes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tikka Masala</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/tikka-masala/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 21:18:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/tikka-masala/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I always love the taste of Indian cuisine, and I usually turn to Indian food when I want a fix of rich and hearty flavours paired with a healthy feel. Today&amp;rsquo;s recipe is rather easy to make compared to other Indian curries, and it is an easy fix for when you crave something creamy. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if it can be classified as a weekday meal, but it is definetely easy enough to make it on a lazy sunday. You&amp;rsquo;ll probably have leftovers to boot.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Garlixplosion Noodles</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/garlicsplosion-noodles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 08:19:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/garlicsplosion-noodles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The only way to make a good dish even gooder is to add an exuberant amount of garlic to it. That was exactly the premise of this little experiment. Adding a lot of garlic and seeing where it leads me. It turned out to be a delightful recipe that I have even decided to share her on my blog. Be warned, not for the faint of heart.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lots of garlic (I used about 2 bulbs, but adjust to your own tolerance/taste)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Noodles&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Zucchini&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ground beef or meatballs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chili oil (I use Lao Gan Ma)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A little vegetable oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Light soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Optional black bean sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To a pot, add some salted water and cook your noodles as per the instructions on the package.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next, mince the onion and cut up the zucchini into small pieces. If you&amp;rsquo;re not using a garlic press, mince your garlic.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add some vegetable oil to your pan and start by sweating the onions. After they are translucent, turn up the heat and add your zucchini and chili oil. Lastly, add your garlic (using a garlic press).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;At this point, you may add your meat. I used meatballs (cursed, I know), but ground beef also works great. Be sure to stir often, as otherwise your aromatics may burn.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;When your sauce has browned, add light soy sauce and optional black bean sauce to taste. I used a ratio of 3:1 for these ingredients. You can also add some more Lao Gan Ma if you want.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lastly, toss your noodles into your pan and stir carefully until it is covered in sauce.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbonara</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/carbonara/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 20:03:41 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/carbonara/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, yesterday I was craving some good &amp;lsquo;ol spaghetti. I usually go with a tomato sauce, but this time, I saw that I still had some parmigiano in my fridge. I simply couldn&amp;rsquo;t resist the urge to try something new, and ended up making this delicious carbonara. It may not be the healthiest, but it was definitely worth it in the end. I included a secret ingredient of miso paste in order to boost the umami content. Although I strongly recommend you put it, the dish will still turn out yummy if omitted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ants Climbing a Tree</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/ants-climbing-a-tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 20:38:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/ants-climbing-a-tree/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a long day of work, you probably don&amp;rsquo;t want to have to cook anything complicated. Whenever I have days like this, I like keeping it simple as well. Of course, simple does not necessarily mean bland, and this dish is both easy and flavorful. The name &amp;ldquo;Ants climbing a tree&amp;rdquo; stems from the fact that the small ingredients on top of the glass noodles look like ants climbing a tree. I&amp;rsquo;ll have to admit that I started cooking this dish purely because I thought the name sounded cute&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mesa&#39;a&#39;ah</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/mesa-ah/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Sep 2024 08:22:49 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/mesa-ah/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There were too many eggplants in my fridge, so I decided to do something about that. I could have made my &lt;a href=&#34;https://paulstapel.com/recipes/melitzanosalata/&#34;&gt;melitzanosalata&lt;/a&gt;, but I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel like that would be filling enough, and it was too cold outside to grill. That&amp;rsquo;s when I stumbled upon a dish I had never heard of before. Behold, the Egyptian dish &amp;ldquo;mesa&amp;rsquo;a&amp;rsquo;ah&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tomato paste (about 1 tsp)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Eggplants (Like, 2 or something)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Strained tomatoes (about 500 grams or something)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dried coriander&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cumin&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lots of olive oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic (about 6 cloves?)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dice your onion and mince your garlic. Add olive oil to a pot and cook your aromatics until fragrant and a little browned.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Start slicing your eggplants into disks (they will be grilled, so try to keep them thick enough). Afterwards, sprinkle them generously with salt and dried coriander.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add tomato paste to your pot and turn up the heat a little. Be careful not to burn the paste.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In a separate pan, grill your eggplant slices (in batches if they don&amp;rsquo;t fit in your pan).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To your pot, finally add your strained tomatoes and cumin to taste. Let it cook on medium heat while you finish grilling your eggplant.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, add your eggplant to your pot and cover it in the sauce. Serve wit pita.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Burger Sauce</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/burger-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 17:18:42 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/burger-sauce/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, I share a very simple recipe for a burger sauce. It&amp;rsquo;s easy to make and a lot more interesting than your usual mayonaise or ketchup that you put on your burger. When making burgers, I suggest you assemble the following: your buns, a leave of lettuce, some fried onions, gherkins/pickles, your patty and lastly this burger sauce.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mayonaise (250 grams)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mustard (30 grams)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 tbsp of white vinegar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;0.5 tbsp of apple vinegar (or just a little more white vinegar)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 tsp of garlic powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 tsp of onion powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 tsp of smoked paprika powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Literally just throw everything into a bowl, mix it, and finally let it cool for about 1 hour (or as long as possible if you need it sooner).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Butter Lemon Pork</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/butter-lemon-pork/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2024 20:19:47 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/butter-lemon-pork/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So today, I tried to do something new with pork belly. Most of my recipes involving this ingredient are Chinese, and so I thought I&amp;rsquo;d spice things up a little by taking some more inspiration from the French kitchen. Be warned, this recipe is quite fatty, but otherwise it&amp;rsquo;s very easy to make and nutritious to boot.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Butter&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dried oregano&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt and Pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pork belly&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lemon juice&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Honey&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Water&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dark soy sauce (for color)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ginger (or ginger powder)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;High smoking point oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Serve with white rice.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;First, slice your pork belly into bite sized pieces and cover with a little salt, pepper and dried oregano.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add some oil to a heated pan. For added crisp and brownness from your pork, use a cast iron pan.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add your pork belly to a pan and let it crisp properly. Once it has browned, add in 2 thin slices of butter and keep cooking your pork until crisp.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Remove your pork and add in onion (in rings or slices). Leave it to brown for a while. For quick caramelisation, you may add some hot water to your pan and cover it with a lid. This way, your onion will come into contact with even more heat, quickening the process. This also prevents your onion from burning when you prepare the sauce.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In a sauce pan, add 2 thin slices of butter, a little bit of oil and your garlic. Stir it until it is fragrant and sauteed. For this sauce, it is up to your own taste, so keep tasting while cooking it so that you can adjust how much of your ingredients to add.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To your sauce, add the ginger, lemon juice and more dried oregano. To sweeten your sauce and counteract the sourness, add in honey to taste. After that, add a little water and dark soy sauce for coloring. Reduce the sauce until it is thick and keep adjusting your sauce until it is to your liking. If needed, you can add a cornstarch slurry to make it thicken faster.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add the sauce, pork and onion into your pan and stir a little until everything is covered.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Japanese Curry</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/japanese-curry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 20:28:31 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/japanese-curry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After having been on a vacation to Vietnam and Singapore for three weeks (hence the gap in posts, haha), this is one cuisine I have fallen in love with. I simply had to get a recipe to make this myself, and in my opinion, I am quite close to mimicking the taste of the curries I&amp;rsquo;ve had in Singapore. Be warned, this recipe can take up to 2 hours. I suggest serving this dish with (white) rice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scuffins</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/scuffins/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 20:22:45 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/scuffins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At first, I was planning on making scones. Because of a lack of better moulds, I decided to use a muffin tray, and the rest is history. This recipe yields about 12 medium-sized scuffins.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;500 grams of all-purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;200 grams of granulated sugar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;About 10 grams of baking powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2 eggs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;250 grams of butter&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;200 grams of crème fraîche&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;About 20 milliliters of milk&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;About 3 teaspoons of vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A pinch of salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Optionally, toppings like milk chocolate, blueberries or caramel&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A muffin tray&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;baking-plan&#34;&gt;Baking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Preheat an oven to 200 degrees Celsius.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add the flour, sugar, salt, and baking powder to a large bowl.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In small cubes or pieces, add in the butter while mixing your bowl. I mix using a mixer, but a whisk would work as well. Mix until you are left with a crumbly dough.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add in your vanilla extract, crème fraîche and eggs. Mix together until the dough becomes sticky and thick. Add in your milk incrementally to make your batter less thick. It should still be sticky!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Butter a muffin tray and fill it with your batter. I used two spoons to transfer the batter, as it will easily stick to your hands.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;With a glove (or your bare hands), push in your toppings. Use a bit more than you might initially think, as the flavours may be lost in the batter.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bake your scuffins in the oven for about 20 - 25 minutes, until they are golden brown.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Serve with clotted cream and jam. (for a quick and easy clotted cream, mix mascarpone and crème fraîche)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Burrito</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/burrito/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 07:38:59 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/burrito/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A good burrito recipe has been like the holy grail for me. I looove burritos, but I just wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to get them to taste quite right. This recipe is finally close to the taste I have been searching for.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ground beef&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Vegetable or olive oil.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lots of beans. I use kidney beans. They will be pasted.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;About 2 parts Salt, 1 part Pepper, 1 part Garlic powder, 4 parts Paprika powder, 8 parts Cumin. This will be your seasoning.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Optionally, you may add vegetables like bell pepper, carrots, leek or whatever you think will taste good. I like the extra variation each bite brings when you add some vegetables to this dish.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Water or beef stock (be careful with the salt content!).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;serve-with&#34;&gt;Serve with&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shredded cheese&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sour cream&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Guacamole&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White or brown rice&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tortillas&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jalapeños&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Optionally, tortilla chips.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Coat your pan lightly with oil and start browning the beef.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;While this is happening, blend your beans until they form a bean paste.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once the beef has been browned, remove it from your pan and start sweating your onions until translucent.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Now, add your optional vegetables and wait until they are done.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add back your ground beef and add your bean paste. Also add in your seasoning.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add some water or beef stock to deglaze your pan and let the water content reduce until the burrito filling has your desired texture. It should be thick and a little runny, but not watery.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Assemble your delicious burrito(s).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OE (Onion &amp; Eggs)</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/egg-and-onion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 21:33:38 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/egg-and-onion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, we will be making OE. I&amp;rsquo;ll let you figure out what that means.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Onions&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Eggs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(also some pepper, salt and cooking oil)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;We will be using about one onion per one egg.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;For people that like the taste of onion, I suggest you let the onions sweat by using a medium-low heat, until the onions turn translucent. This takes about 10 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;For those of you that have time on their hands, let the onions caramelise on the same medium-low heat. This takes an additional 30 to 40 minutes, until they have turned brown and crisp.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add in the eggs and stir on a high heat, untill you have the consistency of scrambled eggs.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, add pepper and salt to taste.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tennessee Onion</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/tennessee-onion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 21:18:06 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/tennessee-onion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ok, so the description may have been a lie. I usually don&amp;rsquo;t barbecue because Dutch weather can be very unpredictable (Dutch struggles). Instead, I like to put stuff in the oven (like a true patriot). Therefore, this dish will be using our favorite inferno machine. The TTC (time to cook) is about an hour, so prepare it well in advance!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White onions&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shredded cheese (Gouda, because it melts well and because it&amp;rsquo;s Dutch)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Butter&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Paprika powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chopped parsley&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dried thyme&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dried oregano&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Aluminum foil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Preheat an oven to 160 degrees Celsius.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Start peeling the onions and cutting them into rings.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In a casserole, layer the onion rings. If you have lots of mouths to feed, make multiple layers.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On top of your layer of onion rings, add your herbs and cheese. Add a generous amount of cheese, but reserve some for later.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, add some small cubes of butter spread evenly throughout the dish and cover it with the aluminum foil. Put it in the oven and cook for 40 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;After 40 minutes, take out your casserole. Sprinkle over a little of your remaining cheese, and put it back into the oven, uncovered. Leave it in for another 20 minutes, and you&amp;rsquo;re ready to serve.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Souvlaki</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/souvlaki/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 07:26:17 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/souvlaki/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a lovely meaty dish that you can serve as a main course. With summer at its peak, you enjoy this dish on straight from the grill during a barbecue for example.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;marinade&#34;&gt;Marinade&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(extra virgin) olive oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Oregano&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sweet paprika powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Thyme (optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bay leaves&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Juice from a lemon&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;LOTS OF GARLIC&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt and pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chicken (cubed, which you&amp;rsquo;ll marinate)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mince the garlic. You should use enough that you can smell it. I used 8 cloves (slightly more than a bulb) per kilo last time.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mix everything into a ziplock bag or marinating bowl.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Stir in the chicken, and let it sit for an hour or preferably two (not for too long! The lemon will slowly cook the chicken, lessening its taste after a certain amount of time)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Skewer the chicken (or cook it in a skillet if you want). You can grill the skewers on a barbecue.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Melitzanosalata</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/melitzanosalata/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 07:12:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/melitzanosalata/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love cooking Greek food. Something about the balance of oils, fresh herbs and grilled meats just really gets me going. But Greek food can be more than just gyros and souvlaki. To give our vegetarians some love, and in order to diversify your Greek palette, let me introduce you to this lovely dish called Melitzanosalata (eggplant salad).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A few Eggplants&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Half a red onion (or a full shallot, if you want a more delicate flavour)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Olive oil, preferably extra virgin.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A clove of garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Apple vinegar (white vinegar also works, just use a bit less)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Some fresh parsley (can be subbed with oregano)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Feta cheese (for garnish, can be omitted)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Olives (for garnish, can be omitted)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Start by roasting your eggplants over a grill or open fire. This takes about 10 minutes, or until the eggplants become soft and mushy inside.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Start mixing together olive oil and vinegar in (roughly) a 4:1 ratio, also adding in a minced clove of garlic.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mince your red onion, and put it in a bowl. Add your mixture, and some chopped parsley.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Remove your eggplant from the fire, and scoop out the flesh. Process the flesh untill it has become a mush.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Optional step, you may want to squeeze out excess moisture with a towel, as it may dilute the flavor of your salad.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, mix everything together and add some feta cheese and olives to your salad as garnish.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sausage Stew</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/sausage-stew/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 21:05:34 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/sausage-stew/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This recipe is a Paul-certified classic. It is easy to make (only about 30 minutes), and is quite filling for when you are having a busy week.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sausage (pork works well)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cooking oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A (small) tin of tomato paste&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yellow onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bell peppers (different colors looks the nicest, doesn&amp;rsquo;t really matter for taste)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Beef broth&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garam masala (can sub for 5-spice)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dark soy sauce (for color and salt)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;First, cook your sausage in an oiled pan until golden brown. Get some Maillard reaction going.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Put the sausage aside and cut it into bit-sized pieces.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dice your onion and bell peppers, and heat them in the pan until most of the water has evaporated.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add your garlic and tomato paste, and let it cook until fragrant.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add your garam masala and pepper to a beef broth. You should be able to smell it.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add the seasoned beef broth and cooked sausage into the pan, and let the mixture reduce to a desired texture.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, add some dark soy sauce for color and salt.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sichuan Pork</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/sichuan-pork/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 21:56:30 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/sichuan-pork/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The recipe I referred to in my &lt;a href=&#34;https://paulstapel.github.io/write-in-blood/&#34;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;. The flavour can best be described as má là, a Chinese term meaning numbing ( má 麻) and spicy ( là 辣). The aroma is citrusy and deep, and the flavour leaves you wanting more. I suggest you serve this with rice. This recipe takes about 45 minutes, but it is well worth it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pork belly (without the rind)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Black pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;About a tablespoon of red Sichuan peppercorns (less if you can&amp;rsquo;t stand the numbing effect)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Five-spice powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;High smoke point cooking oil (like vegetable oil)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Star anise&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ginger&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;As much pepper as you can handle (and don&amp;rsquo;t be a wimp!)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Half a liter of bone or beef stock&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Honey&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shaoxing cooking wine (optional, to deglaze if necessary)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Black bean sauce (optional, adds some counterbalance umami to this spicy dish)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Start by toasting the star anise and red Sichuan peppercorns in a non-oiled pan until fragrant. Put aside the star anise for later use.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Grind the peppercorns into dust, along with some black pepper.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cut your pork belly into bite sized strips, and cover it in about a tablespoon of five-spice powder.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Heat up a wok with oil until smoking, and cook the pork belly until brown. Get some of that Maillard reaction goodness in there. If you want, you can deglaze your pan with some cooking wine.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Put the pork aside, and start sautéing the onion until browned. After a bit, add in your peppers as well.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add your pork back to the pan. Add the stock with your toasted star anise, some slices of ginger and the ground powder of the peppercorn and black pepper. Let your mixture simmer until it has been reduced to about 1/3rd of what you started with. This may take a while.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;After your broth has been reduced to satisfaction, you can choose to take out the pork and add it back in at the last stage. This makes cooking the sauce easier, and it makes sure you don&amp;rsquo;t overcook the pork. It will still be delicious if you don&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To your broth, add some soy sauce, a generous helping of honey (at least 2-3 eating spoons) and some optional black bean sauce. Stir on high heat until the sauce has thickened.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, add everything back together, fish out the star anise and ginger, and serve with white rice.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Egg Drop Soup</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/egg-drop-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 21:12:21 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/egg-drop-soup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve started getting into making soup recently. This is new territory for me, but I decided to give it a try after pondering what to do with the leftover chinese cabbage that had been living rent-free in my fridge for too long. Behold! This soup was the result.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chinese Cabbage&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;About 1 liter of chicken stock&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Eggs (about 3)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White onion (can be omitted)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sesame oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Powdered or grated ginger&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt and (preferably white) pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Scallion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A little bit of cooking oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chop up your onions, garlic and scallion (put aside the green for garnish).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In a deep pot, start sweating the onion and scallion in a little bit of oil. After a few minutes, add the garlic as well.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Meanwhile, start tearing the cabbage apart with your hands. Doing it this way gives you nice and irregular pieces, which is nicer for the texture than when the cabbage is chopped.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add the chicken stock and add ginger, sesame oil, salt and pepper to taste. If you&amp;rsquo;re not sure, you can also add these ingredients after the next step, but I have found this to be less tasty.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add in the cabbage, and cover the pot with a lid. Leave it be for about 10 minutes, untill the cabbage has wilted.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, beat your eggs in a bowl. While stiring with one hand, slowly drizzle in the egg. This creates the signature egg ribbons associated with this dish. Let it rest for a few minutes and you&amp;rsquo;re ready to serve!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Orange Chicken</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/orange-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 21:28:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/orange-chicken/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have to admit, this is a guilty pleasure of mine. I don&amp;rsquo;t make this often, as it can take a bit long to make, but I always enjoy it when I do. If you are looking for a sweet and unique taste, look no further than this recipe. I suggest serving this with white rice.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;for-the-meat&#34;&gt;For the meat&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chicken breasts (whole, or already cubed)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;All purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cornstarch&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;High smoke-point oil like peanut oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;for-the-sauce&#34;&gt;For the sauce&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A bunch of oranges (5 per kilo of chicken, more if you like it saucy)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Alternatively, you can use orange juice instead of fresh oranges&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A bit of sugar (If it isn&amp;rsquo;t sweet enough already)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ginger (or ginger powder)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cornstarch (to thicken the sauce)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Squeeze the oranges and strain the juice.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add some soy sauce, garlic powder, ginger, (optional sugar) and cornstarch to the mixture.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cut the chicken into bite sized pieces (TIP; use sciccors)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Create a batter by mixing the flour and cornstarch in a ratio of about 2/1. Add a bit of water until the batter is smooth and then add a little bit of oil untill the batter is only a little thick.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Heat up a pan of your oil untill very hot. You can check this by putting in a drop of your batter.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Coat your chicken in your batter, and start adding the pieces to your pan one by one. Do this slowly, so that the pieces won&amp;rsquo;t stick to eachother. Be careful with splashing, as the oil doesn&amp;rsquo;t like the water of the batter. To prevent splashing, add some salt to the oil. Put the browned pieces onto a seperate plate.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once all chicken has been fried once, you can choose to fry them again. this will make the coloring nicer, and it will add a nicer crisp to the chicken.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Store the oil somewhere for later use, and pour your sauce mixture into the hot pan. Let it reduce at high heat untill the sauce becomes thick to your liking. I&amp;rsquo;d suggest letting it thicken a little longer than you&amp;rsquo;d think.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, add back the chicken, and coat it in the sauce. Serve it while it&amp;rsquo;s hot, and try not to let it rest too long, because it will lose its crisp.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mint Dip</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/mint-dip/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 21:09:25 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/mint-dip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I am looking more into the indian cuisine. To start things off, I made a simple mint dip to eat with a meal, or just to dip naan in.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yoghurt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mint leaves (dried if fresh isn&amp;rsquo;t available)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lemon juice&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A clove of garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt and pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finely chop the garlic and mint leaves&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mix the ingredients to taste&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hoisin Ground Beef</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/hoisin-ground-beef/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 10:51:32 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/hoisin-ground-beef/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This recipe is both simple and delicious. This is easy comfort food for when I don&amp;rsquo;t feel like cooking for too long.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ground beef&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yellow onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Spring onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(Optional) Shallots&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garden peas&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hoisin sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Oyster sauce (optional, adds umami)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shaoxing cooking wine (to deglaze)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sesame oil (optional, but it really is a finishing touch)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White rice&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Wash the rice and cook it. cut up the spring onion and reserve the greens for garnishing.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cut up the onions, shallots and garlic, and let them sweat on a medium heat, until they turn translucent.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mix in the ground beef, and let it brown on high heat&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add about a tablespoon of cooking wine to deglaze.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add soy sauce, hoisin sauce, oyster sauce and sesame oil in a 1/2/2/1 ratio.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, add the garden peas and garnish&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bbq Sauce</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/bbq-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 18:57:14 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/bbq-sauce/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I really enjoy this bbq-sauce with pulled pork or as a glaze for spare-ribs.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ketchup&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Worcester Sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mustard&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Vinegar``&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Onion powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt, pepper and sugar to taste&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Put it all into a pan and stir over low heat. Go easy on the mustard and vinegar.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teriyaki Sauce</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/teriyaki-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 18:50:31 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/teriyaki-sauce/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love eating this sauce with, for example, chicken and noodles. Do note that this sauce is by no means traditional, and is a take for the home kitchen for people that don&amp;rsquo;t have the ingredients to make traditional teriyaki sauce. I also have &lt;a href=&#34;https://paulstapel.com/recipes/traditional-teriyaki-sauce/&#34;&gt;a more traditional recipe&lt;/a&gt; on my blog, so give that one a try as well, and see for yourself which you like best!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sesame seeds (optional, adds flavour and thickens sauce)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soy Sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Honey&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sugar (only a little if you like it less sweet)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Grated ginger&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sesame oil (optional, ads nice sesame flavours)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Some water&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cornstarch (Add if you like a thicker sauce)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add all ingredients to a pan, and stir over medium heat until desired taste and texture is achieved. Go easy on the sesame oil.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tzatziki</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/tzatziki/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 14:03:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/tzatziki/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a trip to Greece, I fell in love with greek cuisine. Of course, you cant say Greek without Tzatziki, and so I will share this easy recipe for this beloved sauce.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Greek yoghurt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Vinegar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Olive oil (I like extra virgin)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dill&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cucumber&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Some salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;preparation&#34;&gt;Preparation&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finely grate a cucumber and wring out the moisture using a towel.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finely press the garlic, and add it to the yoghurt along with the other ingredients.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Season to taste&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mongolian Beef</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/mongolian-beef/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 10:01:01 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/mongolian-beef/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This recipe makes for a delicious and saucy beef dish. It takes some time to prepare, but is well worth it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;marinade&#34;&gt;Marinade&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Beef (I like using cheap steak for this, as the baking soda will tenderize it anyway)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shaoxing (cooking wine, sub with any rice wine)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(Dark) soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Oyster sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Some white pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A little cooking oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Baking soda (To tenderize the meat)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cornstarch (To keep the beef moist)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;sauce&#34;&gt;Sauce&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soy Sauce (light or dark)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sugar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Oyster Sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shaoxing (To deglaze)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A little cornstarch + water to thicken&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;veggies-for-stir-fry&#34;&gt;Veggies (for stir-fry)&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ginger&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Spring onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bell pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dried chili pepper (you can remove this if you don&amp;rsquo;t like spicy food)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cut the beef into strips and mix it with the marinade (add the cornstarch at the end) Let it sit for at least 15 minutes, but preferably a few hours.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cut the vegetables&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Prepare the sauce in a small bowl, with a separate bowl for the cornstarch slurry&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If time permits, I suggest you deep fry your beef in vegetable oil. This way, the texture will turn out crispy while the beef remains moist. Else, you can simply stir fry your mongolian beef instead.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Remove some of the oil and stir fry the veggies.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add in the sauce and the beef, and season to taste.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rice Pudding</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/rice-pudding/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 15:09:19 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/rice-pudding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Whenever I have rice left over, there are two things that immediately come to mind. Storing it to stir-fry it later, or turning it into a pudding if I have time to do so. This is the ultimate thoughtless recipe for when you want to keep your hands busy while listening to music for example.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(Left over) rice&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Milk&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sugar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Vanilla extract (optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Submerge the rice in milk.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add sugar to taste (I like it a little less sweet).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Stir over a medium-low heat until the texture is smooth.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, you can choose to add a little vanilla extract.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Garlic Beans</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/garlic-beans/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 17:59:38 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/garlic-beans/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Green beans&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ginger&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soy Sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Butter&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;First, fry the beans in the oil till they become shriveled and you begin to see some yellow.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next, in a new pan, add the butter and heat up the garlic, ginger and soy sauce on medium heat. Go easy on the soy sauce.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, add the beans back in and mix them with the sauce.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
