<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Paul&#39;s Particles</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Paul&#39;s Particles</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 20:22:45 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Scuffins</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/scuffins/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 20:22:45 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/scuffins/</guid>
      <description>At first, I was planning on making scones. Because of a lack of better moulds, I decided to use a muffin tray, and the rest is history. This recipe yields about 12 medium-sized scuffins.&#xA;Ingredients 500 grams of all-purpose flour 200 grams of granulated sugar About 10 grams of baking powder 2 eggs 250 grams of butter 200 grams of crème fraîche About 20 milliliters of milk About 3 teaspoons of vanilla extract A pinch of salt Optionally, toppings like milk chocolate, blueberries or caramel A muffin tray Baking plan Preheat an oven to 200 degrees Celsius.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Burrito</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/burrito/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 07:38:59 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/burrito/</guid>
      <description>A good burrito recipe has been like the holy grail for me. I looove burritos, but I just wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to get them to taste quite right. This recipe is finally close to the taste I have been searching for.&#xA;Ingredients Ground beef White onion Vegetable or olive oil. Lots of beans. I use kidney beans. They will be pasted. About 2 parts Salt, 1 part Pepper, 1 part Garlic powder, 4 parts Paprika powder, 8 parts Cumin.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mishaps</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/meditation/mishaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 22:16:37 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/meditation/mishaps/</guid>
      <description>Falling down is an accident, staying down is a choice&#xA;When working on becoming the person you want to be, it is often in the stressful and doubtful situations that you find out your conviction is strong. You can tell alot about yourself and your growth as a person from how you deal with hardship, however small it may be.&#xA;It is good excercise to ask yourself what your instinctual reaction is when something goes wrong.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pretty Things</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/meditation/pretty-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 22:44:55 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/meditation/pretty-things/</guid>
      <description>Beauty exists only to relief us from ugliness&#xA;Often in live, I find myself feeling like I&amp;rsquo;m above the need for beauty. It can be seen as a virtue to look not at appearance but at what lies within. I agree with this, but only recently have I come around to realising that beauty has its place as well. A lack of elegance or beauty can be distracting. This distraction may take some effort to look through, ultimately draining (a slight amount of) energy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beginnings</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/meditation/beginnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 19:52:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/meditation/beginnings/</guid>
      <description>Meditation is conversation with the soul.&#xA;For quite some time now, I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to put more of my creative energy into my blog. To do this, I have tried to understand what makes me me by finding my creative voice. I&amp;rsquo;m afraid this question is too grand for me to answer in one go. In my life, I have meditated quite often, and this is just one of many other topics I will meditate on in my life.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>OE (Onion &amp; Eggs)</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/egg-and-onion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 21:33:38 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/egg-and-onion/</guid>
      <description>Today, we will be making OE. I&amp;rsquo;ll let you figure out what that means.&#xA;Ingredients Onions Eggs (also some pepper, salt and cooking oil) Cooking plan We will be using about one onion per one egg. For people that like the taste of onion, I suggest you let the onions sweat by using a medium-low heat, until the onions turn translucent. This takes about 10 minutes. For those of you that have time on their hands, let the onions caramelise on the same medium-low heat.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tennessee Onion</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/tennessee-onion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 21:18:06 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/tennessee-onion/</guid>
      <description>Ok, so the description may have been a lie. I usually don&amp;rsquo;t barbecue because Dutch weather can be very unpredictable (Dutch struggles). Instead, I like to put stuff in the oven (like a true patriot). Therefore, this dish will be using our favorite inferno machine. The TTC (time to cook) is about an hour, so prepare it well in advance!&#xA;Ingredients White onions Shredded cheese (Gouda, because it melts well and because it&amp;rsquo;s Dutch) Butter Paprika powder Chopped parsley Dried thyme Dried oregano Aluminum foil Cooking plan Preheat an oven to 160 degrees Celsius.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Souvlaki</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/souvlaki/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 07:26:17 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/souvlaki/</guid>
      <description>This is a lovely meaty dish that you can serve as a main course. With summer at its peak, you enjoy this dish on straight from the grill during a barbecue for example.&#xA;Marinate (extra virgin) olive oil Oregano Sweet paprika powder Thyme (optional) Bay leaves Juice from a lemon LOTS OF GARLIC Salt and pepper Chicken (cubed, which you&amp;rsquo;ll marinate) Cooking plan Mince the garlic. You should use enough that you can smell it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Melitzanosalata</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/melitzanosalata/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 07:12:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/melitzanosalata/</guid>
      <description>I love cooking Greek food. Something about the balance of oils, fresh herbs and grilled meats just really gets me going. But Greek food can be more than just gyros and souvlaki. To give our vegetarians some love, and in order to diversify your Greek palette, let me introduce you to this lovely dish called Melitzanosalata (eggplant salad).&#xA;Ingredients A few Eggplants Half a red onion (or a full shallot, if you want a more delicate flavour) Olive oil, preferably extra virgin.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sausage Stew</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/sausage-stew/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 21:05:34 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/sausage-stew/</guid>
      <description>This recipe is a Paul-certified classic. It is easy to make (only about 30 minutes), and is quite filling for when you are having a busy week.&#xA;Ingredients Sausage (pork works well) Cooking oil A (small) tin of tomtato paste Yellow onion Garlic Bell peppers (different colors looks the nicest, doesn&amp;rsquo;t really matter for taste) Beef broth Garam masala (can sub for 5-spice) Pepper Dark soy sauce (for color and salt) Cooking plan First, cook your sausage in an oiled pan until golden brown.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sichuan Pork</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/sichuan-pork/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 21:56:30 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/sichuan-pork/</guid>
      <description>The recipe I referred to in my previous post. The flavour can best be described as má là, a Chinese term meaning numbing ( má 麻) and spicy ( là 辣). The aroma is citrusy and deep, and the flavour leaves you wanting more. I suggest you serve this with rice. This recipe takes about 45 minutes, but it is well worth it.&#xA;Ingredients Pork belly (without the rind) Black pepper About a tablespoon of red Sichuan peppercorns (less if you can&amp;rsquo;t stand the numbing effect) Five-spice powder High smoke point cooking oil (like vegetable oil) Star anise Onion Ginger As much pepper as you can handle (and don&amp;rsquo;t be a wimp!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Write it with Blood</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/write-in-blood/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 May 2024 20:44:13 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/write-in-blood/</guid>
      <description>About 9 in 10 people in the world can read. Crazy, considering just 100 years ago this number barely exceeded 2 in 10. Talking about reading, I was doing some of that just now. I was looking into Sichuan cooking because I wanted to make something nice for diner, until I noticed something annoying. EVERY SINGLE COOKING BLOG PLACES THEIR RECIPE AT THE BOTTOM OF THE PAGE. Now, I&amp;rsquo;m no stranger to the internet and have done some research into SEO and all that, but this nuisance did spark some thoughts in me that I wanted to write down.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Egg Drop Soup</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/egg-drop-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 21:12:21 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/egg-drop-soup/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;ve started getting into making soup recently. This is new territory for me, but I decided to give it a try after pondering what to do with the leftover chinese cabbage that had been living rent-free in my fridge for a too long. Behold! This soup was the result.&#xA;Ingredients Chinese Cabbage About 1 liter of chicken stock Eggs (about 3) White onion (can be omitted) Garlic Sesame oil Powdered or grated ginger Salt and (preferably white) pepper Scallion A little bit of cooking oil Cooking plan Chop up your onions, garlic and scallion (put aside the green for garnish).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Orange Chicken</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/orange-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 21:28:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/orange-chicken/</guid>
      <description>I have to admit, this is a guilty pleasure of mine. I don&amp;rsquo;t make this often, as it can take a bit long to make, but I always enjoy it when I do. If you are looking for a sweet and unique taste, look no further than this recipe. I suggest serving this with white rice.&#xA;Ingredients For the meat Chicken breasts (whole, or already cubed) All purpose flour Cornstarch High smoke-point oil like peanut oil For the sauce A bunch of oranges (5 per kilo of chicken, more if you like it saucy) Alternatively, you can use orange juice instead of fresh oranges A bit of sugar (If it isn&amp;rsquo;t sweet enough already) Soy sauce Garlic powder Ginger (or ginger powder) Cornstarch (to thicken the sauce) Cooking plan Squeeze the oranges and strain the juice.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3D Rotation in Python with quaternions</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/3d-rotation-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 15:55:07 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/3d-rotation-python/</guid>
      <description>Today, I wanted to share a bit of code that you can use to rotate any 3D vector using Python. If you want to read a bit about how the code works, and why quaternions are useful, keep reading. If you are only interested in the code, I have it in full on my GitHub&#xA;Quickly, what is a quaternion? A quaternion is an extension of the complex numbers into 4 dimensions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mint Dip</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/mint-dip/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 21:09:25 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/mint-dip/</guid>
      <description>So I am looking more into the indian cuisine. To start things off, I made a simple mint dip to eat with a meal, or just to dip naan in.&#xA;Ingredients Yoghurt Mint leaves (dried if fresh isn&amp;rsquo;t available) Lemon juice A clove of garlic Salt and pepper Cooking plan Finely chop the garlic and mint leaves Mix the ingredients to taste ENJOY! </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I get motivation to write</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing-motivation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 21:17:08 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing-motivation/</guid>
      <description>So, I have struggled with a lack of motivation to write. Sometimes, I can be to perfectionistic to get anything done, while at other times I simply have to much going on in my head and I feel like I just can&amp;rsquo;t find the time to write. Whatever the reason may be, it&amp;rsquo;s unwarranted more often than not. This does not make the act of sitting down and simply writing any easier off course.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hoisin Ground Beef</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/hoisin-ground-beef/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 10:51:32 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/hoisin-ground-beef/</guid>
      <description>This recipe is both simple and delicious. This is easy comfort food for when I don&amp;rsquo;t feel like cooking for too long.&#xA;Ingredients Ground beef Garlic Yellow onion Spring onion Shallots Garden peas (frozen is more than fine) Soy sauce Hoisin sauce Oyster sauce (optional, adds umami) Shaoxing cooking wine (to deglaze) Sesame oil (optional, but it really is a finishing touch) White rice Cooking plan Wash the rice and cook it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Productive procrastination; boon or bane?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/productive-procrastination/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 21:43:07 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/productive-procrastination/</guid>
      <description>Productive procrastination is the art of delaying the task you need to get done by doing other (often less important) tasks that need to be done. Now, I&amp;rsquo;ve heard many different takes on this habit, and have taken different stances through the years. Today, I will break down some of the benefits and problems. I will also discuss some alternative methods.&#xA;The good Momentum When doing work, you should aim to stay in motion.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VScode extensions that boost my productivity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/vscode-extensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 20:57:18 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/vscode-extensions/</guid>
      <description>As I have stated in my setup-page, I use VScode as my main text editor. I especially like the ability to customize your coding environment with extensions. Today, I will share the extensions that really give a boost to my work.&#xA;Better Comments This first extension allows me to better manage and organize my annotations while coding. When starting comments with alerts (!), questions (?), TODO&amp;rsquo;s (TODO), or important tags (*), this extension automatically colors them to make them stand out more.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bbq Sauce</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/bbq-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 18:57:14 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/bbq-sauce/</guid>
      <description>I really enjoy this bbq-sauce with pulled pork or as a glaze for spare-ribs.&#xA;Ingredients Ketchup Worcester Sauce Mustard Vinegar Garlic powder Onion powder Salt, pepper and sugar to taste Cooking plan Put it all into a pan and stir over low heat. Go easy on the mustard and vinegar. ENJOY! </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teriyaki Sauce</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/teriyaki-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 18:50:31 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/teriyaki-sauce/</guid>
      <description>I love eating this sauce with, for example, chicken and noodles.&#xA;Ingredients Sesame seeds (optional, adds flavour and thickens sauce) Soy Sauce Honey Sugar (only a little if you like it less sweet) Garlic powder Grated ginger Sesame oil (optional, ads nice sesame flavours) Mirin cooking wine (optional, ads extra complexity) Some water Cornstarch (Add if you like a thicker sauce) Cooking plan Add all ingredients to a pan, and stir over medium heat until desired taste and texture is achieved.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tzatziki</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/tzatziki/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 14:03:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/tzatziki/</guid>
      <description>After a trip to Greece, I fell in love with greek cuisine. Of course, you cant say Greek without Tzatziki, and so I will share this easy recipe for this beloved sauce.&#xA;Ingredients Greek yoghurt Garlic Vinegar Olive oil (I like extra virgin) Dill Cucumber Some salt Preparation Finely grate a cucumber and wring out the moisture using a towel. Finely press the garlic, and add it to the yoghurt along with the other ingredients.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mongolian Beef</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/mongolian-beef/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 10:01:01 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/mongolian-beef/</guid>
      <description>This recipe makes for a delicious and saucy beef dish. It takes some time to prepare, but is well worth it.&#xA;Ingredients Marinade Beef (I like using cheap steak for this) Shaoxing (Cooking Wine) (Dark) Soy Sauce Oyster sauce Some white pepper A little cooking oil Baking Soda (To tenderize the meat) Cornstarch (To keep the beef moist) Sauce Soy Sauce (light or dark) Sugar Oyster Sauce Shaoxing (To deglaze) A little cornstarch + water to thicken Veggies (for stir-fry) Garlic Ginger Spring onion Onion Bell pepper Dried chili pepper (you can remove this if you don&amp;rsquo;t like spicy food) Cooking plan Cut the beef into strips and mix it with the marinade (add the cornstarch at the end) Let it sit for at least 15 minutes, but preferably a few hours.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rice Pudding</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/rice-pudding/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 15:09:19 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/rice-pudding/</guid>
      <description>Whenever I have rice left over, there are two things that immediately come to mind. Storing it to stir-fry it later, or turning it into a pudding if I have time to do so. This is the ultimate thoughtless recipe for when you want to keep your hands busy while listening to music for example.&#xA;Ingredients (Left over) rice Milk Sugar Vanilla extract (optional) Cooking plan Submerge the rice in milk.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Garlic Beans</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/garlic-beans/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 17:59:38 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/garlic-beans/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients Green beans Garlic Ginger Soy Sauce Butter Cooking plan First, fry the beans in the oil till they become shriveled and you begin to see some yellow. Next, in a new pan, add the butter and heat up the garlic, ginger and soy sauce on medium heat. Go easy on the soy sauce. Finally, add the beans back in and mix them with the sauce. ENJOY! </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hello world</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 17:59:14 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my blog! This first post gives a basic overview of what this website is about, and why I started it.&#xA;Paul&amp;rsquo;s Particles This is a personal website containing everything I want to share with the world. It is my aim to break these topics down to their fundamentals. In doing so, this website can become a repository of neatly contained packages (particles, if you will) of my knowledge and experience.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
