<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Paul&#39;s Particles</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Paul&#39;s Particles</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 21:43:07 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Productive Procrastination; Boon or Bane?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/productive-procrastination/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 21:43:07 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/productive-procrastination/</guid>
      <description>Productive procrastination is the art of delaying the task you need to get done by doing other (often less important) tasks that need to be done. Now, I&amp;rsquo;ve heard many different takes on this habit, and have taken different stances through the years. Today, I will break down some of its benefits and problems. I will also discuss some alternative methods.&#xA;The good Momentum When doing work, you should aim to stay in motion.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VScode extensions that boost my productivity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/vscode-extensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 20:57:18 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/vscode-extensions/</guid>
      <description>As I have stated in my setup-page, I use VScode as my main text editor. I especially like the ability to customize your coding environment with extensions. Today, I will share the extensions that really give a boost to my work.&#xA;Better Comments This first extension allows me to better manage and organize my annotations while coding. When starting comments with alerts (!), questions (?), TODO&amp;rsquo;s (TODO), or important tags (*), this extension automatically colors them to make them stand out more.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Bbq Sauce</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/bbq-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 18:57:14 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/bbq-sauce/</guid>
      <description>I really enjoy this bbq-sauce with pulled pork or as a glaze for spare-ribs.&#xA;###= Ingredients:&#xA;Ketchup Worcester Sauce Mustard Vinegar Garlic powder Onion powder Salt, pepper and sugar to taste Cooking plan: Put it all into a pan and stir over low heat. Go easy on the mustard and vinegar. ENJOY! </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teriyaki Sauce</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/teriyaki-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 18:50:31 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/teriyaki-sauce/</guid>
      <description>I love eating this sauce with, for example, chicken and noodles.&#xA;Ingredients Sesame seeds (optional, adds flavour and thickens sauce) Soy Sauce Honey Sugar (only a little if you like it less sweet) Garlic powder Grated ginger Sesame oil (optional, ads nice sesame flavours) Mirin cooking wine (optional, ads extra complexity) Some water Cornstarch (Add if you like a thicker sauce) Cooking plan Add all ingredients to a pan, and stir over medium heat until desired taste and texture is achieved.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tzatziki</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/tzatziki/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 14:03:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/tzatziki/</guid>
      <description>After a trip to Greece, I fell in love with greek cuisine. Of course, you cant say Greek without Tzatziki, and so I will share this easy recipe for this beloved sauce.&#xA;Ingredients Greek yoghurt Garlic Vinegar Olive oil (I like extra virgin) Dill Cucumber Some salt Preparation Finely grate a cucumber and wring out the moisture using a towel. Finely press the garlic, and add it to the yoghurt along with the other ingredients.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mongolian Beef</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/mongolian-beef/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 10:01:01 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/mongolian-beef/</guid>
      <description>This recipe makes for a delicious and saucy beef dish. It takes some time to prepare, but is well worth it.&#xA;Ingredients Marinade Beef (I like using cheap steak for this) Shaoxing (Cooking Wine) (Dark) Soy Sauce Oyster sauce Some white pepper A little cooking oil Baking Soda (To tenderize the meat) Cornstarch (To keep the beef moist) Sauce Soy Sauce (light or dark) Sugar Oyster Sauce Shaoxing (To deglaze) A little cornstarch + water to thicken Veggies (for stir-fry) Garlic Ginger Spring onion Onion Bell pepper Dried chili pepper (you can remove this if you don&amp;rsquo;t like spicy food) Cooking plan Cut the beef into strips and mix it with the marinade (add the cornstarch at the end) Let it sit for at least 15 minutes, but preferably a few hours.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rice Pudding</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/rice-pudding/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 15:09:19 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/rice-pudding/</guid>
      <description>Whenever I have rice left over, there are two things that immediately come to mind. Storing it to stir-fry it later, or turning it into a pudding if I have time to do so. This is the ultimate thoughtless recipe for when you want to keep your hands busy while listening to music for example.&#xA;Ingredients (Left over) rice Milk Sugar Vanilla extract (optional) Cooking plan Submerge the rice in milk.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Paul Stapel</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about-me/about-me/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 20:59:30 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about-me/about-me/</guid>
      <description>Hiya, I&amp;rsquo;m Paul! I&amp;rsquo;m a student-writer-tutor-programmer hybrid specializing in science. This website is my first public project, and I look forward to sharing more of my work in the future. Nonetheless, you can find everything you need to know about me on this page.&#xA;Currently working on I&amp;rsquo;m currently following four courses at Utrecht University:&#xA;Data structures Electrodynamics Groups and Rings Probability theory On the side, I work on this blog and write articles for our student society in de Vakidioot (BEWARE: Dutch!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setup</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/set-up/set-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 20:56:45 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/set-up/set-up/</guid>
      <description>Here you can find my current setup with regards to desk, hardware, software and the likes. I often find it useful to read what other people are using and how they stay organized, so in this post I will return the favor.&#xA;My workspace For my workspace, I sit at an Ikea Lagkapten desk, which I like to keep clean and minimal. On it, I have my laptop, a pen, a Harte Ikea LED-lamp and my (bullet) journal.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Garlic Beans</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/garlic-beans/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 17:59:38 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/garlic-beans/</guid>
      <description>Ingredients: Green beans Garlic Ginger Soy Sauce Butter Cooking plan: First, fry the beans in the oil till they become shriveled and you begin to see some yellow. Next, in a new pan, add the butter and heat up the garlic, ginger and soy sauce on medium heat. Go easy on the soy sauce. Finally, add the beans back in and mix them with the sauce. ENJOY! </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hello World</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/hello-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 17:59:14 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/hello-world/</guid>
      <description>Welcome to my blog! This first post gives a basic overview of what this website is about, and why I started it.&#xA;Paul&amp;rsquo;s Particles This is a personal website containing everything I want to share with the world. It is my aim to break these topics down to their fundamentals. In doing so, this website can become a repository of neatly contained packages (particles, if you will) of my knowledge and experience.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
