<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Filipino on Paul&#39;s Particles</title>
    <link>https://paulstapel.com/categories/filipino/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Filipino on Paul&#39;s Particles</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 20:48:12 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://paulstapel.com/categories/filipino/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Pork Adobo</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/pork-adobo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 20:48:12 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/pork-adobo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My auntie Rose from the Philippines shared this awesome recipe with me recently, and i&amp;rsquo;ve made it a few times now. I will be sharing the base recipe with some optional ingredients you may add, but having cooked this dish in a few different ways now, I can safely say that all of them are delicous. Serve with white rice.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pork belly (or chicken for chicken adobo) (Use the bones seperately as well if you have them)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic (lots of it)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Olive oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;String beans (Optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Potatoes (Optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hard boiled egg (Optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White onion (Own addition, optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;for-the-marinade&#34;&gt;For the marinade&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White vinegar (I have found that Chinkiang black vinegar also works, but I prefer white)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Brown sugar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Black pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bay leafs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Warm water&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There are two ways to do the marinade. Firstly, you can add the marinade and salt to your pork and leave it to marinade overnight. Alternatively, you can salt the pork and cook it first, then add the marinade later. Either way, the marinade can be made by mixing all of the ingredients listed and adjusting to taste.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finely mince your garlic. Usually, I use about a foot of garlic. Make sure it is pasted or finely minced.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To a pot on high heat, add your pork (chicken) and brown it. After that is done, you may remove it from the pan and lower the heat.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next add your (optional, chopped) white onion and a (mandatory) lot of garlic to your pan and fry it untill browned.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If you have bones, add them now and cook them in the same oil.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next, you may add your optional string beans and potatoes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once the bones are done, you can add your pork (chicken) back into the pan and continue cooking for a minute before adding your sauce.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;While this is cooking, you may optionally boil some eggs to add to your pan.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Let this simmer on medium heat for a while, until the desired texture is acquired. Serve with white rice.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
