<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Difficulty 4|5 on Paul&#39;s Particles</title>
    <link>https://paulstapel.com/categories/difficulty-45/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Difficulty 4|5 on Paul&#39;s Particles</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 20:44:11 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://paulstapel.com/categories/difficulty-45/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Shoyu Ramen</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/shoyu-ramen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 20:44:11 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/shoyu-ramen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Shoyu ramen is an amazing dish that can be extended to your liking very easily. The name of this ramen dish comes from the addition of soy sauce to your broth (Shoyu = Japanese soy sauce). As this recipe can be made with lots of different ingredients, I will simply suggest some of the ingredients you could add to your ramen. This recipe may take some multi-tasking if you are adding a lot of toppings, so prepping well is recommended!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moussaka</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/moussaka/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 13:22:32 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/moussaka/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is no secret that I love greek food. My stomach simply can&amp;rsquo;t get enough of the delicous fatty recipes that Greek people have come up with. Among these hearty recipes,&#xA;moussaka stands out as one of my favorites. I made it for a birthday dinner last week, and the deliciousness is well worth the preperation time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;meat-filling&#34;&gt;Meat filling&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Beef mince&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tomato passata&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tomato concentrate&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bay leaves&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cinnamon (powder, sticks also work and give an even nicer taste)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Oregano&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sugar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(Cheap) red wine&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Olive oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Beef stock (cubes or homemade)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;besamel-sauce-not-a-typo&#34;&gt;Besamel sauce (not a typo)&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Butter (equal part butter to flower)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Flour&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Milk (cold)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Nutmeg&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Eggs (not vital, but help the sauce brown, creating a nicer color)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Parmesan&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;eggplant-bottom&#34;&gt;Eggplant bottom&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A bunch of eggplants&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;eggplant-bottom-1&#34;&gt;Eggplant bottom&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Start with the bottom of your moussaka by cutting your eggplant into circular slabs of about 1 cm thick.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sprinkle salt over your slabs and let the moisture be drawn out of the eggplant. Let them rest for about 30 minutes while you continue with your meat filling.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Preheat an oven to about 200 degrees Celcius.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;meat-filling-1&#34;&gt;Meat filling&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add some olive oil to a large pan and set it on medium heat. Finely chop up your onions and add them to the pot to caramelise.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;After your onion has browned, turn the heat to high and add your beef mince. Stir it until it has browned, and then add your garlic.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;After your garlic has become fragrant, add your cinnamon, oregano, salt and about a tbsp of sugar to taste. Stir for a bit, before adding wine to almost cover your meat.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;After the alcohol smell is gone, add your tomato concentrate and let it cook a little on high heat.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, add your tomato passata and cover your pan in beef stock. Let this reduce for a while, until filling has become rather thick.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;eggplant-bottom-2&#34;&gt;Eggplant bottom&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pat your eggplant dry of moisture and rub away some of the salt you have previously added.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On a baking tray (or multiple depending on how much you are making), lay out your eggplants and put them in the oven for about 30 minutes. You&amp;rsquo;ll know when they are done when they have become soft.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once done, take them out of the oven and lay them to rest while you prepare the besamel sauce.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Turn the oven to 180 degrees Celcius now, as that is the temperature we will be cooking the moussaka in.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;besamel-sauce&#34;&gt;Besamel sauce&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In a (large) sauce pan, melt your butter and let it sit until it becomes a little browned.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next, add an equal part flower and stir it into the butter (it is easier with slightly more butter if you are struggling with this sauce). You should get a paste that has a texture akin to wet sand, and it should be bubbling a little.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next, add in a bunch of cold milk (about 500 ml per 30 grams of butter/flour). Some people say you should add it incrementally, but I have found that adding it all in one batch helps make the sauce smoother.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Let this sauce simmer for a few minutes, until it has become thick enough to coat the back of a spoon. When you run your finger over the spoon, the line drawn should stay.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, stir in a little nutmeg, some eggs and a bunch of parmesan. The parmesan is what gives this sauce most of its flavor, so be generous.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;assembly&#34;&gt;Assembly&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In a cast iron pan, first layer your eggplant, cover that with meat filling, and finally cover it with your besamel sauce.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Put it in the oven for about 40 minutes, until golden brown.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Let it rest for a bit before serving for the best result.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Japanese Curry</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/japanese-curry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Aug 2024 20:28:31 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/japanese-curry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After having been on a vacation to Vietnam and Singapore for three weeks (hence the gap in posts, haha), this is one cuisine I have fallen in love with. I simply had to get a recipe to make this myself, and in my opinion, I am quite close to mimicking the taste of the curries I&amp;rsquo;ve had in Singapore. Be warned, this recipe can take up to 2 hours. I suggest serving this dish with (white) rice.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sichuan Pork</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/sichuan-pork/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 21:56:30 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/sichuan-pork/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The recipe I referred to in my &lt;a href=&#34;https://paulstapel.github.io/write-in-blood/&#34;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;. The flavour can best be described as má là, a Chinese term meaning numbing ( má 麻) and spicy ( là 辣). The aroma is citrusy and deep, and the flavour leaves you wanting more. I suggest you serve this with rice. This recipe takes about 45 minutes, but it is well worth it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pork belly (without the rind)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Black pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;About a tablespoon of red Sichuan peppercorns (less if you can&amp;rsquo;t stand the numbing effect)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Five-spice powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;High smoke point cooking oil (like vegetable oil)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Star anise&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ginger&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;As much pepper as you can handle (and don&amp;rsquo;t be a wimp!)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Half a liter of bone or beef stock&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Honey&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shaoxing cooking wine (optional, to deglaze if necessary)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Black bean sauce (optional, adds some counterbalance umami to this spicy dish)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Start by toasting the star anise and red Sichuan peppercorns in a non-oiled pan until fragrant. Put aside the star anise for later use.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Grind the peppercorns into dust, along with some black pepper.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cut your pork belly into bite sized strips, and cover it in about a tablespoon of five-spice powder.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Heat up a wok with oil until smoking, and cook the pork belly until brown. Get some of that Maillard reaction goodness in there. If you want, you can deglaze your pan with some cooking wine.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Put the pork aside, and start sautéing the onion until browned. After a bit, add in your peppers as well.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add your pork back to the pan. Add the stock with your toasted star anise, some slices of ginger and the ground powder of the peppercorn and black pepper. Let your mixture simmer until it has been reduced to about 1/3rd of what you started with. This may take a while.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;After your broth has been reduced to satisfaction, you can choose to take out the pork and add it back in at the last stage. This makes cooking the sauce easier, and it makes sure you don&amp;rsquo;t overcook the pork. It will still be delicious if you don&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To your broth, add some soy sauce, a generous helping of honey (at least 2-3 eating spoons) and some optional black bean sauce. Stir on high heat until the sauce has thickened.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, add everything back together, fish out the star anise and ginger, and serve with white rice.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
