<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Productivity on Paul&#39;s Particles</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/productivity/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Productivity on Paul&#39;s Particles</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 19:42:24 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/productivity/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>My Phone&#39;s Home Screen</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/my-phone-home-screen/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2024 19:42:24 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/my-phone-home-screen/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hiya, long time no see! It&amp;rsquo;s been - glances at notes - more than 100 days since I last posted something on Paul&amp;rsquo;s Particles. A lot has happened, but I&amp;rsquo;m finally starting to settle into my usual routine again. I&amp;rsquo;ve got some great content planned, but I thought I would start things off with a simple post sharing what my phone looks like. I actually hide all apps that are not on my home screen in order to avoid distractions from social media apps or apps that I just don&amp;rsquo;t use on a daily basis, meaning my home screen is like a best-of collection for my phone.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How I get motivation to write</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/writing-motivation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 21:17:08 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/writing-motivation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, I have struggled with a lack of motivation to write. Sometimes, I can be to perfectionistic to get anything done, while at other times I simply have to much going on in my head and I feel like I just can&amp;rsquo;t find the time to write. Whatever the reason may be, it&amp;rsquo;s unwarranted more often than not. This does not make the act of sitting down and simply writing any easier off course. That&amp;rsquo;s why I wanted to share some of the ways I make writing (motivation) easier for myself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Productive procrastination; boon or bane?</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/productive-procrastination/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 21:43:07 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/productive-procrastination/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Productive procrastination is the art of delaying the task you need to get done by doing other (often less important) tasks that need to be done. Now, I&amp;rsquo;ve heard many different takes on this habit, and have taken different stances through the years. Today, I will break down some of the benefits and problems. I will also discuss some alternative methods.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-good&#34;&gt;The good&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;momentum&#34;&gt;Momentum&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When doing work, you should aim to stay in motion. Once I&amp;rsquo;ve been going for a while, I often find myself entering a flow state wherein I lose any sense of time. THIS IS WHAT YOU WANT TO ACHIEVE WHEN DOING PRETTY MUCH ANYTHING. When you stop doing productive work, by checking your socials or watching funny memes for example, this state is lost as well. In contrast, procrastinating on other productive tasks still lets mee keep some of the momentum I&amp;rsquo;ve built up, making it easier to start on my main TODO.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VScode extensions that boost my productivity</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/vscode-extensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 20:57:18 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/vscode-extensions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I have stated in my setup-page, I use VScode as my main text editor. I especially like the ability to customize your coding environment with extensions. Today, I will share the extensions that really give a boost to my work.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;better-comments&#34;&gt;Better Comments&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This first extension allows me to better manage and organize my annotations while coding. When starting comments with alerts (!), questions (?), TODO&amp;rsquo;s (TODO), or important tags (*), this extension automatically colors them to make them stand out more. This makes it so I can more easily find the information I&amp;rsquo;m looking for, and it has saved me more time than I initially expected.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
