<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thai on Paul&#39;s Particles</title>
    <link>https://paulstapel.com/categories/thai/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Thai on Paul&#39;s Particles</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 20:58:31 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://paulstapel.com/categories/thai/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Thai Salmon Curry</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/thai-salmon-curry/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Aug 2025 20:58:31 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/thai-salmon-curry/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I wanted to create an easy dish that incorporates some more complex flavors, and haven&amp;rsquo;t cooked with salmon in quite a bit. That&amp;rsquo;s why I decided to create a new recipe using this fishy friend.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salmon (fresh, skin-on, but frozen also works great!)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Black pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Olive oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shallots&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ginger&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Brown sugar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Honey&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Thai red curry paste&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Coconut milk&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fish sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Half a lime (for the juice)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Holy basil (or substitute for regular basil with a touch of anise powder)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If you are using fresh salmon, season with salt and pepper then cook it on its skin with olive oil until golden brown. If you are using frozen salmon, start by thawing the salmon.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chop up your shallots and cook them in the same pan on medium-high heat to quickly caramelise them. Once starting to brown, add some chopped ginger and garlic.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Meanwhile preheat an oven to 220 degrees Celcius.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next, add some brown sugar and red curry paste and cook out its water contents for about 1 or 2 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next add your coconut milk, a splash of fish sauce, juice from half a lime and some holy basil (or substitute), and stir it together.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, lay your salmon into the sauce without covering the top in sauce. Just let it cook a bit while your sauce reduces.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Put some honey and brown sugar on your salmon to glaze it, and then put your pan in the oven. Cook for about 5 - 10 minutes, or until your sugar has begun to caramelise a bit. You could also achieve this with a kitchen blowtorch. I like how the sauce turns out when you put it in the oven for a bit, so that&amp;rsquo;s what I usually do.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Serve with rice, or even a pasta if you wish to be multicultural.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pad Kra Pao</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/pad-kra-pao/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Jul 2025 21:30:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/pad-kra-pao/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is one of my favorite recipes from the Thai kitchen. The combination of ground beef with the aromatics and delicious holy basil just hits different. I&amp;rsquo;m happy to share this recipe with you today.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ground beef&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Holy basil leafs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Black pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lemongrass (optional aromatic)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dried or fresh chilies&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chicken stock&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fish sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cooking oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cilantro (optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lime (optional for garnish)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Start by mincing or grinding the garlic, lemongrass and chilies (aromatics) into a paste&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next, heat some oil in a wok (or pan) until smoking hot&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Stir-fry your ground beef until browned (so for about 3-4 minutes)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next, push aside your meat and add some more oil to cook your aromatics until fragrant and a little crispy. Stir it into your ground beef when finished.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add black pepper, chicken stock and fish sauce and let it reduce into the beef mixture.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, add your holy basil (and optional cilantro) and season to taste. Garnish with a squeeze of lime juice (optionally)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phanaeng</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/phanaeng/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 08:05:10 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/phanaeng/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I really love Thai food, but I&amp;rsquo;ve not been making much of it as of late. I kind of thought it time to change that, so in that spirit I&amp;rsquo;d like to present to you this Thai Phanaeng curry.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cocounut milk&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kaffir lime leafs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fish sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pork, beef or chicken (Cubed, but anything goes) (Make vegetarian by omitting)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bell pepper (sliced into thin strips)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Curry paste (see below)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cooking oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;curry-paste&#34;&gt;Curry paste&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 Shallot&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;4 cloves of garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2 bottom halves of lemongrass stalks&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2 tbsp (roasted) peanuts&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;8 - 12 dried red chilies&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;0.5 - 1 tsp cumin powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;0.5 tsp nutmeg&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1.5 tsp coriander powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 tbsp galangal (tumeric works too)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 tsp shrimp paste (miso paste works too)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A few kaffir lime leafs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pinch of salt and white pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Put all of the curry paste ingredients in a (spice) mixer and add a little water to form a paste.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Season your meat with some fish sauce and cooking oil.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cook some (but not all) of your coconut milk until it becomes frothy, then add your curry paste to it.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Stir for a bit, then add your kaffir lime leafs and finally your meat.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cook your meat through until rare, then add some salt and fish sauce to season.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, stir in your bell pepper.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Serve with jasmine rice.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Larb</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/larb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 13:06:08 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/larb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few years back, I had a trip to Thailand with my family. While there, we ate a lot of very delicious food, and I have been recreating the things I ate there quite often.&#xA;One thing that does bug me about doing this, however, is the fact that some of the ingredients can be quite troublesome to acquire. Not today however, as we will be making larb.&#xA;The ingredients used for this are quite easy to come by in your local Asian supermarket or even just the grocery store. Serve with rice, naan or even tortilla&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
