<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Greek on Paul&#39;s Particles</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/greek/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Greek on Paul&#39;s Particles</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 07:02:11 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/greek/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Greek Chicken and Rice</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/greek-chicken-and-rice/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Jul 2025 07:02:11 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/greek-chicken-and-rice/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, I made a recipe for Spanish chicken and rice. Both family and peers seemed to really enjoy this recipe, and therefore I am creating a Greek twist. I recommend eating it with fresh bread and some &lt;a href=&#34;https://paulstapel.com/recipes/tzatziki/&#34;&gt;Tzatziki.&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chicken breast (If it&amp;rsquo;s too thick, cut it in half crosswise)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lemon&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chicken stock&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White vinegar (just a little will do, optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Rice&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cooking oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;spice-mix&#34;&gt;Spice mix&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;3/2 tsp dill&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;3 or 4 bay leafs, crushed&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 tsp thyme&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 tsp dried rosemary&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 tsp dried oregano&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 tsp dried parsley&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 tsp dried basil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 tsp garlic powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 tsp onion powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 tsp black pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 tsp salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1/2 tsp paprika powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1/2 tsp cinnamon powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pat your chicken dry with a (paper) towel and rub on a squeeze of (half a) lemon and vinegar.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Put about half of your spice mix on your chicken.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In a cast iron pan, heat up some cooking oil and cook your chicken through. Make sure it is nice and browned on both sides. By making the chicken breasts a bit thin, you can keep it juicy while cooking it through fully.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once the chicken is done put your rice in the pan. Cover it in a liquid of chicken stock, (the remaining part of) half a lemon, a dash of vinegar and the rest of your spice mix. Use about 500 ml for a cup of rice. Cook until the rice water is gone and the rice is soft.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, add your chicken and some of the left-over oil back to your pan. You may let it cook a bit more at this point, resulting in a more chewy and pot-sticking rice dish. It can also be served now, both are good.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Htipiti</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/htipiti/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 14:47:30 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/htipiti/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is pronounced &amp;ldquo;tee-pee-tee&amp;rdquo; by the way. Serve with pita or something, idk, idc, I&amp;rsquo;m not your mom.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Feta cheese&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Red bell peppers&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Extra virgin olive oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Red wine vinegar or lemon juice&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Black pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Preheat your oven to 200 degrees Celcius&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cut the four sides of your bell peppers and reduce the stem. Lay them out on a baking tray and put them in the oven for roughly 25 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once your peppers are done, put them in a bowl and cover them to let them steam for another 10 to 20 minutes. This will make it easier to remove the skin of the peppers.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To a food processor, add feta cheese, your bell peppers (skin removed), a little red wine vinegar/lemon juice and some extra virgin olive oil.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, season to taste with salt and pepper.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Moussaka</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/moussaka/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 13:22:32 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/moussaka/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is no secret that I love greek food. My stomach simply can&amp;rsquo;t get enough of the delicous fatty recipes that Greek people have come up with. Among these hearty recipes,&#xA;moussaka stands out as one of my favorites. I made it for a birthday dinner last week, and the deliciousness is well worth the preperation time.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;meat-filling&#34;&gt;Meat filling&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Beef mince&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tomato passata&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tomato concentrate&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bay leaves&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cinnamon (powder, sticks also work and give an even nicer taste)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Oregano&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sugar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(Cheap) red wine&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Olive oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Beef stock (cubes or homemade)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;besamel-sauce-not-a-typo&#34;&gt;Besamel sauce (not a typo)&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Butter (equal part butter to flower)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Flour&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Milk (cold)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Nutmeg&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Eggs (not vital, but help the sauce brown, creating a nicer color)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Parmesan&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;eggplant-bottom&#34;&gt;Eggplant bottom&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A bunch of eggplants&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;eggplant-bottom-1&#34;&gt;Eggplant bottom&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Start with the bottom of your moussaka by cutting your eggplant into circular slabs of about 1 cm thick.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sprinkle salt over your slabs and let the moisture be drawn out of the eggplant. Let them rest for about 30 minutes while you continue with your meat filling.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Preheat an oven to about 200 degrees Celcius.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;meat-filling-1&#34;&gt;Meat filling&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add some olive oil to a large pan and set it on medium heat. Finely chop up your onions and add them to the pot to caramelise.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;After your onion has browned, turn the heat to high and add your beef mince. Stir it until it has browned, and then add your garlic.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;After your garlic has become fragrant, add your cinnamon, oregano, salt and about a tbsp of sugar to taste. Stir for a bit, before adding wine to almost cover your meat.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;After the alcohol smell is gone, add your tomato concentrate and let it cook a little on high heat.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, add your tomato passata and cover your pan in beef stock. Let this reduce for a while, until filling has become rather thick.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;eggplant-bottom-2&#34;&gt;Eggplant bottom&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pat your eggplant dry of moisture and rub away some of the salt you have previously added.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On a baking tray (or multiple depending on how much you are making), lay out your eggplants and put them in the oven for about 30 minutes. You&amp;rsquo;ll know when they are done when they have become soft.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once done, take them out of the oven and lay them to rest while you prepare the besamel sauce.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Turn the oven to 180 degrees Celcius now, as that is the temperature we will be cooking the moussaka in.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;besamel-sauce&#34;&gt;Besamel sauce&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In a (large) sauce pan, melt your butter and let it sit until it becomes a little browned.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next, add an equal part flower and stir it into the butter (it is easier with slightly more butter if you are struggling with this sauce). You should get a paste that has a texture akin to wet sand, and it should be bubbling a little.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next, add in a bunch of cold milk (about 500 ml per 30 grams of butter/flour). Some people say you should add it incrementally, but I have found that adding it all in one batch helps make the sauce smoother.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Let this sauce simmer for a few minutes, until it has become thick enough to coat the back of a spoon. When you run your finger over the spoon, the line drawn should stay.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, stir in a little nutmeg, some eggs and a bunch of parmesan. The parmesan is what gives this sauce most of its flavor, so be generous.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;assembly&#34;&gt;Assembly&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In a cast iron pan, first layer your eggplant, cover that with meat filling, and finally cover it with your besamel sauce.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Put it in the oven for about 40 minutes, until golden brown.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Let it rest for a bit before serving for the best result.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Meatballs in tomato sauce</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/tomato-meatballs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 18:11:37 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/tomato-meatballs/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ok, so last week I was thinking about what I wanted to cook, when I stumbled upon some inspiration for meatballs in tomato sauce, thinking back to how delicious those were back when I visited Greece. Now I am not about to tell you that this is an authentic Greek recipe (it is more of an Italian recipe I believe), but this is an authentic Paul banger, and as such, I would love to share it with you all. If you don&amp;rsquo;t feel like rolling meatballs, you can also just use ground beef. This has the added benefit of making storage for later easier.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Souvlaki</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/souvlaki/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 07:26:17 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/souvlaki/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a lovely meaty dish that you can serve as a main course. With summer at its peak, you enjoy this dish on straight from the grill during a barbecue for example.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;marinade&#34;&gt;Marinade&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(extra virgin) olive oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Oregano&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sweet paprika powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Thyme (optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bay leaves&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Juice from a lemon&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;LOTS OF GARLIC&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt and pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chicken (cubed, which you&amp;rsquo;ll marinate)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mince the garlic. You should use enough that you can smell it. I used 8 cloves (slightly more than a bulb) per kilo last time.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mix everything into a ziplock bag or marinating bowl.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Stir in the chicken, and let it sit for an hour or preferably two (not for too long! The lemon will slowly cook the chicken, lessening its taste after a certain amount of time)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Skewer the chicken (or cook it in a skillet if you want). You can grill the skewers on a barbecue.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Melitzanosalata</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/melitzanosalata/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 07:12:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/melitzanosalata/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love cooking Greek food. Something about the balance of oils, fresh herbs and grilled meats just really gets me going. But Greek food can be more than just gyros and souvlaki. To give our vegetarians some love, and in order to diversify your Greek palette, let me introduce you to this lovely dish called Melitzanosalata (eggplant salad).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A few Eggplants&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Half a red onion (or a full shallot, if you want a more delicate flavour)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Olive oil, preferably extra virgin.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A clove of garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Apple vinegar (white vinegar also works, just use a bit less)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Some fresh parsley (can be subbed with oregano)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Feta cheese (for garnish, can be omitted)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Olives (for garnish, can be omitted)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Start by roasting your eggplants over a grill or open fire. This takes about 10 minutes, or until the eggplants become soft and mushy inside.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Start mixing together olive oil and vinegar in (roughly) a 4:1 ratio, also adding in a minced clove of garlic.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mince your red onion, and put it in a bowl. Add your mixture, and some chopped parsley.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Remove your eggplant from the fire, and scoop out the flesh. Process the flesh untill it has become a mush.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Optional step, you may want to squeeze out excess moisture with a towel, as it may dilute the flavor of your salad.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, mix everything together and add some feta cheese and olives to your salad as garnish.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tzatziki</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/tzatziki/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 14:03:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/tzatziki/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a trip to Greece, I fell in love with greek cuisine. Of course, you cant say Greek without Tzatziki, and so I will share this easy recipe for this beloved sauce.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Greek yoghurt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Vinegar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Olive oil (I like extra virgin)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dill&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cucumber&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Some salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;preparation&#34;&gt;Preparation&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finely grate a cucumber and wring out the moisture using a towel.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finely press the garlic, and add it to the yoghurt along with the other ingredients.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Season to taste&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
