<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chinese on Paul&#39;s Particles</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/chinese/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chinese on Paul&#39;s Particles</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 20:20:57 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/chinese/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Hong Shao Rou</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/hong-shao-rou/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 20:20:57 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/hong-shao-rou/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The name &amp;ldquo;Hong shao rou&amp;rdquo; translates to red braised pork, as this is the color achieved by the combination of dark soy sauce and caramelized sugar (&amp;ldquo;táng gù&amp;rdquo;). Although this dish is not what most would call healthy, it is an absolute treat and guilty pleasure sure to please your guests. It takes a while to cook, but is well worth it. You can leave out a lot of the ingrediënts, but if possible, use them all. Dish takes about 3 hours, so keep that in mind!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hoisin Garlic Chicken</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/hoisin-garlic-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 19:59:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/hoisin-garlic-chicken/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Some good chicken goes a long way. A classic chicken dish with a Chinese touch is Honey garlic chicken, and I decided to create my own take on this popular dish. The result is this Hoisin garlic chicken.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chicken breasts&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Flour&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Butter&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Black pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ginger&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soy sauce (dark)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hoisin sauce (sub with honey if not available for a more popular honey garlic chicken)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Apple vinegar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Start by seasoning your chicken breasts with salt and pepper. Make sure your chicken breasts are cut into relatively thin steaks, as otherwise they won&amp;rsquo;t be cooked evenly.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Melt some butter in a pan on high heat.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cover your chicken in flour and cook it on both sides for about 3 minutes, until golden brown.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Meanwhile, mince some garlic and ginger. Once your chicken is browned, lower the heat and add these aromatics.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, create a sauce by adding soy sauce, apple vinegar and hoisin sauce to taste. I usually do a 2:1:1 ratio.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Serve with rice&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sweet and Spicy Hoisin Beef Tips</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/sweet-and-spicy-hoisin-beef-bliss/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 21:28:30 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/sweet-and-spicy-hoisin-beef-bliss/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love wokking, but it has been a bit too cold to use my wok in the last few months. Today however, I just couldn&amp;rsquo;t resist the urge to wok, and this delicious recipe is the result.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;marinade&#34;&gt;Marinade&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Beef tips&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Black pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hoisin sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cornstarch&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Baking powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sugar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;sauce&#34;&gt;Sauce&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hoisin sauce (2 tbsp) (1 tbsp if you like it a little less sweet)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chili garlic sauce (1 tbsp)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Honey (1 tbsp)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soy sauce (2 tbsp)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Water (2 tbsp)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sesame seeds (optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;for-wokking&#34;&gt;For wokking&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White or yellow onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Green peppers (to add some nice spice, don&amp;rsquo;t remove the seeds)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Spring onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bell peppers (can sub for green peppers if you don&amp;rsquo;t like spicy)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Vegetable oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Combine your marinade in a bowl and let it sit while you prepare your veggies and sauce. For this marinade, combine soy sauce and hoisin sauce in a 3/1 ratio. The cornstarch is meant to retain moisture for your beef tips, and the baking powder is a secret technique to make your meat more tender in a short amount of time.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next, prepare your sauce by mixing all ingredients in a bowl.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chop your veggies into large chunks.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Prepare your wok with some vegetable oil and wait until your wok is smoking hot.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add your veggies and stir-fry until browned a little.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next, add your beef and quickly stir-fry until browned and a little crispy.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, add your sauce and reduce until it creates a nice coating on your meat and veggies.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Serve with white rice&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sweet and Sour Chicken</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/sweet-and-sour-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 21:59:06 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/sweet-and-sour-chicken/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have always loved sweet and sour chicken. When I was little, I used to eat this on vacations to New York, at a local mall in Middletown, New York. I wanted to recreate this taste, but without having to use tomato ketchup, as that is usually a little too processed for me (and also, I don&amp;rsquo;t always have it in my pantry). The result is this recipe.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chicken breasts (cubed)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cornstarch&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Black pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sunflower oil (or other cooking oil with a high smoking point)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bell peppers (red and green)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ginger&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sugar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tomato paste&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Black vinegar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pineapple chunks (Optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pineapple juice (extra sweet) or lemon juice (extra sour) (Optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Serve with white rice&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Start by cubing your chicken breasts, seasoning them generously with salt and pepper. Afterwards, coat with cornstarch.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add a large amount of sunflower oil to a pan and fry your chicken until golden brown.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In the meantime, prepare the sauce by adding the following: soy sauce, black vinegar and tomato sauce in a 3:3:2 tbsp ratio. Also add about 2-3 cloves of garlic and some grated ginger to taste. Add your lemon/pineapple juice if you want. Finally, add sugar to taste.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Remove your chicken from the pan and leave them to rest on some paper towels to catch off excess oil. Store most of the oil in a container, and leave a small amount to cook your vegetables.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cut your bell peppers and white onion into large chunks and stir-fry them on medium-high heat. After a little while, also add your optional pineapple chunks for a more traditional recipe.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;After your onion has become nice and brown on the edges, add in your sauce and stir until thickened.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add your chicken at the end in order to keep them crispy for longer. Serve with white rice.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Garlixplosion Noodles</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/garlicsplosion-noodles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 08:19:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/garlicsplosion-noodles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The only way to make a good dish even gooder is to add an exuberant amount of garlic to it. That was exactly the premise of this little experiment. Adding a lot of garlic and seeing where it leads me. It turned out to be a delightful recipe that I have even decided to share her on my blog. Be warned, not for the faint of heart.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lots of garlic (I used about 2 bulbs, but adjust to your own tolerance/taste)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Noodles&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Zucchini&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ground beef or meatballs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chili oil (I use Lao Gan Ma)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A little vegetable oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Light soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Optional black bean sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To a pot, add some salted water and cook your noodles as per the instructions on the package.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next, mince the onion and cut up the zucchini into small pieces. If you&amp;rsquo;re not using a garlic press, mince your garlic.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add some vegetable oil to your pan and start by sweating the onions. After they are translucent, turn up the heat and add your zucchini and chili oil. Lastly, add your garlic (using a garlic press).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;At this point, you may add your meat. I used meatballs (cursed, I know), but ground beef also works great. Be sure to stir often, as otherwise your aromatics may burn.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;When your sauce has browned, add light soy sauce and optional black bean sauce to taste. I used a ratio of 3:1 for these ingredients. You can also add some more Lao Gan Ma if you want.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lastly, toss your noodles into your pan and stir carefully until it is covered in sauce.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sichuan Pork</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/sichuan-pork/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 May 2024 21:56:30 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/sichuan-pork/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The recipe I referred to in my &lt;a href=&#34;https://paulstapel.github.io/write-in-blood/&#34;&gt;previous post&lt;/a&gt;. The flavour can best be described as má là, a Chinese term meaning numbing ( má 麻) and spicy ( là 辣). The aroma is citrusy and deep, and the flavour leaves you wanting more. I suggest you serve this with rice. This recipe takes about 45 minutes, but it is well worth it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pork belly (without the rind)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Black pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;About a tablespoon of red Sichuan peppercorns (less if you can&amp;rsquo;t stand the numbing effect)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Five-spice powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;High smoke point cooking oil (like vegetable oil)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Star anise&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ginger&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;As much pepper as you can handle (and don&amp;rsquo;t be a wimp!)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Half a liter of bone or beef stock&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Honey&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shaoxing cooking wine (optional, to deglaze if necessary)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Black bean sauce (optional, adds some counterbalance umami to this spicy dish)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Start by toasting the star anise and red Sichuan peppercorns in a non-oiled pan until fragrant. Put aside the star anise for later use.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Grind the peppercorns into dust, along with some black pepper.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cut your pork belly into bite sized strips, and cover it in about a tablespoon of five-spice powder.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Heat up a wok with oil until smoking, and cook the pork belly until brown. Get some of that Maillard reaction goodness in there. If you want, you can deglaze your pan with some cooking wine.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Put the pork aside, and start sautéing the onion until browned. After a bit, add in your peppers as well.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add your pork back to the pan. Add the stock with your toasted star anise, some slices of ginger and the ground powder of the peppercorn and black pepper. Let your mixture simmer until it has been reduced to about 1/3rd of what you started with. This may take a while.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;After your broth has been reduced to satisfaction, you can choose to take out the pork and add it back in at the last stage. This makes cooking the sauce easier, and it makes sure you don&amp;rsquo;t overcook the pork. It will still be delicious if you don&amp;rsquo;t.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To your broth, add some soy sauce, a generous helping of honey (at least 2-3 eating spoons) and some optional black bean sauce. Stir on high heat until the sauce has thickened.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, add everything back together, fish out the star anise and ginger, and serve with white rice.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;Enjoy!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Egg Drop Soup</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/egg-drop-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 21:12:21 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/egg-drop-soup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve started getting into making soup recently. This is new territory for me, but I decided to give it a try after pondering what to do with the leftover chinese cabbage that had been living rent-free in my fridge for too long. Behold! This soup was the result.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chinese Cabbage&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;About 1 liter of chicken stock&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Eggs (about 3)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White onion (can be omitted)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sesame oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Powdered or grated ginger&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt and (preferably white) pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Scallion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A little bit of cooking oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chop up your onions, garlic and scallion (put aside the green for garnish).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In a deep pot, start sweating the onion and scallion in a little bit of oil. After a few minutes, add the garlic as well.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Meanwhile, start tearing the cabbage apart with your hands. Doing it this way gives you nice and irregular pieces, which is nicer for the texture than when the cabbage is chopped.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add the chicken stock and add ginger, sesame oil, salt and pepper to taste. If you&amp;rsquo;re not sure, you can also add these ingredients after the next step, but I have found this to be less tasty.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add in the cabbage, and cover the pot with a lid. Leave it be for about 10 minutes, untill the cabbage has wilted.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, beat your eggs in a bowl. While stiring with one hand, slowly drizzle in the egg. This creates the signature egg ribbons associated with this dish. Let it rest for a few minutes and you&amp;rsquo;re ready to serve!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Orange Chicken</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/orange-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 21:28:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/orange-chicken/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have to admit, this is a guilty pleasure of mine. I don&amp;rsquo;t make this often, as it can take a bit long to make, but I always enjoy it when I do. If you are looking for a sweet and unique taste, look no further than this recipe. I suggest serving this with white rice.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;for-the-meat&#34;&gt;For the meat&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chicken breasts (whole, or already cubed)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;All purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cornstarch&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;High smoke-point oil like peanut oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;for-the-sauce&#34;&gt;For the sauce&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A bunch of oranges (5 per kilo of chicken, more if you like it saucy)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Alternatively, you can use orange juice instead of fresh oranges&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A bit of sugar (If it isn&amp;rsquo;t sweet enough already)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ginger (or ginger powder)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cornstarch (to thicken the sauce)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Squeeze the oranges and strain the juice.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add some soy sauce, garlic powder, ginger, (optional sugar) and cornstarch to the mixture.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cut the chicken into bite sized pieces (TIP; use sciccors)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Create a batter by mixing the flour and cornstarch in a ratio of about 2/1. Add a bit of water until the batter is smooth and then add a little bit of oil untill the batter is only a little thick.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Heat up a pan of your oil untill very hot. You can check this by putting in a drop of your batter.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Coat your chicken in your batter, and start adding the pieces to your pan one by one. Do this slowly, so that the pieces won&amp;rsquo;t stick to eachother. Be careful with splashing, as the oil doesn&amp;rsquo;t like the water of the batter. To prevent splashing, add some salt to the oil. Put the browned pieces onto a seperate plate.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once all chicken has been fried once, you can choose to fry them again. this will make the coloring nicer, and it will add a nicer crisp to the chicken.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Store the oil somewhere for later use, and pour your sauce mixture into the hot pan. Let it reduce at high heat untill the sauce becomes thick to your liking. I&amp;rsquo;d suggest letting it thicken a little longer than you&amp;rsquo;d think.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, add back the chicken, and coat it in the sauce. Serve it while it&amp;rsquo;s hot, and try not to let it rest too long, because it will lose its crisp.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hoisin Ground Beef</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/hoisin-ground-beef/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Apr 2024 10:51:32 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/hoisin-ground-beef/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This recipe is both simple and delicious. This is easy comfort food for when I don&amp;rsquo;t feel like cooking for too long.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ground beef&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yellow onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Spring onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(Optional) Shallots&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garden peas&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hoisin sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Oyster sauce (optional, adds umami)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shaoxing cooking wine (to deglaze)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sesame oil (optional, but it really is a finishing touch)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White rice&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Wash the rice and cook it. cut up the spring onion and reserve the greens for garnishing.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cut up the onions, shallots and garlic, and let them sweat on a medium heat, until they turn translucent.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mix in the ground beef, and let it brown on high heat&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add about a tablespoon of cooking wine to deglaze.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add soy sauce, hoisin sauce, oyster sauce and sesame oil in a 1/2/2/1 ratio.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, add the garden peas and garnish&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mongolian Beef</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/mongolian-beef/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 10:01:01 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/mongolian-beef/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This recipe makes for a delicious and saucy beef dish. It takes some time to prepare, but is well worth it.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;marinade&#34;&gt;Marinade&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Beef (I like using cheap steak for this, as the baking soda will tenderize it anyway)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shaoxing (cooking wine, sub with any rice wine)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(Dark) soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Oyster sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Some white pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A little cooking oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Baking soda (To tenderize the meat)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cornstarch (To keep the beef moist)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;sauce&#34;&gt;Sauce&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soy Sauce (light or dark)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sugar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Oyster Sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shaoxing (To deglaze)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A little cornstarch + water to thicken&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;veggies-for-stir-fry&#34;&gt;Veggies (for stir-fry)&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ginger&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Spring onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bell pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dried chili pepper (you can remove this if you don&amp;rsquo;t like spicy food)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cut the beef into strips and mix it with the marinade (add the cornstarch at the end) Let it sit for at least 15 minutes, but preferably a few hours.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cut the vegetables&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Prepare the sauce in a small bowl, with a separate bowl for the cornstarch slurry&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If time permits, I suggest you deep fry your beef in vegetable oil. This way, the texture will turn out crispy while the beef remains moist. Else, you can simply stir fry your mongolian beef instead.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Remove some of the oil and stir fry the veggies.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add in the sauce and the beef, and season to taste.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Garlic Beans</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/garlic-beans/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 17:59:38 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/garlic-beans/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Green beans&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ginger&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soy Sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Butter&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;First, fry the beans in the oil till they become shriveled and you begin to see some yellow.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next, in a new pan, add the butter and heat up the garlic, ginger and soy sauce on medium heat. Go easy on the soy sauce.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, add the beans back in and mix them with the sauce.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
