<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Indian on Paul&#39;s Particles</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/indian/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Indian on Paul&#39;s Particles</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 21:18:46 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/indian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Tikka Masala</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/tikka-masala/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 21:18:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/tikka-masala/</guid>
      <description>I always love the taste of Indian cuisine, and I usually turn to Indian food when I want a fix of rich and hearty flavours paired with a healthy feel. Today&amp;rsquo;s recipe is rather easy to make compared to other Indian curries, and it is an easy fix for when you crave something creamy. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if it can be classified as a weekday meal, but it is definetely easy enough to make it on a lazy sunday.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sausage Stew</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/sausage-stew/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 21:05:34 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/sausage-stew/</guid>
      <description>This recipe is a Paul-certified classic. It is easy to make (only about 30 minutes), and is quite filling for when you are having a busy week.&#xA;Ingredients Sausage (pork works well) Cooking oil A (small) tin of tomato paste Yellow onion Garlic Bell peppers (different colors looks the nicest, doesn&amp;rsquo;t really matter for taste) Beef broth Garam masala (can sub for 5-spice) Pepper Dark soy sauce (for color and salt) Cooking plan First, cook your sausage in an oiled pan until golden brown.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mint Dip</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/mint-dip/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 21:09:25 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/mint-dip/</guid>
      <description>So I am looking more into the indian cuisine. To start things off, I made a simple mint dip to eat with a meal, or just to dip naan in.&#xA;Ingredients Yoghurt Mint leaves (dried if fresh isn&amp;rsquo;t available) Lemon juice A clove of garlic Salt and pepper Cooking plan Finely chop the garlic and mint leaves Mix the ingredients to taste ENJOY! </description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
