<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Indian on Paul&#39;s Particles</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/indian/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Indian on Paul&#39;s Particles</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 20:06:04 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/indian/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Coconut Keema</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/coconut-keema/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 28 May 2025 20:06:04 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/coconut-keema/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yep, another keema recipe. Ground beef is cheap here in the Netherlands, and I always like to try interesting ways to spice up such a simple base. This is a go-to for when I crave some quick coconutty flavors.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ground beef&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Vegetable oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ginger&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Coconut milk&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tomato paste&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Koriander (Cilantro) (optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lemongrass (optional, for more of a Thai kick to the dish)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lemon juice (optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garam masala (optional, for extra seasoning to taste)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Spice mix (see below)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;spice-mix&#34;&gt;Spice mix&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2 tbsp coriander powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 tbsp turmeric powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 tbsp chili powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 tbsp paprika powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 tbsp cumin powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1/2 tsp ginger powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1/2 tsp Cinnamon powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1/2 tsp garlic powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1/2 tsp clove powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1/2 tsp cardamom powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1/2 tsp ground pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1/2 tsp salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Heat some vegetable oil in a pan on high heat and brown your ground beef until the water contents have evaporated.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chop up your aromatic vegetables (garlic, ginger, white onion, optional lemongrass) and add them to the pan. Optionally, you may want to give more attention to these veggies by removing the beef from the pan, but if you&amp;rsquo;re in a hurry, you can keep it all in the same pan.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add your tomato paste and let it cook for a bit to remove the water contents.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next, add your spice mix, stir a bit and then add your beef back to the pan.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add coconut milk until most of the beef is covered, and then let it simmer and reduce until the beef has become creamy and thick.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Season with garam masala, koriander and lemon juice to taste.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Aloo Keema</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/aloo-keema/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 21:52:56 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/aloo-keema/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ok, so I&amp;rsquo;ve got another Indian recipe I&amp;rsquo;d like to share with y&amp;rsquo;all. This is a dish that I did not understand for quite a while, and looking at recipes online, it seemed a little bland to me. Turns out this was all just a skill-issue, as I did not quite understand Indian food at that time. Knowing what I know now, I&amp;rsquo;d like to share an actually tasty recipe for aloo keema. I like serving this with naan, rice and my &lt;a href=&#34;https://paulstapel.com/recipes/mint-dip/&#34;&gt;mint dip&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gunter Chicken Masala</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/gunter-chicken-masala/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 07:12:39 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/gunter-chicken-masala/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been making a lot of masala recently, and this gunter chicken masala was really tasty when I tried making it. I have made some adjustments to my first iteration, and I hope you enjoy cooking this! Do keep in mind, this dish is among the spiciest I&amp;rsquo;ve made so far, so reduce the amount of dried chili&amp;rsquo;s if that is a problem.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;masala-powder&#34;&gt;Masala powder&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;About 4-5 dried chili&amp;rsquo;s&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2 tsp coriander seeds&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 tsp black peppercorns&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;1 tsp cumin seeds&#xA;To make the masala powder, first toast the whole spices and dried chili&amp;rsquo;s whole, and put them in a spice blender.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;masala-paste&#34;&gt;Masala paste&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2 tsp masala powder (that you just made)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;About 1 - 2 tsp minced ginger&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;About 4-5 cloves of garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A little water to make it a paste&#xA;We will use this masala paste to marinate the chicken. Again, mix all ingredients in a blender&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;marinade&#34;&gt;Marinade&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chicken (bone-in)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tumeric powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Masala paste (that you just made)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garam masala (only a little)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kashmiri chili powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Some salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yoghurt/lemon (yoghurt for more oily sauce, lemon for a bit of a drier curry)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;curry&#34;&gt;Curry&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mustard seeds&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cumin seeds&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Red onions&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tomato passata&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Masala powder (that you just made)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Vegetable oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chopped koriander (for garnish, optional but recommended)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cinnamon (to taste, for seasoning, optional but recommended)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In a pan, add some oil and start by cooking the mustard seeds and cumin seeds until fragrant.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next, add your red onions and stir for a while on medium-high heat, until they become a little browned and crispy.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In a food processor, blend the contents in your pan into a smooth paste. We will add this back later.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In your now cleared pan, start roasting the chicken on high heat. You want your chicken to be browned and almost cooked through.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next, add your tomato passata into the pan, and stir back in your onion paste.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Season with your masala powder, some optional cinnamon (for a little bit of a sweeter note to balance the spicy flavors) and top with your chopped koriander&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Saagwala</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/saagwala/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Mar 2025 21:13:47 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/saagwala/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am becoming a little obsessed with Indian cuisine, and while searching for new things to cook I stumbled upon Saagwala, and because I am a large fan of spinach, I simply had to try this. I find it is best served with Naan, but Roti and rice would also complement it quite well.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;marinate&#34;&gt;Marinate&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chicken (bone-in)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cooking oil (1 tbsp)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yoghurt (full) (enough to cover)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cayenne powder (2 tsp)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garam masala (2 tsp)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Coriander powder (2 tsp)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cumin powder (1 tsp)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fenugreek seeds (1 tsp)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;tumeric powder (1/2 tsp)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;curry&#34;&gt;Curry&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Spinach (a load of spinach, about equal weight to your meat)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Vegetable oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White onions (minced)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic (minced)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ginger (grated)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tomato paste&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Red or green chili&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Heavy cream (yoghurt would also work)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mint leafs (fresh, but dried also works)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cumin powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Coriander powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garam masala&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tumeric powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cayenne powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Start by marinating your chicken beforehand. Leave for at least 1 hour, but for about 6 hours or more if possible. Mix all of your marinate ingredients.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Preheat your oven to 200 degrees Celcius. Once it is warm, place your chicken on a baking sheet lined with parchment and cook for 30 minutes, turning it over after 15 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;While this is happening, boil some water and cook your spinach for about 5 minutes, until it has wilted completely. Once your spinach is done, drain it and blend it into a smooth paste.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In a large pan, start by heating up some vegetable oil and stir frying your white onions, garlic and ginger.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once browned a little, add your chili pepper and tomato paste, stiring all the while.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next, add your spices. Cumin powder, coriander powder, garam masala, tumeric powder and cayenne powder.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Stir back in your spinach and cover with heavy cream or yoghurt. Mix your curry well and let it cook through a little. If it is too thick, you may add some water or coconut milk.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;When your chicken is done, add it back to your curry.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garnish with fresh mint leafs. You may add some swirls of heavy cream or yoghurt for garnish as well.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chicken Korma</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/chicken-korma/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 20:52:55 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/chicken-korma/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I am always delighted when I try a new Indian recipe, and today was no different. I have eaten quite some Korma during my last trip to Singapore, and now I am happy to announce that I have managed to bring this flavor home. Enjoy this korma with white rice or naan.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;marinade&#34;&gt;Marinade&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chicken (bone-in)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garam masala&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Greek yoghurt (any fatty yoghurt will do)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Paprika powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kurkuma/tumeric powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ginger (fresh or alternatively ground)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic (fresh or alternatively ground)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;curry&#34;&gt;Curry&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ghee (or cooking oil)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Greek yoghurt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ground cardemom&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garam Masala&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White onion (We will caramelise, but for a more traditional flavor, deep fry the onion)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cashew nuts (for extra creaminess, normally tomatoes are added, but I prefer cashew nuts)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Green (or red) chilis&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cinnamon (stick, or ground)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cloves (whole or ground)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Nutmeg (grated or ground)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Coriander powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Fresh coriander leafs and/or mint leafs (or dried works fine as well)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bay leaf (optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mace (optional, but traditional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Start by marinating the chicken with all of the ingredients. Let it sit for about half an hour, or longer if time permits.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In a pan, heat up some ghee or oil and add some of your cardemom, until fragrant. Meanwhile, chop up your white onion into small chunks.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add your white onion into the pan and let it caramelise (or at least brown) on medium heat. Add a pinch of salt to speed up this process, as this will draw out the moisture. Near the end of the process, add your cashew nuts and chili pepper.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Put everything in this pan inside of a blender, along with enough yoghurt to cover it all. This will be a paste to add creaminess and flavor to your curry.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add some more ghee or oil to your pan and start by toasting your cinnamon, cloves, bay leaf, mace and some more cardemom.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once they are fragrant, add your chicken to the pan and let it cook on medium-high heat until it is (almost) cooked through.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next, add back your blended paste along with some hot water and season with garam masala and ground coriander.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, season to taste with some salt, garam masala, nutmeg and ground cloves (be careful with the amount you add!)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garnish with fresh koriander leafs and/or mint leafs, and serve with white rice or naan.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kheer</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/kheer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 07:31:25 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/kheer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been making breakfast more of a part of my daily routine lately. I think it has something to do with the fact that a lot of SEA-countries have warm breakfast, and I felt more invigorated last time I visited. So I started experimenting with breakfast recipes, and I have now decided to make it an entire category. To start, i wanted to share this Kheer recipe, as it is easy to make and energising. If you add more sugar, it can also be a dessert.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Roti</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/roti/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 17:23:35 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/roti/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love roti, and having now made it myself, I can safely say that its lovely flavor carries over to the home kitchen.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Flour (200 grams)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Butter (40 grams)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Butter (60+ grams) (used for the grilling of the roti)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Water (~100 grams after boiling)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt (1 teaspoon)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add together your butter, flour and a little salt.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Boil your water and let it cool to just below boiling temperature. Add it to your dough (this will melt the butter) and start mixing it. Use forks at first, and your hands after it has cooled down a bit.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Roll out your dough into thin sheets. The thinner they are, the better they will be cooked once they go into your pan.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cook your roti at high heat in a skillet or non-stick pan. For each roti you cook, coat the pan with butter and lay your roti on it. Wait until it bubbles up a little and starts to brown, and then flip it over. Your roti should be coated in the butter, so add more if you didn&amp;rsquo;t add enough.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;tips&#34;&gt;Tips&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You may want to pre-melt your butter used for cooking. This way, you have more control over the amount of butter added, and you can add more or less depending on the thickness of your dough (for thicker dough, it would be better to add twice instead of just once, so as to evenly coat both sides).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;You can rest your dough for about 15 minutes if time permits. This makes it easier to handle the dough. It does not do much for the flavor from what I have noticed, but it made rolling into sheets a bit easier for me.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tikka Masala</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/tikka-masala/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 21:18:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/tikka-masala/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I always love the taste of Indian cuisine, and I usually turn to Indian food when I want a fix of rich and hearty flavours paired with a healthy feel. Today&amp;rsquo;s recipe is rather easy to make compared to other Indian curries, and it is an easy fix for when you crave something creamy. I&amp;rsquo;m not sure if it can be classified as a weekday meal, but it is definetely easy enough to make it on a lazy sunday. You&amp;rsquo;ll probably have leftovers to boot.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sausage Stew</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/sausage-stew/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 21:05:34 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/sausage-stew/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This recipe is a Paul-certified classic. It is easy to make (only about 30 minutes), and is quite filling for when you are having a busy week.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sausage (pork works well)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cooking oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A (small) tin of tomato paste&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yellow onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bell peppers (different colors looks the nicest, doesn&amp;rsquo;t really matter for taste)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Beef broth&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garam masala (can sub for 5-spice)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dark soy sauce (for color and salt)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;First, cook your sausage in an oiled pan until golden brown. Get some Maillard reaction going.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Put the sausage aside and cut it into bit-sized pieces.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dice your onion and bell peppers, and heat them in the pan until most of the water has evaporated.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add your garlic and tomato paste, and let it cook until fragrant.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add your garam masala and pepper to a beef broth. You should be able to smell it.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add the seasoned beef broth and cooked sausage into the pan, and let the mixture reduce to a desired texture.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, add some dark soy sauce for color and salt.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mint Dip</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/mint-dip/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Apr 2024 21:09:25 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/mint-dip/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I am looking more into the indian cuisine. To start things off, I made a simple mint dip to eat with a meal, or just to dip naan in.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Yoghurt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mint leaves (dried if fresh isn&amp;rsquo;t available)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lemon juice&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A clove of garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt and pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finely chop the garlic and mint leaves&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mix the ingredients to taste&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
