<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Meditations on Paul&#39;s Particles</title>
    <link>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Meditations on Paul&#39;s Particles</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 22:20:43 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://paulstapel.com/meditation/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Sore Loser</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/sore-loser/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2025 22:20:43 +0800</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/sore-loser/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I figured it out - I figured it out from black and white&amp;rdquo; [One Direction]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;All I do is win, win, win no matter what&amp;rdquo; [DJ Khaled]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Just wanted to share a quick observation on humans, call it a philosophical inquiry if you will. Every person I know of is a sore loser. I believe this is something that lies in our human nature even.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Let me start off by saying that I don&amp;rsquo;t think that everyone gets angry at &amp;ldquo;losing&amp;rdquo;. Actually, I do think that all people would feel strongly in some way about losing, but taking a hard L, so to speak, is something that is exceptionally rare in developed human beings. I&amp;rsquo;ll stop being obtuse and give you the clue: we humans are very good at twisting the game and redefining it in our favor. So good, in fact, that we do nothing but win. Even if we show sportmanship at losing, we are in fact considering ourselves victorious because of our virtues. Even if mess something up, we rationalise it under the spirit of learning and consider ourselves winners. Does winning even hold any meaning? Maybe it is no more than a coping mechanism for losing.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Focus</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/focus/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Aug 2025 21:27:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/focus/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;If you want to complete a project, maximise the time you spend sat on your chair&amp;rdquo; [Jonathon Blow]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During this summer, I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing quite some work at the company I work for. Along with all the social obligations and events, it tired me out quite a bit. I got to do what I wanted to do, but I did notice that I noticed that I struggled staying focussed on what is important to me. Because of this, I wanted to do some reflection on focus, and how to get things done.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I Forgot</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/i-forgot/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 09:32:02 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/i-forgot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The right way to go easy is to forget the right way&amp;rdquo; [Zhuangzi]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I was looking at my blog, and found that some of the posts where set to draft. I forgot to post them, but ah well, it doesn&amp;rsquo;t really matter. I will be posting them soon, I think &amp;ndash; otherwise all posts will just be uploaded today, and that would be strange.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Forgetting is quite an interesting thing. We are scared to forget, but at the same time, it is something that helps us move on in life. It helps us keep our minds clean, and it helps us see things in a new perspective. There is pain in forgetting, and having to let go, but also a relief. It is a weird feeling, a feeling that tastes of grapefruits and freshly picked blackberries.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Purpose</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/on-purpose/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 08:10:23 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/on-purpose/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;He who has a why to live can bear almost any how&amp;rdquo; [Nietzsche]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Although my philosophy on life has been shaped quite strongly in the past few years, the goal of this philosophy was never quite as clear to me. I have built the framework from which I can persue my life goals, but for this to happen, I still needed true life goals. I always knew a direction somewhat, but experience has taught me that vague goals are almost never inspiring enough to be persued.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Response</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/correspondence/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2025 21:10:47 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/correspondence/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Dear Niels,&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I usually write towards myself in these meditations, but today I would like to write back to you instead.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;To start at the ending of your letter, I would like to say that I feel the concepts of &amp;ldquo;perception,&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;choosing,&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;reality&amp;rdquo; are indeed perceptions themselves—only deemed as such because we deem them to be reality. For quite a while now, I have taken a stance of contextual truth—that is, truth as something that lives within the construct of reality. With this letter, I would like to explore with you what reality and truth really entail for me.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Different Worlds</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/different-worlds/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Jun 2025 13:11:28 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/different-worlds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;World is as much perception as it is fact [Me]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As we develop and grow older, we come to face many realities. It starts at nothing, nothing to be percieved or thought, an empty slate. From there, we gain insight into the reality around us, our parents, our home, eventually our school. We play pretend, maybe watch some shows, play some games. Through our development, we come into contact with many different worlds. Even as adults, we meet new worlds at work, college, social gatherings, new towns and cities we may move to, countries we visit and the likes.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Muscle Memory</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/muscle-memory/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jun 2025 11:31:24 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/muscle-memory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;I fear not the man who has practiced 10,000 kicks once, but I fear the man who has practiced one kick 10,000 times&amp;rdquo; [Bruce Lee]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Proficiency is a beautiful thing. When we have reached a point where we can perform an action without having to think about it, it frees our mind to focus on what we wish to focus on, bringing us closer to non-action. In martial arts, we often hear that we must practice a certain technique hundreds of times over, and the same thing holds for all aspects of life. There where we want to live a truly fulfilling life, we must be able to have our body, mind and soul align with our actions.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Morning Rythms</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/morning-rythms/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 08:53:26 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/morning-rythms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Bathing in the morning sun, not only can we feel a presence of mind, but also a presence of God [Me]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;What a luxury it would be to have your window aligned with the sunrise. When spring slowly turns into summer, one of the most inspiring changes is that the sunrise is brought to us earlier and earlier. When I awake, I tend to become most energetic at sunrise, and this means that my sleep schedule also shifts earlier into the day. As the sun gently wakes me up, I awake without the need for an alarm &amp;ndash; ah what a wonderful feeling natural waking is.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Breakfast Battle</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/breakfast-struggles/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Apr 2025 07:12:52 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/breakfast-struggles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;“Eat breakfast like a king, lunch like a prince, and dinner like a pauper” [Adelle Davis]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d like to spend more time on my breakfasts. Usually, I cook quite lavishly when it comes to dinner, and I take quite some time to prepare a good meal for lunch, but breakfast has always been left behind a little by me. I&amp;rsquo;d like to change this soon, but there seem to be some things that stand in my way. These are a feeling that I lack creativity when it comes to the options for cooking breakfast, and a feeling that time could be wasted a little by taking too long on breakfast.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Setting Up</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/setting-up/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 21:28:53 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/setting-up/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[Donald Knuth] &amp;ldquo;Premature optimization is the root of all evil&amp;rdquo;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, I struggle with getting started on things because there are too many options for the set-up. Maybe this is because no real best way to do something is known, or maybe it is because there are too many good options available, but it leaves me a little paralysed afraid of heading down the wrong rabbit hole.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I meditated a little on this, and wanted to share two things that have helped me in this. Firstly, I need to accept that failing often is the best way to go (flywheel of becoming). Instead of going for the &amp;ldquo;most logical&amp;rdquo; or &amp;ldquo;most suitable&amp;rdquo; option, I should first go with the option with which I vibe the most. After that, I can always decide to switch if I find that something is wrong with the way I&amp;rsquo;m doing things now. Secondly, I should allow myself only a fixed set of time to work on making decisions when it comes to the set-up&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Poems on a Walk</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/poems-on-a-walk/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Apr 2025 22:08:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/poems-on-a-walk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[Me] Eenden op het meer // Een blad valt langzaam naar benee // Water onveroerd&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[Me] Boom van goud en rood // Buigt voorzichtig oeverwaarts // Kijkend naar zichzelf&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[Me] In zonnenflux // Stap voor stap // Ademt mijn geest // Een overstap // In rust&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;[Me] Ik dans // Naar het ritme // Van het ruisende gras in mijn tred // En de melodie // Van de zingende wind in mijn armen // Door de stilte heen // Ik dans&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Weak Week Planning</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/weak-week-planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Apr 2025 22:23:38 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/weak-week-planning/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Having no destination I am never lost&amp;rdquo; [Ikkyū]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When planning ahead, I usually only plan for one day. Everything after that is a little too far into the future for me, and I think it distracts from the present. If I plan too much, it may lead to &lt;a href=&#34;https://paulstapel.com/meditation/the-crushing-weight-of-time/&#34;&gt;multi-timing&lt;/a&gt;, which I try to avoid at all costs. Besides this, not planning too much is a way of practicing calendar yoga.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Of course, there are some things that need to be planned in advance. Most notibly, events like birthdays or hang-outs cannot usually be planned on the same day, as then it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t fit in everyone&amp;rsquo;s schedule. When it comes to my calendar then, I tend to only keep track of future events and obligations. Lastly, I practice something that I call &amp;ldquo;weak week planning&amp;rdquo;. While I set in stone the tasks I want to get done that day each morning, I simply assign days a certain theme for a week or even month. For example, knowing I have 5 courses I am enrolled in, I would theme each day around a certain subject, and make sure to keep one day free to finish everything I couldn&amp;rsquo;t on that day. The most important thing in this kind of scheduling is that I know that in a given week, everything will have a day assigned to it. These days are easily interchangable, but knowing what needs to be done in rough terms help me understand what trade-offs I am making when I decide to suddenly do something else.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My Experience with Romance</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/why-need-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Apr 2025 14:47:43 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/why-need-love/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;My formula for greatness in a human being is amor fati: that one wants nothing to be different, not forward, not backward, not in all eternity. Not merely bear what is necessary, still less conceal it - all idealism is mandaciousness in the face of what is necessary - but love it&amp;rdquo; [Friedrich Nietzsche]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As I have stated last week, love is a troubling subject to me. It has taken many a nights of pondering this abstract topic for me to even discover my feelings on it, and only after a relationship of about two years have I grasped them in some capacity. One of the greatest findings has been that I actually don&amp;rsquo;t feel a strong need for romantic love. I would like to bring some nuance to these thoughts of mine.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Silent Observation</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/silent-observation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2025 20:30:43 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/silent-observation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Poetry should be great and unobtrusive, a thing which enters into one&amp;rsquo;s soul, and does not startle it or amaze it with itself, but with its&#xA;subject&amp;rdquo; [John Keats]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I could ask myself to think about the way I am breathing currently. It is often joked that this makes you start to think too much about your breathing, making you switch from automatic breathing to manual breathing. I have been reading &amp;ldquo;The Art of Game Design&amp;rdquo; by Jesse Schell, and in one of the earlier chapters, he talks about the paradox of actually observing your experiences. If we want to learn our thoughts about a certain experience, it would be best to observe our own thoughts while we are still experiencing it, as it is much harder to bring back those feelings after the fact. The quantum-mechanics-like problem we face here is that the act of observing our experience disturbs it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Post Mortem of First Love</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/post-mortum-of-love/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Apr 2025 20:36:52 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/post-mortum-of-love/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The saddest thing about love is not only that it cannot last forever, but that heartbreak is soon forgotten&amp;rdquo; [William Faulkner]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Last December, I broke up with my first serious partner. We had been together for 2 years by then, but we both agreed that it would be better for us to go our own ways. As it has now been 5 months already, I felt it was finally time to write down some of my meditations that came from this breakup. I was hesitant to post things too soon, as it could have been interpreted as either spiteful or bitter to post about my past relationship so soon after it ended. Of course, I don&amp;rsquo;t mean this post to be any of those things, and I&amp;rsquo;d like to reiterate that there has been no bad blood between us &amp;lt;3.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>View From the Summit</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/view-from-the-summit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 21:10:30 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/view-from-the-summit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Defeat is a state of mind; no one is ever defeated until defeat has been accepted as a reality&amp;rdquo; [Bruce Lee]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Yesterday marked the end of my most recent semester of university, and one of the most challenging semesters yet. I was faced with the mountain that was the course &amp;ldquo;topology and geometry&amp;rdquo;, a course on abstract topology. If you are interested in reading my original thoughts on this course, &lt;a href=&#34;https://paulstapel.com/meditation/facing-mountains/&#34;&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d refer you to this post&lt;/a&gt;, where I shared my anxieties going into this semester. Just having finished the exam yesterday, I am happy to announce that I passed this and all other courses generously.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Rejecting the Self</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/on-rejecting-the-self/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 08:16:12 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/on-rejecting-the-self/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Oh, you sentimental hypocrites, you lustful men! You lack innocence in desire: and therefore you now slander desiring!&amp;rdquo;  [Nietzsche]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;After re-reading Nietzsche&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;Of immaculate perception&amp;rdquo;, I started seeing some of the subjects of resentment more clearly. It is all too common to reject our own nature, and resent our love and desire in this world for we lack a certain innocence in this desiring. We can be a jealous bunch, afraid of our own desires. It is like a child throwing a tantrum, saying that if they can&amp;rsquo;t have it, nobody can. Instead of little fists, we wave around morals and values.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>On Company And Solitude</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/on-company-and-solitude/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Feb 2025 21:48:14 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/on-company-and-solitude/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;My solitude doesn&amp;rsquo;t depend on the presence or absence of people; on the contrary, I hate who steals my solitude without, in exchange, offering me true company&amp;rdquo; [Nietzsche]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Solitude is a tricky thing. On the one hand, I strive to find peace in solitude, and the time I spend with myself is among the most peaceful time I can have. On the other, I recognise that a certain balance needs to be struck between relying on friends and relying on self. Both love of your neighbours and love of solitude can come from resentment of yourself. Truly, our company can be solitude when it is an escape from the self, for how can we be present if we have fled? And similarly, our solitude can become numbing if the &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rdquo; escapes the self, for how can we feel if we have fled?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Awake</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/awake/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2025 08:08:04 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/awake/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;As yet hath his knowledge not learned to smile, and to be without jealousy; as yet hath his gushing passion not become calm in beauty [Nietzsche]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, things in life may inspire you to a deeper contemplation. Things that once eluded you suddenly become clearer, and more present in your mind. It can feel as if things just fall in place, and a fire of passion consumes you thus. But it is not that which life reveals to me, but that which life conceals from me that fuels me most. There hangs an innate urge in mankind to dig up all that which is hidden from it; we are a curious bunch. To dig is a noble cause, but those who dig must beware its consequences. As humanity ever carves deeper into world&amp;rsquo;s flesh, world itself becomes &amp;hellip; a graveyard! Oh, how to express that this is devoutly to be wished? And if our knowledge not be sent to the grave, let it be cremated in the flames of our inspiration!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Crushing Weight of Time</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/the-crushing-weight-of-time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 08:01:39 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/the-crushing-weight-of-time/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;The past wants to be loved, the future heard and the present lived - such is the nature of time&amp;rdquo; [Me]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;We are subject to much force throughout our lives. I myself can feel this resistance in much of what I do. A principle I try to live by is to follow the path of least resistance - to go with the flow of the way of life. I also believe that life is what you make of it, and that our actions shape these paths for our future. Living with only the present in mind, while admirable, may lead to greater resistance down the line.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Facing Mountains</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/facing-mountains/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 08:00:26 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/facing-mountains/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;On the mountains of truth you can never climb in vain; either you will reach a point higher up today, or you will be training so that you will be able to climb higher tomorrow&amp;rdquo; [Nietzsche]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Last academic period didn&amp;rsquo;t go easy on me. Or more accurately, I didn&amp;rsquo;t go easy on myself. I always aim to challenge myself, and with all the things that I had to do outside of studying I found myself struggling quite a bit more than previous periods. This, i believe, is a good thing, as it means that I am slowly approaching my limit and finding new ways to challenge myself.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>The Slow Days of January</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/the-slow-days/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 16 Jan 2025 13:28:45 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/the-slow-days/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Winter is a slow heartbeat, an aged murmur of lifelong love&amp;rdquo; [Angie Weiland-Crosby]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;During these cold winter months, it is easy to let the mind slow down to a halt. The combination of cold temperature and short days makes for a season of tiredness, but also of tranquility. I wanted to take this slow afternoon to reflect on this beautiful January, and to shape my winter ways.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;staying-lively&#34;&gt;Staying lively&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Winter is a numb season. The trees and flowers that promptly die, the frost that paints our windows and the cold winds that chill us to the bone all exemplify this. How then, must we keep our spirit bright when all around us is white and gray? Can we manage to see this blank canvas of a world as a contrast to our own colors all the more? Laugh then! Let not only the sun reflect on your teeth as it does on the snow, but let this laugh itself become sun.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Conversations are like fishing</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/social-initiation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Jan 2025 08:33:09 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/social-initiation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Life is a conversation, make it a good one&amp;rdquo; [Glennon Doyle]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In keeping with my new year resolutions, I started meditating on how I can become a more sociable person. One of the core parts of being social is conversation, and while I have learned a lot about how to hold an engaging conversation, there is always one thing that I find difficult: How do you start a conversation in a natural way?&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I may run a marathon</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/marathon_idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 08:01:35 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/marathon_idea/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Once you make the decision that you will not fail, the heart and body will follow&amp;rdquo; [Kara Goucher]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;So a few friends of mine came up with the idea to run a marathon in 2026. Now, I have been running for about 4 months, and I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have imagined doing this 1 year ago. I wanted to share some of my personal observations.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-physical-confidence&#34;&gt;My physical confidence&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In my youth, I wasn&amp;rsquo;t always the fittest person. Some could say I was a little chubby, or more bluntly, quite fat. I was bad at sports and couldn’t run a mile if my life depended on it.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>My resolutions for 2025</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/resolutions2025/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 11:28:11 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/resolutions2025/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;A path is made by walking it&amp;rdquo; [Chuang Tsu]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;2024 was a good year for me. It was a year of great fortune in my education, work and home life. That being said, I have even more to look forward to in 2025, and one of the things I always embrace in the new year is the opportunity to steer myself in the right direction along the tracks of life. Today, I will discuss the things I would like to improve upon when it comes to my body, mind and soul in 2025.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Noticing My Bad Habits</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/noticing-no-no/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 21:23:27 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/noticing-no-no/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Every battle is won before it is fought&amp;rdquo; [Sun Tzu]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;In my life, I have noticed that most of my failings are only recognized in hindsight. It is often easier to look back with an analytical mind than to analyze the situation on the fly. This is exactly why I mostly fall victim to my unwillingness to say no when I am put on the spot. From my experience, the best way to shift this bad habit is to analyze the course of action beforehand. Luckily, I already have some systems in place that make it easier for me to act more mindfully, and the implementation of these tricks is exactly what this meditation was centered around.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning To Say No</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/learning-to-say-no/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Sep 2024 19:56:21 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/learning-to-say-no/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;You have to learn to say no to many good things if you want to say yes to many great things&amp;rdquo; [Unknown]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Recently, I have found myself having trouble saying no to people. Of course, when push comes to shove, I know when to stand my ground when I strongly believe in something, but the main problem lies in saying no to good things. In order to explore this, I will take you on a journey of meditation where I explore this side of myself for the first time. That&amp;rsquo;s right, it&amp;rsquo;s time for a certified &amp;ldquo;Paul character arc&amp;rdquo;!&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rebalancing Oneself</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/rebalancing-oneself/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Sep 2024 21:41:30 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/rebalancing-oneself/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Balance is not something you find but something you create&amp;rdquo; [Me]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Sometimes, I feel like I&amp;rsquo;m finally getting in a good groove. In those times, my studying routine works, my workout routine works, I&amp;rsquo;m being social and am taking care of myself and the people around me. Then, something happens that knocks me off-balance. This summer, it has been a wonderful vacation to Vietnam that saw me quickly adapt my way of living to this travelling lifestyle, but this sweeping force may also be something a little less enjoyable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mishaps</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/mishaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jul 2024 22:16:37 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/mishaps/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Falling down is an accident, staying down is a choice&amp;rdquo; [Unknown]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;When working on becoming the person you want to be, it is often in the stressful and doubtful situations that you find out your conviction is strong. You can tell alot about yourself and your growth as a person from how you deal with hardship, however small it may be.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It is good excercise to ask yourself what your instinctual reaction is when something goes wrong. For me, I usually get quite defensive, trying to either shift the blame or talk my way out of it. For me, the first step in growth is recognising this harmful behaviour. The next step is to correct it when I notice it happening. The final step would be to let go of this behaviour altogether.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pretty Things</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/pretty-things/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2024 22:44:55 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/pretty-things/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Beauty exists only to relief us from ugliness&amp;rdquo; [Oscar Wilde]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Often in live, I find myself feeling like I&amp;rsquo;m above the need for beauty. It can be seen as a virtue to look not at appearance but at what lies within. I agree with this, but only recently have I come around to realising that beauty has its place as well. A lack of elegance or beauty can be distracting. This distraction may take some effort to look through, ultimately draining (a slight amount of) energy.Oppositely, beauty can also motivate and invigorate the mind. It can be seen as a way of seeing beauty in the world and embracing the effect it has on you.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beginnings</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/beginnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jul 2024 19:52:09 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/meditation/beginnings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Meditation is conversation with the soul&amp;rdquo; [Me]&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;/blockquote&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;For quite some time now, I&amp;rsquo;ve been wanting to put more of my creative energy into my blog. To do this, I have tried to understand what makes me me by finding my creative voice. I&amp;rsquo;m afraid this question is too grand for me to answer in one go. In my life, I have meditated quite often, and this is just one of many other topics I will meditate on in my life.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
