<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Coding on Paul&#39;s Particles</title>
    <link>https://paulstapel.com/categories/coding/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Coding on Paul&#39;s Particles</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 08:49:06 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://paulstapel.com/categories/coding/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Ode to MVPs</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/ode-to-mvp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 19 Apr 2025 08:49:06 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/ode-to-mvp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I believe humans have an innate urge to create things. We like being creative and making things like books, paintings or clothes. It is quite a shame, then, that people often have a rough time getting started with such a creative project. Procrastination is quite easy, and one large part in this is that it takes time before a project actually becomes fun to work on. It doesn&amp;rsquo;t help that the start of a project is usually the time when you are most overwhelmed with options. Because of this, it can take a lot of effort to even get started with a project, let alone finish it. I have reflected on this quite a bit and would like to share some of my findings.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creating a Table of Contents</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/creating-table-of-contents/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 15:15:55 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/creating-table-of-contents/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ok, so as my blog has been growing recently, I decided it was about time I started implementing some more features. One of the things I wanted to add was a little floating table of contents. From there, users would be able to more easily navigate through a given page, and as I have just recently implemented my &lt;a href=&#34;https://paulstapel.com/codex/codex-meae-mentis/&#34;&gt;codex&lt;/a&gt;, I felt it was about time to create this. As I found it rather difficult to find things about this online, I wanted to quickly share my implementation. I will be using HTML, Javascript and CSS.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3D Rotation in Python with quaternions</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/3d-rotation-python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 20 Apr 2024 15:55:07 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/3d-rotation-python/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today, I wanted to share a bit of code that you can use to rotate any 3D vector using Python.&#xA;If you want to read a bit about how the code works, and why quaternions are useful, keep reading. If you are only interested in the code, I have it in full &lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/PaulStapel/quaternions&#34;&gt;on my GitHub&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;quickly-what-is-a-quaternion&#34;&gt;Quickly, what is a quaternion?&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A quaternion is an extension of the complex numbers into 4 dimensions. Just like how you can describe a rotation in 2D using a complex number, a quaternion can describe rotation in 3D. By defining some rules for multiplication ($i^2 = j^2 = k^2 = ijk = -1$), we get certain properties that make rotation very intuitive. See this &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Quaternions_and_spatial_rotation&#34;&gt;wikipedia article on quaternions&lt;/a&gt; for more details.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VScode extensions that boost my productivity</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/vscode-extensions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 20:57:18 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/vscode-extensions/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As I have stated in my setup-page, I use VScode as my main text editor. I especially like the ability to customize your coding environment with extensions. Today, I will share the extensions that really give a boost to my work.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;better-comments&#34;&gt;Better Comments&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This first extension allows me to better manage and organize my annotations while coding. When starting comments with alerts (!), questions (?), TODO&amp;rsquo;s (TODO), or important tags (*), this extension automatically colors them to make them stand out more. This makes it so I can more easily find the information I&amp;rsquo;m looking for, and it has saved me more time than I initially expected.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
