<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Difficulty 2|5 on Paul&#39;s Particles</title>
    <link>https://paulstapel.com/categories/difficulty-25/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Difficulty 2|5 on Paul&#39;s Particles</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 20:29:54 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://paulstapel.com/categories/difficulty-25/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Roasted Veggies</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/roasted-veggies/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 20:29:54 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/roasted-veggies/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This post is a simple one, but simple does not always have to equal bland. Usually when veggies are served, I find them a little dull, but I have just recently opened my eyes to the possibilities of some good ol&amp;rsquo; roasted veggies. Pair them with a juicy piece of meat, and you&amp;rsquo;ve got yourself a wonderful meal.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Extra virgin olive oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt and pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dried Italian herbs (rosemary, basil, oregano, thyme, parsley)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mustard&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Grated cheese (only a little, ads a nice flavor and crisp)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;veggies&#34;&gt;Veggies&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Choose any combination of:&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Peanut Noodles</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/peanut-noodles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Apr 2025 07:47:32 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/peanut-noodles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;On a budget? Check! Done in under 10 minutes? Check! Vegan? Check! Delicous? CHEACHK (check in Portuguese?).&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Whole peanuts&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sesame seeds&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Peanut butter&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Noodles (I use udon noodles)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Spring onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soy sauce (I use dark, but light works as well for a stronger flavor)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Vinegar (I use Chinkiang vinegar)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chili oil (Lao Gan Ma also works)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ginger&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Grind some of your peanuts and leave some whole for a more interesting texture. Then, start by toasting your whole peanuts and sesame seeds.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next, finely mince your garlic and ginger, add chili oil to your pan and sauté your aromatics.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Meanwhile, bring some water to a boil and cook your noodles per package instructions.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once fragrant, add the white part of your spring onion as well.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To your pan, add some vinegar, soy sauce and some scoops of peanut butter to taste. Mix well, as the peanut butter needs to be fully encorporated into the sauce.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally mix your noodles through your sauce and garnish with the green part of your spring onion.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chili Beans</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/chili-beans/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 07:38:52 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/chili-beans/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For this dish, I was inspired by a recipe from a book I was recently given (One Piece: Pirate Recipes xD). It is a very simple recipe, and I wished to expand upon it to make it even tastier.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kidney beans&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ground beef (or pork, or mixed)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ground cayenne pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Paprika powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tomato paste&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Diced chipotle peppers in adobo sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cooking oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Start by seasoning your ground beef with ground cayenne pepper, salt and paprika powder.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To a pan add some cooking oil and brown your ground beef.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Meanwhile, start mincing your onion and garlic. Once your ground beef is done, remove it from your pan and add the onion. After it has turned translucent, add your garlic.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add some tomato paste to your pan, along with the diced chipotle peppers in adobo sauce. Stir and let it deepen its color a little before adding some water and your kidney beans.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Let the beans simmer for a bit until most of the water has evaporated. Finally, add back in your ground beef and season to taste with your spices.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This recipe pairs well with nachos, tortillas or rice for example.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Eel Brioche Amuse</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/eel-brioche-amuse/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 13:09:16 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/eel-brioche-amuse/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My friend Levi and I usually like to cook when we meet up. He is active in the culinary world as a host, and before that he has also worked in the kitchen for a while. It helps that we both have a soft spot for good food :). Last week, he surpised me with an amuse that he had devised himself. It was light yet incredibly tasty, and for how easy it was to make, it left a fancy impression. To honor him, I&amp;rsquo;d like to share this recipe on my blog.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Festival</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/festival/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 09:40:40 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/festival/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I really like &lt;a href=&#34;https://paulstapel.com/recipes/jerk-chicken/&#34;&gt;my take on jerk chicken&lt;/a&gt;, which is why I decided to try a side-dish to complement it. I eventually settled on this classic Jamaican treat: festivals. It is quick and easy to make, and can even be enjoyed as a dessert with some added sugar.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Flour (500 grams)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cornmeal (60 grams) (or substitute with breadcrumbs)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Baking powder (25 grams)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Brown sugar (2 - 4 table spoons, depending on how sweet you like it)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cocounut milk (200 milliliters)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Butter (50 grams) (softened or melted)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A pinch of salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cinnamon (3/4 - 1 tsp)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Grated/powdered nutmeg (A hint, about 1/4 - 1/2 tsp)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Oil to fry in (I used sunflower oil)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In a pan on medium to high, heat up your cooking oil. We will fry the festivals in this. The temperature should not be too high, as it will cause the dough to not cook properly on the inside.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In a bowl, start by quickly mixing your dry ingredients.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Work in your butter, and then incrementally mix in your coconut milk until you get a singular clump of dough. The dough should be a little flaky, and should easily break apart when stretched.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Let your dough rest for at least 10 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;From the dough, roll small cylinders of medium thickness. Fit as many as you can in your pan, but be careful not to overcrowd, as they grow when you place them in the oil. Once they turn a nice golden brown color, remove from the oil and lay on some paper towels to drain off excess oil.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Keep frying until all of the dough has been depleted.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Queso</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/queso/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 09:19:17 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/queso/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I have guests around, I want to make something easy and filling that I can just put on the table and forget about. Dips are perfect for this, as it creates a central piece whereabout everyone can gather. I really like this recipe as a guilty pleasure, and would like to share it with you all now.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ground beef or chorizo (about 300 to 400 grams)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White onion (one large white onion)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Flour (2 tbsp)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Milk (1.5 cups, less if you want a more solid queso)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mozerella (2 pieces)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Old cheese (To taste)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Parmesan (To taste)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cilantro (a.k.a. coriander) (To taste)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt and black pepper (be mindful of salt content in your other ingredients) (To taste)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Diced chipotle peppers (optional, add extra rich flavor and makes the whole more varied)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Preheat your oven to 200 degrees Celcius.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In a skillet, brown your ground beef or heat up your chorizo. Season it with salt and pepper. While it is browning, chop up a white onion.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once browned, add your chopped onion and stir on high heat until translucent and a little browned.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add some flour to your pan and let it heat up for a bit. Then, add your milk as well.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add your mozerella, and grate your old cheese and parmesan. Add it to the pan and let it melt a bit.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Stir through some cilantro (and diced chipotle peppers) and further season to taste with more salt and pepper if necessary.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Put your skillet int he oven until you queso has bubbled up and has achieved a golden yellow color.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pico De Gallo</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/pico-de-gallo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 08:50:28 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/pico-de-gallo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love Mexican food, and I can never resist a good salsa. I wanted to start making more salsa whenever I make Mexican food from now on, and I decided to start with a pico de gallo, as it is well defined and a tried and true recipe. This is definetely not my own recipe, as I am just throwing ingredients in a bowl, but I will outline some of the things I do to make it taste even better.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Kheer</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/kheer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 07 Feb 2025 07:31:25 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/kheer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have been making breakfast more of a part of my daily routine lately. I think it has something to do with the fact that a lot of SEA-countries have warm breakfast, and I felt more invigorated last time I visited. So I started experimenting with breakfast recipes, and I have now decided to make it an entire category. To start, i wanted to share this Kheer recipe, as it is easy to make and energising. If you add more sugar, it can also be a dessert.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mustard Béchamel Sauce</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/mustard-bechamel-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 07:29:04 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/mustard-bechamel-sauce/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So I was looking for something to add some extra flavor to schnitzels, as I really like eating them, but they get a little plain after a while if you only add lemon. That&amp;rsquo;s why I thought of making some kind of mustard sauce, and ended up with this recipe. A friend of mine talked about making béchamel sauce using chicken stock, and after having tried this it actually tasted better than I expected, so I added it to this main recipe.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jerk Chicken my way</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/jerk-chicken/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 10:54:29 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/jerk-chicken/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Yesterday, I combined my love for Jamaican food and inventing new foods to come up with a delicious take on jerk chicken. The result is this simple recipe that consists of simply grilling the chicken and then broiling it in the flavorsome jerk sauce. I usually serve this with a baguette, as the sauce is just heavenly for dipping.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I am trying to experiment with measurements, as I&amp;rsquo;ve had quite some people approach me saying they would like to know exactly how much to add of each ingredient. Keep in mind that I don&amp;rsquo;t exactly measure my ingredients, and that these measurements are thus geusstimates of how much I usually add.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Htipiti</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/htipiti/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 14:47:30 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/htipiti/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is pronounced &amp;ldquo;tee-pee-tee&amp;rdquo; by the way. Serve with pita or something, idk, idc, I&amp;rsquo;m not your mom.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Feta cheese&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Red bell peppers&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Extra virgin olive oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Red wine vinegar or lemon juice&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Black pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Preheat your oven to 200 degrees Celcius&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cut the four sides of your bell peppers and reduce the stem. Lay them out on a baking tray and put them in the oven for roughly 25 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once your peppers are done, put them in a bowl and cover them to let them steam for another 10 to 20 minutes. This will make it easier to remove the skin of the peppers.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To a food processor, add feta cheese, your bell peppers (skin removed), a little red wine vinegar/lemon juice and some extra virgin olive oil.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, season to taste with salt and pepper.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Larb</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/larb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 13:06:08 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/larb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few years back, I had a trip to Thailand with my family. While there, we ate a lot of very delicious food, and I have been recreating the things I ate there quite often.&#xA;One thing that does bug me about doing this, however, is the fact that some of the ingredients can be quite troublesome to acquire. Not today however, as we will be making larb.&#xA;The ingredients used for this are quite easy to come by in your local Asian supermarket or even just the grocery store. Serve with rice, naan or even tortilla&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beef/Pork Stroganoff</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/beef-stroganoff/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 21:19:53 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/beef-stroganoff/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;All jokes aside, this recipe results in a rich and creamy beef stroganoff. As pork is a lot cheaper where I live, I often use pork as instead of beef. This is still very tasty, but if you can, try making it with beef, as it will be even richer in flavor. You should serve it with pasta. I recommend serving this with pasta like tagliatelle, but mashed potatoes would also be verrryyy good I imagine. Without further ado, let&amp;rsquo;s get into this recipe :D&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pork Adobo</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/pork-adobo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 20:48:12 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/pork-adobo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My auntie Rose from the Philippines shared this awesome recipe with me recently, and i&amp;rsquo;ve made it a few times now. I will be sharing the base recipe with some optional ingredients you may add, but having cooked this dish in a few different ways now, I can safely say that all of them are delicous. Serve with white rice.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pork belly (or chicken for chicken adobo) (Use the bones seperately as well if you have them)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic (lots of it)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Olive oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;String beans (Optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Potatoes (Optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hard boiled egg (Optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White onion (Own addition, optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;for-the-marinade&#34;&gt;For the marinade&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White vinegar (I have found that Chinkiang black vinegar also works, but I prefer white)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Brown sugar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Black pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bay leafs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Warm water&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There are two ways to do the marinade. Firstly, you can add the marinade and salt to your pork and leave it to marinade overnight. Alternatively, you can salt the pork and cook it first, then add the marinade later. Either way, the marinade can be made by mixing all of the ingredients listed and adjusting to taste.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finely mince your garlic. Usually, I use about a foot of garlic. Make sure it is pasted or finely minced.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To a pot on high heat, add your pork (chicken) and brown it. After that is done, you may remove it from the pan and lower the heat.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next add your (optional, chopped) white onion and a (mandatory) lot of garlic to your pan and fry it untill browned.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If you have bones, add them now and cook them in the same oil.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next, you may add your optional string beans and potatoes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once the bones are done, you can add your pork (chicken) back into the pan and continue cooking for a minute before adding your sauce.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;While this is cooking, you may optionally boil some eggs to add to your pan.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Let this simmer on medium heat for a while, until the desired texture is acquired. Serve with white rice.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Garlixplosion Noodles</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/garlicsplosion-noodles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 08:19:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/garlicsplosion-noodles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The only way to make a good dish even gooder is to add an exuberant amount of garlic to it. That was exactly the premise of this little experiment. Adding a lot of garlic and seeing where it leads me. It turned out to be a delightful recipe that I have even decided to share her on my blog. Be warned, not for the faint of heart.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lots of garlic (I used about 2 bulbs, but adjust to your own tolerance/taste)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Noodles&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Zucchini&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ground beef or meatballs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chili oil (I use Lao Gan Ma)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A little vegetable oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Light soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Optional black bean sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To a pot, add some salted water and cook your noodles as per the instructions on the package.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next, mince the onion and cut up the zucchini into small pieces. If you&amp;rsquo;re not using a garlic press, mince your garlic.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add some vegetable oil to your pan and start by sweating the onions. After they are translucent, turn up the heat and add your zucchini and chili oil. Lastly, add your garlic (using a garlic press).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;At this point, you may add your meat. I used meatballs (cursed, I know), but ground beef also works great. Be sure to stir often, as otherwise your aromatics may burn.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;When your sauce has browned, add light soy sauce and optional black bean sauce to taste. I used a ratio of 3:1 for these ingredients. You can also add some more Lao Gan Ma if you want.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lastly, toss your noodles into your pan and stir carefully until it is covered in sauce.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbonara</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/carbonara/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 20:03:41 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/carbonara/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, yesterday I was craving some good &amp;lsquo;ol spaghetti. I usually go with a tomato sauce, but this time, I saw that I still had some parmigiano in my fridge. I simply couldn&amp;rsquo;t resist the urge to try something new, and ended up making this delicious carbonara. It may not be the healthiest, but it was definitely worth it in the end. I included a secret ingredient of miso paste in order to boost the umami content. Although I strongly recommend you put it, the dish will still turn out yummy if omitted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ants Climbing a Tree</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/ants-climbing-a-tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 20:38:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/ants-climbing-a-tree/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a long day of work, you probably don&amp;rsquo;t want to have to cook anything complicated. Whenever I have days like this, I like keeping it simple as well. Of course, simple does not necessarily mean bland, and this dish is both easy and flavorful. The name &amp;ldquo;Ants climbing a tree&amp;rdquo; stems from the fact that the small ingredients on top of the glass noodles look like ants climbing a tree. I&amp;rsquo;ll have to admit that I started cooking this dish purely because I thought the name sounded cute&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tennessee Onion</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/tennessee-onion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 21:18:06 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/tennessee-onion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ok, so the description may have been a lie. I usually don&amp;rsquo;t barbecue because Dutch weather can be very unpredictable (Dutch struggles). Instead, I like to put stuff in the oven (like a true patriot). Therefore, this dish will be using our favorite inferno machine. The TTC (time to cook) is about an hour, so prepare it well in advance!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White onions&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shredded cheese (Gouda, because it melts well and because it&amp;rsquo;s Dutch)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Butter&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Paprika powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chopped parsley&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dried thyme&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dried oregano&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Aluminum foil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Preheat an oven to 160 degrees Celsius.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Start peeling the onions and cutting them into rings.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In a casserole, layer the onion rings. If you have lots of mouths to feed, make multiple layers.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On top of your layer of onion rings, add your herbs and cheese. Add a generous amount of cheese, but reserve some for later.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, add some small cubes of butter spread evenly throughout the dish and cover it with the aluminum foil. Put it in the oven and cook for 40 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;After 40 minutes, take out your casserole. Sprinkle over a little of your remaining cheese, and put it back into the oven, uncovered. Leave it in for another 20 minutes, and you&amp;rsquo;re ready to serve.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Souvlaki</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/souvlaki/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 07:26:17 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/souvlaki/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a lovely meaty dish that you can serve as a main course. With summer at its peak, you enjoy this dish on straight from the grill during a barbecue for example.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;marinade&#34;&gt;Marinade&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(extra virgin) olive oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Oregano&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sweet paprika powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Thyme (optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bay leaves&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Juice from a lemon&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;LOTS OF GARLIC&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt and pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chicken (cubed, which you&amp;rsquo;ll marinate)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mince the garlic. You should use enough that you can smell it. I used 8 cloves (slightly more than a bulb) per kilo last time.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mix everything into a ziplock bag or marinating bowl.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Stir in the chicken, and let it sit for an hour or preferably two (not for too long! The lemon will slowly cook the chicken, lessening its taste after a certain amount of time)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Skewer the chicken (or cook it in a skillet if you want). You can grill the skewers on a barbecue.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Egg Drop Soup</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/egg-drop-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 21:12:21 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/egg-drop-soup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve started getting into making soup recently. This is new territory for me, but I decided to give it a try after pondering what to do with the leftover chinese cabbage that had been living rent-free in my fridge for too long. Behold! This soup was the result.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chinese Cabbage&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;About 1 liter of chicken stock&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Eggs (about 3)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White onion (can be omitted)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sesame oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Powdered or grated ginger&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt and (preferably white) pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Scallion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A little bit of cooking oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chop up your onions, garlic and scallion (put aside the green for garnish).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In a deep pot, start sweating the onion and scallion in a little bit of oil. After a few minutes, add the garlic as well.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Meanwhile, start tearing the cabbage apart with your hands. Doing it this way gives you nice and irregular pieces, which is nicer for the texture than when the cabbage is chopped.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add the chicken stock and add ginger, sesame oil, salt and pepper to taste. If you&amp;rsquo;re not sure, you can also add these ingredients after the next step, but I have found this to be less tasty.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add in the cabbage, and cover the pot with a lid. Leave it be for about 10 minutes, untill the cabbage has wilted.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, beat your eggs in a bowl. While stiring with one hand, slowly drizzle in the egg. This creates the signature egg ribbons associated with this dish. Let it rest for a few minutes and you&amp;rsquo;re ready to serve!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teriyaki Sauce</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/teriyaki-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 18:50:31 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/teriyaki-sauce/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love eating this sauce with, for example, chicken and noodles. Do note that this sauce is by no means traditional, and is a take for the home kitchen for people that don&amp;rsquo;t have the ingredients to make traditional teriyaki sauce. I also have &lt;a href=&#34;https://paulstapel.com/recipes/traditional-teriyaki-sauce/&#34;&gt;a more traditional recipe&lt;/a&gt; on my blog, so give that one a try as well, and see for yourself which you like best!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sesame seeds (optional, adds flavour and thickens sauce)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soy Sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Honey&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sugar (only a little if you like it less sweet)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Grated ginger&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sesame oil (optional, ads nice sesame flavours)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Some water&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cornstarch (Add if you like a thicker sauce)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add all ingredients to a pan, and stir over medium heat until desired taste and texture is achieved. Go easy on the sesame oil.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rice Pudding</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/rice-pudding/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 15:09:19 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/rice-pudding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Whenever I have rice left over, there are two things that immediately come to mind. Storing it to stir-fry it later, or turning it into a pudding if I have time to do so. This is the ultimate thoughtless recipe for when you want to keep your hands busy while listening to music for example.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(Left over) rice&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Milk&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sugar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Vanilla extract (optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Submerge the rice in milk.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add sugar to taste (I like it a little less sweet).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Stir over a medium-low heat until the texture is smooth.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, you can choose to add a little vanilla extract.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Garlic Beans</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/garlic-beans/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 17:59:38 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/garlic-beans/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Green beans&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ginger&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soy Sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Butter&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;First, fry the beans in the oil till they become shriveled and you begin to see some yellow.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next, in a new pan, add the butter and heat up the garlic, ginger and soy sauce on medium heat. Go easy on the soy sauce.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, add the beans back in and mix them with the sauce.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
