<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Difficulty 2|5 on Paul&#39;s Particles</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/difficulty-25/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Difficulty 2|5 on Paul&#39;s Particles</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 14:47:30 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/difficulty-25/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Htipiti</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/htipiti/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 14:47:30 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/htipiti/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It is pronounced &amp;ldquo;tee-pee-tee&amp;rdquo; by the way. Serve with pita or something, idk, idc, I&amp;rsquo;m not your mom.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Feta cheese&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Red bell peppers&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Extra virgin olive oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Red wine vinegar or lemon juice&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Black pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Preheat your oven to 200 degrees Celcius&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cut the four sides of your bell peppers and reduce the stem. Lay them out on a baking tray and put them in the oven for roughly 25 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once your peppers are done, put them in a bowl and cover them to let them steam for another 10 to 20 minutes. This will make it easier to remove the skin of the peppers.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To a food processor, add feta cheese, your bell peppers (skin removed), a little red wine vinegar/lemon juice and some extra virgin olive oil.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, season to taste with salt and pepper.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Larb</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/larb/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 13:06:08 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/larb/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A few years back, I had a trip to Thailand with my family. While there, we ate a lot of very delicious food, and I have been recreating the things I ate there quite often.&#xA;One thing that does bug me about doing this, however, is the fact that some of the ingredients can be quite troublesome to acquire. Not today however, as we will be making larb.&#xA;The ingredients used for this are quite easy to come by in your local Asian supermarket or even just the grocery store. Serve with rice, naan or even tortilla&amp;rsquo;s.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Beef/Pork Stroganoff</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/beef-stroganoff/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 21:19:53 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/beef-stroganoff/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;All jokes aside, this recipe results in a rich and creamy beef stroganoff. As pork is a lot cheaper where I live, I often use pork as instead of beef. This is still very tasty, but if you can, try making it with beef, as it will be even richer in flavor. You should serve it with pasta. I recommend serving this with pasta like tagliatelle, but mashed potatoes would also be verrryyy good I imagine. Without further ado, let&amp;rsquo;s get into this recipe :D&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pork Adobo</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/pork-adobo/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 20:48:12 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/pork-adobo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;My auntie Rose from the Philippines shared this awesome recipe with me recently, and i&amp;rsquo;ve made it a few times now. I will be sharing the base recipe with some optional ingredients you may add, but having cooked this dish in a few different ways now, I can safely say that all of them are delicous. Serve with white rice.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Pork belly (or chicken for chicken adobo) (Use the bones seperately as well if you have them)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic (lots of it)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Olive oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;String beans (Optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Potatoes (Optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Hard boiled egg (Optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White onion (Own addition, optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;for-the-marinade&#34;&gt;For the marinade&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White vinegar (I have found that Chinkiang black vinegar also works, but I prefer white)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Brown sugar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Black pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bay leafs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Warm water&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;There are two ways to do the marinade. Firstly, you can add the marinade and salt to your pork and leave it to marinade overnight. Alternatively, you can salt the pork and cook it first, then add the marinade later. Either way, the marinade can be made by mixing all of the ingredients listed and adjusting to taste.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finely mince your garlic. Usually, I use about a foot of garlic. Make sure it is pasted or finely minced.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To a pot on high heat, add your pork (chicken) and brown it. After that is done, you may remove it from the pan and lower the heat.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next add your (optional, chopped) white onion and a (mandatory) lot of garlic to your pan and fry it untill browned.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;If you have bones, add them now and cook them in the same oil.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next, you may add your optional string beans and potatoes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once the bones are done, you can add your pork (chicken) back into the pan and continue cooking for a minute before adding your sauce.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;While this is cooking, you may optionally boil some eggs to add to your pan.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Let this simmer on medium heat for a while, until the desired texture is acquired. Serve with white rice.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Garlixplosion Noodles</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/garlicsplosion-noodles/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 08:19:15 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/garlicsplosion-noodles/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The only way to make a good dish even gooder is to add an exuberant amount of garlic to it. That was exactly the premise of this little experiment. Adding a lot of garlic and seeing where it leads me. It turned out to be a delightful recipe that I have even decided to share her on my blog. Be warned, not for the faint of heart.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lots of garlic (I used about 2 bulbs, but adjust to your own tolerance/taste)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Noodles&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Zucchini&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ground beef or meatballs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chili oil (I use Lao Gan Ma)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A little vegetable oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Light soy sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Optional black bean sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To a pot, add some salted water and cook your noodles as per the instructions on the package.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next, mince the onion and cut up the zucchini into small pieces. If you&amp;rsquo;re not using a garlic press, mince your garlic.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add some vegetable oil to your pan and start by sweating the onions. After they are translucent, turn up the heat and add your zucchini and chili oil. Lastly, add your garlic (using a garlic press).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;At this point, you may add your meat. I used meatballs (cursed, I know), but ground beef also works great. Be sure to stir often, as otherwise your aromatics may burn.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;When your sauce has browned, add light soy sauce and optional black bean sauce to taste. I used a ratio of 3:1 for these ingredients. You can also add some more Lao Gan Ma if you want.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lastly, toss your noodles into your pan and stir carefully until it is covered in sauce.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Carbonara</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/carbonara/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 20:03:41 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/carbonara/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;So, yesterday I was craving some good &amp;lsquo;ol spaghetti. I usually go with a tomato sauce, but this time, I saw that I still had some parmigiano in my fridge. I simply couldn&amp;rsquo;t resist the urge to try something new, and ended up making this delicious carbonara. It may not be the healthiest, but it was definitely worth it in the end. I included a secret ingredient of miso paste in order to boost the umami content. Although I strongly recommend you put it, the dish will still turn out yummy if omitted.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ants Climbing a Tree</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/ants-climbing-a-tree/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 20:38:46 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/ants-climbing-a-tree/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After a long day of work, you probably don&amp;rsquo;t want to have to cook anything complicated. Whenever I have days like this, I like keeping it simple as well. Of course, simple does not necessarily mean bland, and this dish is both easy and flavorful. The name &amp;ldquo;Ants climbing a tree&amp;rdquo; stems from the fact that the small ingredients on top of the glass noodles look like ants climbing a tree. I&amp;rsquo;ll have to admit that I started cooking this dish purely because I thought the name sounded cute&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tennessee Onion</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/tennessee-onion/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jul 2024 21:18:06 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/tennessee-onion/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ok, so the description may have been a lie. I usually don&amp;rsquo;t barbecue because Dutch weather can be very unpredictable (Dutch struggles). Instead, I like to put stuff in the oven (like a true patriot). Therefore, this dish will be using our favorite inferno machine. The TTC (time to cook) is about an hour, so prepare it well in advance!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White onions&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shredded cheese (Gouda, because it melts well and because it&amp;rsquo;s Dutch)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Butter&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Paprika powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chopped parsley&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dried thyme&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Dried oregano&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Aluminum foil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Preheat an oven to 160 degrees Celsius.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Start peeling the onions and cutting them into rings.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In a casserole, layer the onion rings. If you have lots of mouths to feed, make multiple layers.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;On top of your layer of onion rings, add your herbs and cheese. Add a generous amount of cheese, but reserve some for later.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, add some small cubes of butter spread evenly throughout the dish and cover it with the aluminum foil. Put it in the oven and cook for 40 minutes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;After 40 minutes, take out your casserole. Sprinkle over a little of your remaining cheese, and put it back into the oven, uncovered. Leave it in for another 20 minutes, and you&amp;rsquo;re ready to serve.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Souvlaki</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/souvlaki/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2024 07:26:17 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/souvlaki/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a lovely meaty dish that you can serve as a main course. With summer at its peak, you enjoy this dish on straight from the grill during a barbecue for example.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;marinade&#34;&gt;Marinade&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(extra virgin) olive oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Oregano&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sweet paprika powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Thyme (optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bay leaves&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Juice from a lemon&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;LOTS OF GARLIC&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt and pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chicken (cubed, which you&amp;rsquo;ll marinate)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mince the garlic. You should use enough that you can smell it. I used 8 cloves (slightly more than a bulb) per kilo last time.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mix everything into a ziplock bag or marinating bowl.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Stir in the chicken, and let it sit for an hour or preferably two (not for too long! The lemon will slowly cook the chicken, lessening its taste after a certain amount of time)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Skewer the chicken (or cook it in a skillet if you want). You can grill the skewers on a barbecue.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Egg Drop Soup</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/egg-drop-soup/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2024 21:12:21 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/egg-drop-soup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve started getting into making soup recently. This is new territory for me, but I decided to give it a try after pondering what to do with the leftover chinese cabbage that had been living rent-free in my fridge for too long. Behold! This soup was the result.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chinese Cabbage&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;About 1 liter of chicken stock&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Eggs (about 3)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White onion (can be omitted)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sesame oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Powdered or grated ginger&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt and (preferably white) pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Scallion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A little bit of cooking oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Chop up your onions, garlic and scallion (put aside the green for garnish).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In a deep pot, start sweating the onion and scallion in a little bit of oil. After a few minutes, add the garlic as well.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Meanwhile, start tearing the cabbage apart with your hands. Doing it this way gives you nice and irregular pieces, which is nicer for the texture than when the cabbage is chopped.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add the chicken stock and add ginger, sesame oil, salt and pepper to taste. If you&amp;rsquo;re not sure, you can also add these ingredients after the next step, but I have found this to be less tasty.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add in the cabbage, and cover the pot with a lid. Leave it be for about 10 minutes, untill the cabbage has wilted.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, beat your eggs in a bowl. While stiring with one hand, slowly drizzle in the egg. This creates the signature egg ribbons associated with this dish. Let it rest for a few minutes and you&amp;rsquo;re ready to serve!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Teriyaki Sauce</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/teriyaki-sauce/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 18:50:31 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/teriyaki-sauce/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love eating this sauce with, for example, chicken and noodles. Do note that this sauce is by no means traditional, and is a take for the home kitchen for people that don&amp;rsquo;t have the ingredients to make traditional teriyaki sauce. I also have &lt;a href=&#34;https://paulstapel.com/recipes/traditional-teriyaki-sauce/&#34;&gt;a more traditional recipe&lt;/a&gt; on my blog, so give that one a try as well, and see for yourself which you like best!&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sesame seeds (optional, adds flavour and thickens sauce)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soy Sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Honey&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sugar (only a little if you like it less sweet)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Grated ginger&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sesame oil (optional, ads nice sesame flavours)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Some water&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cornstarch (Add if you like a thicker sauce)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add all ingredients to a pan, and stir over medium heat until desired taste and texture is achieved. Go easy on the sesame oil.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rice Pudding</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/rice-pudding/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Apr 2024 15:09:19 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/rice-pudding/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Whenever I have rice left over, there are two things that immediately come to mind. Storing it to stir-fry it later, or turning it into a pudding if I have time to do so. This is the ultimate thoughtless recipe for when you want to keep your hands busy while listening to music for example.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;(Left over) rice&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Milk&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sugar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Vanilla extract (optional)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Submerge the rice in milk.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add sugar to taste (I like it a little less sweet).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Stir over a medium-low heat until the texture is smooth.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, you can choose to add a little vanilla extract.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Garlic Beans</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/garlic-beans/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 17:59:38 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/garlic-beans/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Green beans&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ginger&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Soy Sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Butter&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;First, fry the beans in the oil till they become shriveled and you begin to see some yellow.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next, in a new pan, add the butter and heat up the garlic, ginger and soy sauce on medium heat. Go easy on the soy sauce.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, add the beans back in and mix them with the sauce.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
