<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mexican on Paul&#39;s Particles</title>
    <link>https://paulstapel.com/categories/mexican/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mexican on Paul&#39;s Particles</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 07:38:52 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://paulstapel.com/categories/mexican/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Chili Beans</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/chili-beans/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Mar 2025 07:38:52 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/chili-beans/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For this dish, I was inspired by a recipe from a book I was recently given (One Piece: Pirate Recipes xD). It is a very simple recipe, and I wished to expand upon it to make it even tastier.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Kidney beans&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ground beef (or pork, or mixed)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Garlic&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ground cayenne pepper&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Paprika powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tomato paste&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Diced chipotle peppers in adobo sauce&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cooking oil&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Start by seasoning your ground beef with ground cayenne pepper, salt and paprika powder.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;To a pan add some cooking oil and brown your ground beef.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Meanwhile, start mincing your onion and garlic. Once your ground beef is done, remove it from your pan and add the onion. After it has turned translucent, add your garlic.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add some tomato paste to your pan, along with the diced chipotle peppers in adobo sauce. Stir and let it deepen its color a little before adding some water and your kidney beans.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Let the beans simmer for a bit until most of the water has evaporated. Finally, add back in your ground beef and season to taste with your spices.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;This recipe pairs well with nachos, tortillas or rice for example.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Queso</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/queso/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2025 09:19:17 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/queso/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I have guests around, I want to make something easy and filling that I can just put on the table and forget about. Dips are perfect for this, as it creates a central piece whereabout everyone can gather. I really like this recipe as a guilty pleasure, and would like to share it with you all now.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ground beef or chorizo (about 300 to 400 grams)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White onion (one large white onion)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Flour (2 tbsp)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Milk (1.5 cups, less if you want a more solid queso)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Mozerella (2 pieces)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Old cheese (To taste)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Parmesan (To taste)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Cilantro (a.k.a. coriander) (To taste)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Salt and black pepper (be mindful of salt content in your other ingredients) (To taste)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Diced chipotle peppers (optional, add extra rich flavor and makes the whole more varied)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Preheat your oven to 200 degrees Celcius.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In a skillet, brown your ground beef or heat up your chorizo. Season it with salt and pepper. While it is browning, chop up a white onion.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once browned, add your chopped onion and stir on high heat until translucent and a little browned.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add some flour to your pan and let it heat up for a bit. Then, add your milk as well.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add your mozerella, and grate your old cheese and parmesan. Add it to the pan and let it melt a bit.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Stir through some cilantro (and diced chipotle peppers) and further season to taste with more salt and pepper if necessary.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Put your skillet int he oven until you queso has bubbled up and has achieved a golden yellow color.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pico De Gallo</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/pico-de-gallo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 08:50:28 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/pico-de-gallo/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I love Mexican food, and I can never resist a good salsa. I wanted to start making more salsa whenever I make Mexican food from now on, and I decided to start with a pico de gallo, as it is well defined and a tried and true recipe. This is definetely not my own recipe, as I am just throwing ingredients in a bowl, but I will outline some of the things I do to make it taste even better.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Burrito</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/burrito/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 07:38:59 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/burrito/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A good burrito recipe has been like the holy grail for me. I looove burritos, but I just wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to get them to taste quite right. This recipe is finally close to the taste I have been searching for.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ground beef&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Vegetable or olive oil.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lots of beans. I use kidney beans. They will be pasted.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;About 2 parts Salt, 1 part Pepper, 1 part Garlic powder, 4 parts Paprika powder, 8 parts Cumin. This will be your seasoning.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Optionally, you may add vegetables like bell pepper, carrots, leek or whatever you think will taste good. I like the extra variation each bite brings when you add some vegetables to this dish.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Water or beef stock (be careful with the salt content!).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;serve-with&#34;&gt;Serve with&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shredded cheese&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sour cream&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Guacamole&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White or brown rice&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tortillas&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jalapeños&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Optionally, tortilla chips.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Coat your pan lightly with oil and start browning the beef.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;While this is happening, blend your beans until they form a bean paste.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once the beef has been browned, remove it from your pan and start sweating your onions until translucent.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Now, add your optional vegetables and wait until they are done.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add back your ground beef and add your bean paste. Also add in your seasoning.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add some water or beef stock to deglaze your pan and let the water content reduce until the burrito filling has your desired texture. It should be thick and a little runny, but not watery.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Assemble your delicious burrito(s).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
