<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Mexican on Paul&#39;s Particles</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/categories/mexican/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Mexican on Paul&#39;s Particles</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 07:38:59 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/categories/mexican/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Burrito</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/recipes/burrito/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 07:38:59 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/recipes/burrito/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A good burrito recipe has been like the holy grail for me. I looove burritos, but I just wasn&amp;rsquo;t able to get them to taste quite right. This recipe is finally close to the taste I have been searching for.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Ground beef&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White onion&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Vegetable or olive oil.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Lots of beans. I use kidney beans. They will be pasted.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;About 2 parts Salt, 1 part Pepper, 1 part Garlic powder, 4 parts Paprika powder, 8 parts Cumin. This will be your seasoning.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Optionally, you may add vegetables like bell pepper, carrots, leek or whatever you think will taste good. I like the extra variation each bite brings when you add some vegetables to this dish.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Water or beef stock (be careful with the salt content!).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;serve-with&#34;&gt;Serve with&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Shredded cheese&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Sour cream&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Guacamole&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;White or brown rice&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Tortillas&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Jalapeños&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Optionally, tortilla chips.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;cooking-plan&#34;&gt;Cooking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Coat your pan lightly with oil and start browning the beef.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;While this is happening, blend your beans until they form a bean paste.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once the beef has been browned, remove it from your pan and start sweating your onions until translucent.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Now, add your optional vegetables and wait until they are done.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add back your ground beef and add your bean paste. Also add in your seasoning.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add some water or beef stock to deglaze your pan and let the water content reduce until the burrito filling has your desired texture. It should be thick and a little runny, but not watery.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Assemble your delicious burrito(s).&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
