<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Baking on Paul&#39;s Particles</title>
    <link>https://paulstapel.com/categories/baking/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Baking on Paul&#39;s Particles</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 14:24:19 +0100</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://paulstapel.com/categories/baking/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>S&#39;mores in a pan</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/smores/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Dec 2024 14:24:19 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/smores/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I, like most people, like s&amp;rsquo;mores. Shame that I don&amp;rsquo;t really like camping that much :/ but a well. Luckily, I don&amp;rsquo;t have to miss out on this treat, as I can just use my oven to make s&amp;rsquo;mores in a pan.&#xA;I was originally not going to write down the recipe, but after struggling with the marshmallows sticking to the pan the first time, I decided it would be helpful to also explain an easy trick to prevent that from happening.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Brownie</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/brownie/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Nov 2024 17:35:12 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/brownie/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t bake often, but from time to time, I really enjoy filling my pantry with some sweet deliciousness. This brownie recipe is one of my favs when it comes to that purpose. You can store this brownie for later, but even better would be to scoop them right out of the pan and eat it while it&amp;rsquo;s hot.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;220 grams sugar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;120 grams butter&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;80 grams all-purpose flower&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;3 or 4 eggs (3 if you want it fudgy, 4 if you like them more solid)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;60 grams cacao powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A little bit of salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Optional vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Optional chocalate chips or chunks&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Optional whipped cream for serving&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;baking-plan&#34;&gt;Baking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Start by heating an oven to about 180 degrees Celcius.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Start by melting the butter in a heated skillet.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;When the butter is melted, add your sugar, mix it well.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once mixed, add your cacao powder and stir it through.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Once this has been stirred, you may add some optional vanilla extract. half a teaspoon will do.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;After this, turn of the heat and stir your eggs through the brownie mixture.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Next, add your flour and stir it until the mixture has turned brown.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Finally, you may add your optional chocalate chips to the mixture however you may like.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Put the pan in the oven for about 20 (for gooey brownies) to 25 (for more firm brownies) minutes.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY!&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Scuffins</title>
      <link>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/scuffins/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 26 Jul 2024 20:22:45 +0200</pubDate>
      <guid>https://paulstapel.com/recipes/scuffins/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At first, I was planning on making scones. Because of a lack of better moulds, I decided to use a muffin tray, and the rest is history. This recipe yields about 12 medium-sized scuffins.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;ingredients&#34;&gt;Ingredients&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;500 grams of all-purpose flour&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;200 grams of granulated sugar&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;About 10 grams of baking powder&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;2 eggs&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;250 grams of butter&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;200 grams of crème fraîche&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;About 20 milliliters of milk&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;About 3 teaspoons of vanilla extract&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A pinch of salt&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Optionally, toppings like milk chocolate, blueberries or caramel&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;A muffin tray&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;baking-plan&#34;&gt;Baking plan&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Preheat an oven to 200 degrees Celsius.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add the flour, sugar, salt, and baking powder to a large bowl.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;In small cubes or pieces, add in the butter while mixing your bowl. I mix using a mixer, but a whisk would work as well. Mix until you are left with a crumbly dough.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Add in your vanilla extract, crème fraîche and eggs. Mix together until the dough becomes sticky and thick. Add in your milk incrementally to make your batter less thick. It should still be sticky!&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Butter a muffin tray and fill it with your batter. I used two spoons to transfer the batter, as it will easily stick to your hands.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;With a glove (or your bare hands), push in your toppings. Use a bit more than you might initially think, as the flavours may be lost in the batter.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Bake your scuffins in the oven for about 20 - 25 minutes, until they are golden brown.&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;li&gt;Serve with clotted cream and jam. (for a quick and easy clotted cream, mix mascarpone and crème fraîche)&lt;/li&gt;&#xA;&lt;/ul&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;enjoy&#34;&gt;ENJOY&lt;/h2&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
